{"_id": "46377871", "question": "What is the difference between a 2 stroke and a 4 stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "566649fa", "question": "What's the difference between a two stroke and four stroke motorcycle engine?", "answers": "It is in reference to the engine both are piston engine.\n2 stroke has 2 cycles. With each cycle doing multiple things in each.\nCompare to 4 stroke:\n+ Better power band (single each down stroke is a power stroke).\n+ Lighter (therefore higher power per weight ratio).\n+ Easier to make (which translate to cheaper)\n+ Plugs last longer\n+ No valve adjustment/maintenance is needed (since the reed valve is a simple mechanism compare to the valve in the 4 stroke which rarely require adjustment)\n- Worst fuel economy\n- Worst for the enviroment\n- Noisier\n- Engines last much less\n- 2 cycle oil is harder to get (with fewer options)\n- uses more oil\nSome progress has being made to improve the 2 stroke engine (like direct injection which eliminates the reed valve, but makes it more complicated to build, increase the weight but greatly improves the mileage and engine durability while reducing polution) but I am not aware of anyone mass manufacturing these.\n4 stroke engine\n4 stroke engines. Have 4 simpler cycles (which is cycle doing 1 main task)\nCompare to 2 stroke:\n+ Much better mileage (sometime double)\n+ More environmentally friendly\n+ Oil is available almost anywhere\n+ No oil/gas mixture problems\n+ Last longer\n+ There are more engine types (sizes, types)\n+ Not as noisy\nHigher power weight\n- less power\n- heavier\n- more complicated to make\n- more expensive\n- requires valve maintenance\n\nIMO: In general, anyone wanting to get a scooter (something normally known for lack of power) is better off to get a scooter with a bigger 4 stroke engine than a 2 stroke engine scooter. There is more upfront cost but gas and durability makes it worth it."}
{"_id": "385a6763", "question": "How can one identify which one is a two stroke engine and which one is a four stroke engine?", "answers": "2 strokes don’t have a “dip stick”\nSince 2 strokes mix oil and gas together, there’s no ….\noil pump..\noil sump\noil filter..\noil pressure system or oil pressure gauge..\nSmall 2 stroke engines go “ ring da ding da ding da ding ding dind]g din When they idle.\n4 strokes go “duh duh duh duh duh..\nIf you put straight gas in it, and 30 seconds later, it stops running.. It WAS a 2 stroke…\nIf it’s something you can hold in your hands, if it runs when it’s upside down, it’s probably a 2 stroke.\nIf you push the primer bulb, and can’t smell gas, it’s a 2 stroke. ( In a 2 stroke, the primer bulb just brings fresh fuel to the carb.. it doesn’t introduce fuel into the manifold),\nIf you push the primer bulb, and you can smell gas, it’s a 4 stroke.. In a 4 stroke, the primer bulb injects raw gas into the intake, to facilitate cold starting..\nIf there’s no bolts going through the head, into the engine.. it’s probably a 2 stroke.\nIf there’s fuel in the tank, and it looks blue, it’s a 2 stroke. 2 stroke premix oil is dyed to let you know if your can had 4 or 3 stroke oil in it,,"}
{"_id": "2e494954", "question": "What does it feel like to have a stroke?", "answers": "It's May 9th 2018. My alarm sounds at 8:45pm. I have had a headache all day that wouldn't shift but it's the last of my night duties and I can enjoy a couple of days off. I sit up on the side of my bed. My head felt so much like it exploded that I turned around expecting my bed to be covered in blood. It hurts to hold my head up but I want to hyperextend my neck. Pain is shooting down my back. I am a nurse who works with brain injured patients. Immediately I am trying to make a clinical sense from my symptoms. I can barely stand. I tell my eldest daughter I can't go to work. It's less than an hour until my shift starts but she calls in for me. I am worrying for leaving it so late to call in. It's not always easy to get a night duty replacement at short notice so it means one of the evening shift will probably end up doing an 18 hour shift. My daughter and my work are telling me not to worry. They too know what I am describing. My daughter takes me to emergency and I am thankful that we only live 7 minutes from work. We get to emergency and of course they know me. I've worked at the hospital for a long time. They know what a thunderclap headache is …\nI'm immediately put in for a CT Brain where they could see the bleed happening. I have burst an aneurysm in my subarachnoid space. It has bled through the Sylvian Fissure and 4 lobes are hit. By this time my GCS has fallen to 3 when it should be 15. I am unaware what is happening and I am taken to surgery for coiling by the Neurologist. The coiling was unsuccessful and again my vitals are dropping. Back to surgery where the neurosurgeon cut my hair off and opened my scalp to take a part of my skull out to perform an evacuation and clipping.\nI wake up to a phone full of messages. My sister is at my bedside crying. I am immediately concerned and ask her what has happened, thinking she has come to tell me something terrible. She laughs gives me a hug and tells me everything is fine now. I can't make sense of the messages I have. Why are people asking me where I have been? Am I ok? Why is my long hair now so short it feels like stubble? Why are my eyes swollen and what are these metal clips across my skull for? Why do I have a tube running out of the top of my head?\nThe surgical team come in as the nurses have said I am awake. I listen to what the Neurosurgeon is saying. Burst aneurysm. 4 lobes involved. Another two aneurysms remain but not the time to operate on the left side of my brain as my right side needs to heal.\nI am amazed at what has happened. Trying to process everything and marvel at so much happening yesterday to be thankfully awake today. Only it wasn't yesterday. I have lost a week in ICU. I can't remember anything after May 9th 2018.\nI'm suddenly aware of my daughter's smiling when they tell me what day it is. It isn't until they remind me they have told me several times already what day it is. The nurses update my patient care board every day with current day/date and what the day will contain. I read it and then 5 minutes later I am asking what day it is and have we had breakfast.\nThe only thing I know is the pressure I feel in my head is immense. I am getting drugs orally and intravenously. Every 4 hours around the clock I am woken to take anti spasmodics. They are a godsend. The spasms in my head bring about immediate anxiety. I wonder why no one has gotten me out of bed to walk around. The bed rails make it hard for me to get myself up. I can hear patient buzzers going off and all I know is I need to get up to answer them but the other nurses won't let me. As soon as a buzzer sounds there is suddenly a nurse at my bedside telling me it's ok and one of the others are tending to the patient who is buzzing for a nurse.\nThe physio starts my therapy. I'm so unsteady on my feet and need an “old persons\" walker to help steady me. WHAT IS GOING ON WITH ME? This isn't making sense. I was perfectly fine “yesterday\".\nAfter a number of weeks I am discharged into the care of the brain injury unit. They are heaven sent. I know a few of them through work even though it is an external unit. They work like a well oiled machine. Speech Therapy, Physiotherapy, Occupational Therapy, Pyschologist, Neuropsych, Social Work and the wonderful Rehab Consultant I have known since he was a resident.\nIt's been a long year. I have come to accept the shortcomings I have. My peripheral astigmatisms have improved. My depth perception makes for laughs. When the girls ask me to throw them a pen etc. it can be like a missile lol. I have a very sensitive area on my skull. Sometimes I can touch it and it's fine. Other times things like brushing my hair can make me jump like I've been shocked. I have to take medications every day and I am still under the care of the neurosurgical team as an outpatient. I have to have regular CT angiograms to check the status of my two remaining aneurysms.\nI am now working on my return to work program. I am thankful that I have recovered as well as I have. I am even more thankful that my work kept my position for me so I had a job to go back to. I am blessed to have had the family and friends support I have.\nMy memory is back to normal. My brain fatigue is improving. I no longer need to sleep 18 hours a day. I maintain a healthy diet and exercise as per my improving tolerance. When I get tired I limp. My grip isn't as strong as it used to be but I am now able to open jars etc.\nWhat I am thankful for is that (at the risk of sounding cliched) it has given me a new appreciation for life. I have always enjoyed the beauty that surrounds us and the simple pleasures but now I find I am more patient of not only others but of myself. I’m not in such a hurry to get here or there now. Traffic doesn't frustrate me. The long line at the grocery store is an opportunity to stop a while and be still.\nLife is good … and I am thankful :)"}
{"_id": "f019c8a7", "question": "What are the leading risk factors for having a stroke?", "answers": "If you can answer this in a Quora answer, I’d say you deserve the Nobel’s Prize in Medicine!\nIn some cases, it’s obvious what caused a stroke: if somebody’s obese, has really high blood pressure, is really old, etc., it’s pretty clear-cut.\nBut I was 115 pounds, 90/60, and 24 years old when I had my stroke. My doctors looked at me, referred me to a cardiologist for another test, which was negative, and told me to go on my way. “The chance of you having a subsequent stroke is very small,” they assured me.\nSix months later, I was back in the hospital with another one. =(\nAbout six months after THAT, I was able to peer out from beneath my lead jacket of fatigue and pick my head up enough to wonder WHY I’d had a second one. It’d be nice to figure it out, I wagered, to prevent a third one. At that point, I’d already decided that if I had another one, JUST LET ME DIE.\nMy speech therapist referred me to a neurologist at the big city hospital nearby. In retrospect, he was nuts, but he did decide to perform a test just to check for certain that the cardiologist I’d originally seen hadn’t missed anything. (The first test, a TEE — trans esophageal echocardiogram — checked for a hole in my heart by sticking a camera down my throat look to look at my heart. The second test, a TCD — transcranial doppler — shot minuscule bubbles into my arm via an IV and listened to my brain to see if any of them made it up there.) Lo and behold, it dinged! I had a hole in my heart that allowed bubbles/clots/etc to pass through a ventricle and into my brain.\nBut, a week later, the neurologist called and said he wasn’t sure that the hole was the cause of my stroked. He explained that doctors usually require both a hole and a hypercoagulable disease — i.e. you need a hole in your heart and a reason to have a clot. “Why the h*ll did you have me do this test, then?” I wanted to shout.\nTo make a long story short, I decided to go ahead and have surgery to close the hole. It’s not terribly risky, but it is heart surgery. I haven’t had another stroke in 12 years, I’ve had a very good neurologist tell me that clots sometimes form in the area right around the hole *just because*, I’ve had doctors tell me to get my head screwed on straight — everybody knows a hole isnt enough without a hypercoagulable disease … I’ve pretty much just given up having any chance of ever knowing what caused my strokes.\nSo please, figure it out! LOL"}
{"_id": "1d542981", "question": "How can I prevent myself from having a stroke?", "answers": "Currently, we have no Heimlich maneuver for CVA, other than a substance called TPA, which is injected into the bloodstream and causes any clots to break apart, thus opening any blocked vesicles in the brain. BUT— and it’s a big but—\nCVAs can be caused by clots (ischemic), yessireee, but they can also be caused by bleeds (hemorrhagic). If you have a bleed in your brain causing symptoms of stroke, and you just happen to have some TPA laying around, and you just happen to still be capable of injecting said TPA into your vein to break up a clot you think you have, do you know what happens? The bleed in your brain bleeds faster, and you could bleed out, because TPA works on clots, not bleeds.\nSo, you’re having stroke symptoms- sided weakness, some pins-and-needles, confusion- is it being caused by a clot or a bleed? Quickly now- guess correctly and quickly, you want to stop this immediately, remember?\nBzzzzzzt! Time’s up and guess what, you can’t know without a CT scan. What? You don’t have a CT scanner at your house? Well now what?! How are you going to stop this immediately without a CT scanner?\nYou are going to call 911 or whatever your emergency services number is, and let trained, qualified medical professionals do their job and get your clogged or bleeding brain to a hospital as fast as they can. Time is brain functioning in a stroke; we have stretched the golden hour to the golden three hours, but less than one hour is still best.\nYou will be immediately evaluated while in the ambulance and wheeled directly to radiology for that CT scan. The scan will be read by a neurologist who will determine if there is a bleed- no bleed, you’ll be offered TPA. You say yes, the nurse adds a small bag of clear fluid to your IV. Within minutes, you start to feel less confused, not so groggy. Every minute after that, you ‘clear’ a bit more. You may come all the way back in a matter of hours, there may always be some residual damage, you won’t know until you are on your individual journey.\nIf the scan showed a bleed, you will be whisked into surgery and the bleed will be stopped if possible- if accessible. Sometimes a transfusion of clotting factors can be given if the bleed cannot be reached. Then, of course, care must be taken there’s not a clot in the brain, too. You may come all the way back in a matter of hours, there may always be some residual damage, you won’t know until you are on your individual journey.\nBut, that is the best we have right now, and it is far and away better than what we had even a quarter century ago. Thank your lucky stars."}
{"_id": "a64bf0e8", "question": "How do two-stroke engines differ from four-stroke engines?", "answers": "(Play the gifs below while reading to get a better understanding)\nTwo Stroke Engines\nAs the name suggest, the two stroke engine cycle consists of two strokes - namely the intake/exhaust stroke and the compression/combustion stroke.\n1. During the intake/exhaust stroke, the fuel-air mixture from the carburettor is taken in from the intake valve and the exhaust from the previous cycle is expelled from the exhaust shaft. As you may have already guessed/known, this exchange of fuel-air mixture with exhaust gases is not perfect. As demonstrated below, the piston creates an area of low pressure when it is at the beginning of the intake stroke and sucks in air from both intake and exhaust shafts. Hence, exhaust gases are sucked back into the engine for combustion and the fuel-air mixture from the intake shaft are expelled.\n2. During the compression/combustion stroke, the fuel-air mixture (along with some exhaust gases) is compressed. This is the first half of the cycle, until the the piston reaches it's highest point in the cylinder. The next half of the cycle occurs when a spark plug ignites the fuel-air mixture when the piston is at it's peak, thereby causing the violent expansion of gases and pushing the piston back down to power the crankshaft and ultimately your vehicle. (This is sometimes also know as the \"Power Stroke\")\nThe above two step repeat themselves again and again, and that's what makes a two stroke engined vehicle move.\nAdvantages of two strokes - Due to the existence of only two strokes, the \"Power Stroke\" occurs every half cycle. One in every two strokes produces power (whereas in four stroke engines, only one in four strokes produces power). This gives two stroke engines a significantly higher power-to-weight ratio than four strokes. Hence, even today chainsaws, lawnmowers and other small engined tools have a two stroke engine instead of a four stroke.\nDisadvantages of two strokes - Very low fuel economy due to the combustion of exhaust gases and the escape of fuel. Since exhaust gases are re-compressed and hydrocarbons (fuel) are expelled from the exhaust, the exhaust is rich with carbon (causing it's characteristic white colour) and unusually high amounts of carbon monoxide.\nFour Stroke Engines\nThe four stroke engine consists of four strokes - namely Intake, Compression, Combustion and Exhaust.\n1. Intake Stroke - Fuel-air mixture (shown in blue below) is sucked in to the piston when it as it's lowest point due the creation of low pressure. It is important to remember that unlike two stroke engines, four strokes have valves. During this stroke, only the intake valve opens up and a fuel-air mixture enters the cylinder.\n2. Compression Stroke - The contents of the cylinder are compressed by the momentum of the crankshaft and piston caused by previous strokes. For petrol/gasoline the compression ratio is usually between 8:1 and 12:1, whereas for diesel, the compression ratio is between 14:1 and 25:1. This is because diesel is a much denser fuel (oil) and requires higher temperatures to reach it's combustion point. If you remember from school, according to Gay Lussac's Law, temperature increases with the increase in temperature (Check out http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gas_laws\n)\n3. Combustion Stroke - For petrol/gasoline engines, the compressed fuel is combusted with the help of a spark plug. But for a diesel engine, the compressed fuel automatically combusts due to the (relatively) high temperatures inside the engine. This stroke is what powers the engine, causing the piston to be forced down due to the expansion of gases in the cylinder.\n4. Exhaust Stroke - The contents of the cylinder after combustion are expelled when the piston moves up due to momentum carried over by previous cycles. Now, the exhaust valve opens and the exhaust is let out.\n\nAdvantages of four strokes - Much higher fuel economy than two stroke engines because the intake and exhaust strokes are treated as two different steps.\nDisadvantages of four strokes - Their power-to-weight ratio is much smaller as compared to two stokes because only one in ever four strokes produces power."}
{"_id": "6a8952fb", "question": "Why is four stroke engine prefered over two stroke engine?", "answers": "Working in a locomotive shop, I have experience with both 2 stroke and 4 stroke diesel engines.\nShort answer: the reason why the 4 stroke has become more popular is because of efficiency and emissions.\nLong answer requires some knowledge of how the 2 stroke engine works. In a two stroke Diesel engine, you have a power cycle every rotation of the crankshaft. Below is a diagram of the engine.\nIntake air comes into the engine and is pressurized by some meathod, either a roots blower as shown above, A centrifugal supercharger, or like EMD engines, a hybrid turbo-supercharger\n6–71 Detroit Roots Blower\nEMD Turbocharger- note gear drive\nThis pressurized inlet air is fed into the cylinders through a series of ports in the bottom of the cylinder in a process known as scavenging. The exhaust valves on the top of the cylinder are open at the same time that the piston has gone below the inlet ports allowing the pressurized inlet air coming in to push the exhaust out of the cylinder.\nEMD Power assembly- note the inlet ports on the bottom of the cylinder and the exhaust at the top.\nThe exhaust valves close, the piston covers up the inlet port, and compresses the air. At top dead Center the injector injects fuel into the cylinder which ignited and pushes the piston down until the valves and ports are opened and the process repeats.\nThis is a very simple and reliable setup and can take a lot of abuse and keep running. But as I mentioned, efficiency and emissions are not these engines strong suits. I will explain why.\nEfficiency\nI hear a lot of old diesel finatics preach about the efficiency of the two stroke engine, but it’s not so. They are great for power and acceleration due to the extra power stroke they get over the four stroke, but they are limited. Why? Because your engine is an air pump first and foremost. What does that effect.\nWell, one of the most crucial aspects of an engines efficiency is its intake and exhaust durations, measured in degrees of crank rotation. Guys who build performance engines know this all too well. So let’s look at a four stroke engine. Below is a cam spec sheet for a small block Chevy I’m going to use as my example.\nSo let’s look at our cam profile. Our intake valve opens at 49 degrees before top dead Center, and closes at 81 degrees after bottom dead Center, for a total of 310 degrees. Our exhaust valve opens at 98 degrees before bottom dead Center, and closes 42 degrees after top dead Center for a total of 320 degrees. This gives you plenty of time for air to come in and go out.\nNow look at the two stroke. It’s inlet and exhaust duration is limited to the time that both the inlet port at the bottom, and exhaust valve on top are open. Let’s say hypothetically you inlet port is uncovered by the piston at 60 degrees before bottom dead Center, and closed off at 60 degrees after bottom dead Center. Your duration is only 120 degrees to get your intake air in and your exhaust out, which is a far cry shorter then the 310 that the four stroke gets. This is the number one limiting factor on a two stroke, and it can’t be solved.\nEmissions\nSo, why can’t a two stroke Diesel engine make emissions? Simply put, because they are so dirty. Because the piston throws oil up the cylinder, some inevitably gets into the intake port and burned. Oil makes horrible fuel and doesn’t burn clean, adding to carbon, particulate, and other emissions.\nJust so you can see what we have to deal with, this is what the air box on an EMD engine looks like. This is the source of the combustion air for the engine."}
{"_id": "6d1fbe5c", "question": "What is a four stroke engine?", "answers": "Basically to understand the answer you need to know the components of a four stroke engine..\nAn engine has two Valves which are connected on top of the cylinder or a combustion chamber which contains a Piston that is rotated by a Crankshaft..\n2. First Valve is Intake valve which opens for Air and Fuel mixture..\n3. Second Valve is Exhaust valve which opens for exhaust gases to escape after internal combustion..\n4. A Spark plug which is responsible to ignite the air and Fuel mixture in the Cylinder..\nSo let us see the four Strokes..\nFIRST SROKE (INTAKE)\nThe intake valve opens and allows the air and Fuel mixture to fill in the Cylinder there by pushing the Piston down which rotated through the Crankshaft by the connecting rod..\nSECOND STROKE (COMPRESSION)\nThe Piston swivels up by one complete rotation and compresses the air and Fuel mixture both the valves remaining closed..\nTHIRD STROKE (POWER)\nSpark plug ignites the air and Fuel mixture by creating an explosion in the cylinder and forcing the Piston down which creates power to engine and both valves remaining closed..\nFOURTH STROKE (EXHAUST)\nThe Piston pushes out the burnt fuel through the exhaust valve which opens to lead the gases..\nThe above cycle repeats in the engine which drives the power to transmission and to the wheels.."}
{"_id": "7ebf5591", "question": "Which one has higher efficiency: a two stroke or four stroke petrol engine? Why?", "answers": "Mechanical efficiency: 2-Stroke. Because theoretically a two stroke engine produces the same amount power in a single revolution of the crankshaft as that produced by a 4-stroke in two revolutions.\nVolumetric Efficiency: 4-stroke. Because more time for mixing of fuel and supply.\nThermal Efficiency: 4-stroke. Thermal Efficiency = Work output/ Heat Input. Theoretically for the 2 stroke work output is double that of 4 stroke for a single revolution of the crankshaft and so is the fuel input. Practically, the work output is less and the since there are no separate valves, so a part of the incoming fuel mixes with the exhaust and leaves the chamber before burning. Hence the thermal efficiency will be less"}
{"_id": "85b47b61", "question": "Why are the flywheels in a 2 stroke engine lighter than in a 4 stroke engine?", "answers": "The two stroke engine’s flywheels can be lighter than a 4 stroke flywheel because they don’t have to carry the load for the extra exhaust and inlet stroke but are not always lighter than a similar power rated four cycle engine, as the flywheels, are usually solid steel or nodular cast iron and are typically larger in diameter than the stroke of the camshaft as the crank pin is pressed into a hole in each one. The loading on the crank pin determines its size, therefore the size of the hole in the flywheel and the amount of metal radially outside the hole.\nThe volume of the crank case is determined by the flywheel size, and if the piston, on the down stroke has to develop sufficient pressure to force the air/fuel charge into the cylinder through the transfer port, to develop sufficient pressure, the crank case must be filled as much as possible by the flywheels, so, by necessity the flywheels may end up quite heavy. If it was absolutely imperative the flywheels must be very light to get more rapid acceleration, the flywheels could be cast or forged in the shape of a typical 4-stroke crankshaft, then a light metal, could be cast to it to fill up the crank case. Cost goes up with performance but, for a professional racer, it could be worth it. The size of the flywheel is also taken into consideration of ease of starting and operating rpm band, needing to be large and heavy if the engine is to operate at very low speeds and if also to have great torque at low speed. Two cycle engines are very inexpensive to modify for increased speed and power as ports can easily have much less flow restriction than poppet valves."}
{"_id": "82c1d3c5", "question": "Though a 2-stroke engine has a better power output than a 4-stroke engine even then we use 4-stroke engine in cars. Can we tweak a 2-stroke engine for better efficiency than a 4-stroke, why or why not?", "answers": "The answer very easy. Emissions.\nI should end it right there because that’s the big one and being on my phone and limited time I’m going to leave things out and I’m going to make blanket statements that need more explanation but no time to do so.\nMany people don’t realize that a huge reason for DOHC engines is for cleaner emissions and a distant second place is for power. With this setup you can alter valve timing, cam phase, overlap (which can’t be done with a SOHC) advance and retard overall timing to the point EGR is not always needed or needed less. It’s also nice to have a smooth idle which also brings hydrocarbons way down while still pulling strong to high rpm. While I love an old car with big cam and lopey idle to move the power up in the rpm range, idle has to suffer and vice versa. Catalysts don’t last but days on a big cam car and I use them to pass emissions for an hour and off it comes.\nBut enough about cam/valve timing, a 2-stroke is extremely hard if not impossible to bring into the strict emissions compliance to be legal in the US and most of the world. There’s no fine tuning of intake and exhaust “valve “ timing based on rpm and load , there’s really no adjustable timing at all except for some crude and unpopular designs.\nEven if you could control the intake and exhaust events by rpm and load, a 2-stroke is dirty by nature. The most obvious is oil in the fuel. While the ratios can be very high, with little oil needing to be mixed in, this goes against it. A converter will clean it up but life will be decreased. Some don’t need oil in the fuel.\nAs bad as oil burning, combustion is incomplete a lot of the time, causing hydrocarbons to go off the chart. When they’re “bubbling” and not “clean”, no converter will have a chance of reducing the hydrocarbons to acceptable levels. It’s a mix of “EGR” sort of , diluting the intake charge. When they’re clean and more efficient, in their powerband NOx is off the charts.\nFuel economy is another huge problem. If you took a 4stroke and a 2-stroke with the same power level and ran them at full throttle, fuel usage is close. For part throttle operation which is 95%, the 4-stroke gets much better mpg. Before anyone says anything, there are “narrow rpm” 2-strokes out there in marine applications that can be tuned to be very efficient with a near constant engine speed. That obviously doesn’t work well in a car. That’s what all of the variable valve timing tech and variable intake runner length and other technologies are for in our daily driven 4 strokes, to make them more efficient at every rpm and load, both mpg and power.\nThere are other reasons but I think I covered the main ones. Power delivery/torque gets honorable mention. The 2-stroke has a narrower powerband and makes less torque for its power output, resulting in needing more rpm to make its power, it’s hard to justify it in a regular automobile. You would need a way to keep rpms considerably higher than a comparable 4-stroke. I’m a manual, maybe a much shorter 1st gear so you don’t need to skip the clutch excessively and more closely spaced gears. With an auto, a higher stall converter will further kill mpg. I have a turbo car with a 5,800rpm stall and just to keep up with traffic when taking off from a light, with 1/10th throttle, rpms hover around 3,200 and with just a slight touch of the throttle you’re at 4K just to easily pass someone. It’s lots of fun but after owning it for years it’s just not practical for a daily and it gets 8mpg in the city if I behave myself and that’s for a V6 that only sees boost rarely. For comparison my other one is built similarly but has a smaller but much more modern and responsive turbo, only requiring a 2,800rpm stall and it gets 13–16 city. Obviously highway isn’t a problem with every car having a lockup converter (most logic locks them constantly in the city when appropriate) but even the final drive would have to be lower, I can imagine lugging a 2-stroke down the freeway at 1,500rpm at 70mph. Honestly a current 2-stroke would need to spin fewer rpm per mile covered to begin getting ok mpg. I’m thinking of power strokes per mile even if cylinder pressures were the same.\nI had high hopes direct gasoline injection might help bring the 2-stroke back for consideration, along with exotic valving technologies but it doesn’t seem so. It is a match made in heaven for 4 stroke turbocharging, enabling much higher boost on a given octane without preignition and with the newest batch of turbos, enabling a tiny 2.0 4 cylinder to make 250lbs of torque at 1,500rpm and 260hp, pulling strong to 7,000rpm. 260hp from a turbo 2.0 has been exceeded decades ago but they were laggy, usually needed more octane than pump gas would allow, and from what I saw on the streets and the track, not too reliable.\nMy point above is that with DI and turbocharging you get a small engine that makes the power of a larger engine and drives just like a larger engined car while hauling around a 3,900lb 5 series which demands a lot more than a 2,000lb gutted Civic. No lag and good power right off of idle, more torque made at a lower rpm, giving more power at a lower rpm, usually, exceeding its larger NA alternative in off idle power and peak power. Better mpg and no hit to emissions with a fatter powerband than just about any NA engine. Sort of the nail in the coffin for 2-strokes even if they overcame the emissions hurdles, with the mentioned advantages, and now specific output and size and weight becoming more similar (not the same yet) with the turbo DI 4-strokes. In theory the 2-stroke seems the better choice with twice as many power strokes at a given rpm but so far we don’t have the technology to make them practical in cars. Maybe an old Detroit supercharged/turbocharged 2-stroke diesel scaled down and drastically moddedwould be the basic model to start from. Probably not."}
{"_id": "4b6afc58", "question": "How does a 6 stroke engine work?", "answers": "Think about a normal four-stroke engine. The piston moves down to suck in air and fuel, then the fuel pushes up to compress, then the spark plug fires and the burning gas forces the piston down. Then the piston moves back up to push up the exhaust. The six-stroke engine adds two more strokes after the exhaust stroke. Water is injected, and as it turns into steam, it pushes the piston down. Then the piston comes back up to force out the steam. It's really simple.\nA six-stroke engine combines an internal combustion engine with a steam engine to turn some of the waste heat into power. The only catch is that you have to add a water tank to your car that's about the same size as the gas tank. The good news is that you can probably eliminate the radiator. (As per HSW)\nThe video might clearly explain you that.\nThe main use of it is to increase the efficiency to near 40%. Actually the efficiency of petrol engines will be around 25-35%.."}
{"_id": "aab1ad16", "question": "Can your mind heal after a stroke?", "answers": "It depends on several things.\nThis comes from personal experiences watching my father in law go through one.\n1) type of stroke. A Hemorrhage is easier to recover from than a blocked vessel as it involves releaving the pressure. A blocked vessel is much harder to clear quickly.\nThere is still archangel for damage long term depending on reaction to symptoms. In his case it was too long if it was a clot, but because it was pressure he regained virtually all his functions back after removal and replacement of a piece of skull. Had it been a clot the time frame would have been FAR to long, almost 5-6 hours from symptoms to surgery to releive pressure.\nI say mostly when it comes to his recovery. There are still some cognitive issues from damage bit if you didn't know him, you'd never notice.\n2) location of the stroke. Certain locations are far less severe, but correct treatment is necessary. My grandfather had a stroke in his neck. Had he stayed at the hospital, and on bed rest, he'd have recovered with no issues. He believed nothing was wrong and felt fine in bed, so he checked himself out. He returned 2 hours later with a full on stroke and now struggles with movement on one side of his body.\nHis stubbornness against staying still and the location caused the issue.\n3) time\nThe longer you wait the worse the recovery. Regardless of type or location of the stroke."}
{"_id": "ab247f19", "question": "What is a stroke?", "answers": "When the blood flow to your brain is interrupted, it is a medical emergency known as a stroke. When the flow of blood to your brain is stopped the time it takes to get medical treatment is critical. As many neurologists will tell you, “Time is brain”. What this means is anytime the flow of blood to your brain is interrupted, the damage is occurring and prompt medical treatment at a hospital is needed. The sooner you can get medical treatment, the more likely you are to have a better outcome.\nWe usually think of stroke as a blood clot stopping the flow of blood in your brain. This is, in fact, the most common type of stroke called an ischemic stroke. According to the American Heart Association, 87% of stokes are estimated to be ischemic. There are three main types of stokes and all are considered medical emergencies.\nAnother type of stoke is a hemorrhagic stroke. A hemorrhagic stroke occurs when a blood vessel ruptures in your head. This can be caused by an aneurysm, an arteriovenous malformation, or a weakened small blood vessel caused by very high blood pressure.\nLastly, a transient ischemic attack or TIA is also called a mini-stroke or a warning stroke. TIA’s are caused by a temporary blood clot that lasts for a shorter period of time. They are usually a warning sign that something is going on and a full ischemic stroke is likely if treatment is not sought.\nOur brains are complex and affect all parts of our body including movement, speech, learning, and so much more. When the blood flow to your brain is stopped either by a clot or a bleed it is vital to your outcome to get medical treatment immediately. So how can you tell if someone is having a stroke? The American Stroke Association has set the following guidelines to help everyone recognize the common symptoms of a stroke.\nRemember this acronym to help determine if someone is having a stroke: F.A.S.T.\nFace- Does one side of the person’s face appear to be drooping? Ask the person to smile- does one side of their mouth drop down?\nArm- Is one arm weak? Ask the person to raise both arms- does one arm drop down?\nSpeech- Is it slurred or difficult to understand?\nTime- Call 9-1-1- immediately. Time is brain! If you or someone you are with experience any of these symptoms, call 9-1-1 immediately.\nWhile these are the most common symptoms, it should also be noted that if someone complains of the worst headache of their life, has sudden confusion, trouble walking, or sudden problems with coordination they can also be signs of a stroke and immediate medical attention is needed. Remember, stroke is a medical emergency and the sooner you can get help, the more you improve the chances for a better outcome. [1]\nFootnotes\n[1] Post | OneHandReview"}
{"_id": "60712a8d", "question": "How does a two-stroke engine work?", "answers": "A two-stroke engine is a type of internal combustion engine which completes a power cycle with two strokes (up and down movements) of the piston during only one crankshaft revolution. Compared to four-stroke engines, two-stroke engines have a greatly reduced number of moving parts, and so can be more compact and significantly lighter.\n2 Stroke Petrol Engine-\nIts two strokes are described as follows:\nUpward Stroke: During the upward stroke, the piston moves from bottom dead centre to top dead centre, compressing the air-petrol mixture in the cylinder. The cylinder is connected to a closed crank chamber. Due to upward movement of the piston, a partial vacuum is created in the crankcase, and a new charge is drawn into the crankcase through the uncovered inlet port. The exhaust port and transfer port are covered when the piston is at the top dead centre position. The compressed charge is ignited in the combustion chamber by a spark provided by the spark plug.\nDownward Stroke: As soon as the charge is ignited, the hot gases force the piston to move downwards, rotating the crankshaft, thus doing the useful work. During this stroke the inlet port is covered by the piston and the new charge is compressed in the crank case. Further downward movement of the piston uncovers first the exhaust port and then the transfer port. The burnt gases escape through the exhaust port. As soon as the transfer port opens, the compressed charge from the crankcase flows into the cylinder. The charge is deflected upwards by the pump provided on the head of the piston and pushes out most of the exhaust gases. It may be noted that the incoming air-petrol mixture helps the removal of burnt gases from the engine cylinder, which is called as the scavenging process. If in case these exhaust gases do not leave the cylinder, the fresh charge gets diluted and efficiency of the engine will decrease. The cycle of events is then repeated.\n2 Stroke Diesel Engine-\nIn a two stroke cycle diesel engine, only air is compressed inside the cylinder and the diesel is injected by an injector. There is no spark plug in this engine. The remaining operations of the two stroke cycle diesel engine are exactly the same as those of the two stroke cycle petrol engine. Its two strokes are described as follows:\nUpward Stroke: During the upward stroke, the piston moves from bottom dead centre to top dead centre, compressing the air in the cylinder. The cylinder is connected to a closed crank chamber. Due to upward movement of the piston, a partial vacuum is created in the crankcase, and a new charge is drawn into the crankcase through the uncovered inlet port. The exhaust port and transfer port are covered when the piston is at the top dead centre position. The compressed charge is mixed with the injected diesel and gets auto-ignited in the combustion chamber because of the high pressure and temperature present.\nDownward Stroke: As soon as the fuel is ignited, the hot gases force the piston to move downwards, rotating the crankshaft, thus doing the useful work. During this stroke the inlet port is covered by the piston and the new charge is compressed in the crank case. Further downward movement of the piston uncovers first the exhaust port and then the transfer port. The burnt gases escape through the exhaust port. As soon as the transfer port opens, the compressed charge from the crankcase flows into the cylinder. The charge is deflected upwards by the pump provided on the head of the piston and pushes out most of the exhaust gases. It may be noted that the incoming air helps the removal of burnt gases from the engine cylinder, which is called as scavenging process. If in case these exhaust gases do not leave the cylinder, the fresh charge gets diluted and efficiency of the engine will decrease. The cycle of events is then repeated."}
{"_id": "9e90bf7f", "question": "What is some real life experience of a brain stroke? What were the symptoms prior to the stroke? Were there symptoms weeks/days before the stroke? Was there any mini stroke before the major stroke?", "answers": "First of all, ‘brain stroke’ is a silly term. All strokes occur in the brain.\nPrior to my strokes, I was brilliant. I was a master’s student at Caltech and had just moved to Colorado, where our little town with no traffic lights far exceeded life in the perpetual parking lot of Los Angeles. I hiked all around the Front Range with my beloved dog, Chaco, and our new puppy, Bonzo. Life was GOOD.\nOne Friday in September, I flew back from Seattle — my first business trip. When I woke up the next morning, I seemed to me like I was ‘losing it’. I listened to my husband, a former lecturer at Caltech, preach for over an hour about the ins and outs of Java, which was pretty uncharacteristic of me. I slept for over ten hours, which was really unusual for me; I was used to life at Caltech, where problem sets that lasted all night had killed my ability to sleep for that long. My face was ‘lopsided’, to quote my husband. I got lost going down to Boulder for a football game — VERY uncharacteristic of me, as I was a geologist. (We’re known for being able to tell you where north is at all times.) And I exhibited aphasia, which is when you can’t recall the correct words for things. (I emailed a close friend that “I’d like to meet you at the pizza place, but it burned down.” Which was fine except that the pizza restaurant I had been referencing hadn’t, indeed, burned down, but was simply closed for a week. Oops.)\nThat was my “zeroth” stroke. I call it that because the symptoms resolved themselves within about a week and weren’t particularly severe AND to pester a particularly annoying doctor I once visited who told me “What do you mean by zeroth stroke? That makes no sense. Please call them stroke #1, #2, and #3.” I thought my nomenclature was pretty clever. ;)\nTwo weeks later, I was sitting in my office down in Boulder when my arm became paralyzed. Then it kind of resolved before returning to dead weight. When my foot followed suit, I called the lady across the hall for some help. She called another coworker of mine, who called the nurse, who said in no uncertain terms to call 9–1–1. I got a nice ride to the hospital from some friendly EMS personnel.\nThat was stroke #2. My stay at Casa Hospital lasted two nights, after which I was discharged with orders to attend PT (because, though I could walk, it wasn’t real smooth yet), OT (because my hand strength was abysmal), and ST (because I was still suffering from aphasia).\nFive and a half months later, I suffered a THIRD stroke, which was, in my case, ‘the kiss of death’. While my first stroke was somewhere in the back of my brain, and my second was in my right basal ganglia, my third was in my left basal ganglia. I STRONGLY urge people to avoid bilateral injuries to their brains! In my case, it made the medications I was on to keep my awake virtually useless. Picture coffee doing nothing for you except making you jittery — not improving your cognition or wakefulness or doing anything remotely useful.\nIn my case, I could probably have avoided the third stroke in two ways: (1) I could have gone to the doctor (whom I didn’t yet have) or ER after my first stroke or (2) I could have insisted that I be put on something stronger than aspirin after my second stroke. Cie la vie, I suppose =(\nNow, 12 years later, I’ve gotten much better. Ironically, I became depressed after my third stroke, which led me to discover a medication that wakes me up called Wellbutrin. Wellbutrin is an antidepressant with few of the side effects common to SSRIs — AND, instead of making you sluggish, it’s like being on Adderall. I’ve also discovered a new therapy that has woken me up significantly; it’s a vision therapy pioneered by a doctor in Chicago. And I’m finding it fairly difficult to remember what it was like to be me 12 years ago; it is difficult to know how awake I felt then versus now. I have a sense of “not feeling right” some days, but I can no longer say for sure, “I could have [spent a morning at the trampoline park without going home and sleeping for two days] before.”"}
{"_id": "08748645", "question": "What happens when you pour 2-stroke oil into a 4-stroke vehicle?", "answers": "If you pour 2-stroke oil into the oil fill on the 4-stroke engine, not much. It is probably a little thin and so it won’t lubricate as well as your engine manual might specify. I doubt you would notice for 1 oil change. If you keep doing it, you are likely under-lubricating the engine and that will increase wear.\nIf you pour 2-stroke oil into the gas tank, not much. You will get lots of smoke, some rough running, and eventually you will foul the spark plugs. If you do it once, I would say it is not a big deal. If you do it regularly, you can expect to wear out the plugs and possibly the exhaust system."}
{"_id": "5b727eea", "question": "Emergency Medicine: How are stroke patients treated?", "answers": "Treatment\nEmergency treatment for stroke depends on whether you're having an ischemic stroke blocking an artery — the most common kind — or a hemorrhagic stroke that involves bleeding into the brain.\nIschemic stroke\nTo treat an ischemic\nstroke\n, doctors must quickly restore blood flow to your brain.\nEmergency treatment with medications. Therapy with clot-busting drugs must start within 4.5 hours if they are given into the vein — and the sooner, the better. Quick treatment not only improves your chances of survival but also may reduce complications. You may be given:\nIntravenous injection of tissue plasminogen activator (tPA). This injection of recombinant tissue plasminogen activator (tPA), also called alteplase, is considered the gold standard treatment for ischemic stroke. An injection of tPA is usually given through a vein in the arm. This potent clot-busting drug ideally is given within three hours. In some instances, tPA can be given up to 4.5 hours after stroke symptoms begin.This drug restores blood flow by dissolving the blood clot causing your stroke, and it may help people who have had strokes recover more fully. Your doctor will consider certain risks, such as potential bleeding in the brain, to determine if tPA is appropriate for you.\nEmergency endovascular procedures. Doctors sometimes treat ischemic strokes with procedures performed directly inside the blocked blood vessel. These procedures must be performed as soon as possible, depending on features of the blood clot:\nMedications delivered directly to the brain. Doctors may insert a long, thin tube (catheter) through an artery in your groin and thread it to your brain to deliver tPA directly into the area where the stroke is occurring. This is called intra-arterial thrombolysis. The time window for this treatment is somewhat longer than for intravenous tPA, but is still limited.\nRemoving the clot with a stent retriever. Doctors may use a catheter to maneuver a device into the blocked blood vessel in your brain and trap and remove the clot. This procedure is particularly beneficial for people with large clots that can't be completely dissolved with tPA, though this procedure is often performed in combination with intravenous tPA.\nSeveral large and recent studies suggest that, depending on the location of the clot and other factors, endovascular therapy might be the most effective treatment. Endovascular therapy has been shown to significantly improve outcomes and reduce long-term disability after ischemic stroke.\nOther procedures. To decrease your risk of having another stroke or transient ischemic attack, your doctor may recommend a procedure to open up an artery that's narrowed by plaque. Doctors sometimes recommend the following procedures to prevent a stroke. Options will vary depending on your situation:\nCarotid endarterectomy. In a carotid endarterectomy, a surgeon removes plaques from arteries that run along each side of your neck to your brain (carotid arteries). In this procedure, your surgeon makes an incision along the front of your neck, opens your carotid artery and removes plaque that blocks the carotid artery.Your surgeon then repairs the artery with stitches or a patch made from a vein or artificial material (graft). The procedure may reduce your risk of ischemic stroke. However, a carotid endarterectomy also involves risks, especially for people with heart disease or other medical conditions.\nAngioplasty and stents. In an angioplasty, a surgeon usually accesses your carotid arteries through an artery in your groin. Here, your surgeon can gently and safely navigate to the carotid arteries in your neck. A balloon is then inflated to expand the narrowed artery. Then a stent can be inserted to support the opened artery.\nHemorrhagic stroke\nEmergency treatment of hemorrhagic stroke focuses on controlling your bleeding and reducing pressure in your brain. You might also need surgery to help reduce future risk.\nEmergency measures. If you take warfarin (Coumadin, Jantoven) or anti-platelet drugs such as clopidogrel (Plavix) to prevent blood clots, you may be given drugs or transfusions of blood products to counteract the blood thinners' effects. You may also be given drugs to lower pressure in your brain (intracranial pressure), lower your blood pressure, prevent vasospasm or prevent seizures.\nOnce the bleeding in your brain stops, treatment usually involves supportive medical care while your body absorbs the blood. Healing is similar to what happens while a bad bruise goes away. If the area of bleeding is large, your doctor may perform surgery to remove the blood and relieve pressure on your brain.\nSurgical blood vessel repair. Surgery may be used to repair blood vessel abnormalities associated with hemorrhagic strokes. Your doctor may recommend one of these procedures after a stroke or if an aneurysm or arteriovenous malformation (AVM) or other type of vascular malformation caused your hemorrhagic stroke:\nSurgical clipping. A surgeon places a tiny clamp at the base of the aneurysm, to stop blood flow to it. This clamp can keep the aneurysm from bursting, or it can prevent re-bleeding of an aneurysm that has recently hemorrhaged.\nCoiling (endovascular embolization). A surgeon inserts a catheter into an artery in your groin and guides it to your brain using X-ray imaging. Tiny detachable coils are guided into the aneurysm (aneurysm coiling). The coils fill the aneurysm, which blocks blood flow into the aneurysm and causes the blood to clot.\nSurgical AVM removal. Surgeons may remove a smaller AVM if it's located in an accessible area of your brain, to eliminate the risk of rupture and lower the risk of hemorrhagic stroke. However, it's not always possible to remove an AVM if its removal would cause too large a reduction in brain function, or if it's large or located deep within your brain.\nStereotactic radiosurgery. Using multiple beams of highly focused radiation, stereotactic radiosurgery is an advanced minimally invasive treatment used to repair vascular malformations."}
{"_id": "afd59169", "question": "Why don't we have 3 stroke engine?", "answers": "Yes we have three strike engine.A Variable cycle three-stroke engine is a type of internal combustion engine, patented by Michael A. V. Ward, US patent 5454352 dated Oct 3, 1995. Although the engine runs on the four-stroke cycle, the cycle is completed in one revolution of the crankshaft, as in the Atkinson cycle engine. However, this is achieved by the use of an elliptical cam instead of the jointed linkage used in the Atkinson engine.The three stroke engine does not exist in reality but according to the patent this cycle can be termed as 3 stroke. In real it is a 2 stroke engine. The term \"three-stroke\" indicates that, to quote from the patent, \"total cycle displacement (of) the engine equals approximately three expansion ratios.\nA virtual three-stroke engine with intake and compression strokes approximately one half of the power stroke of approximately 12 to one expansion ratio and with total firing cycle stroke lengths equal to approximately three expansion strokes to minimize engine throttling and frictional losses over the real world drive cycle and provide high torque from a one-to-one drive shaft RPM to engine firing cycle RPM provided by a cam type driver for controlling the piston motions and extracting the power from the piston."}
{"_id": "628de02b", "question": "What is meant by the stroke of an engine?", "answers": "The stroke of an engine means the completion of the piston movement in cylinder from TDC (top dead centre) to BDC(BOTTOM DEAD CENTRE) of cylinder……\nStroke also means the distance travelled by the piston\nTypes:\nFour stroke internal combustion:\nIn this their are in all 4 strokes completed by the piston\nSUCTION: Fuel is taken inside the cylinder Piston moves down.\nCOMPRESSION: Piston Moves up and compresses the fuel inside the cylinder.\nPOWER: Here spark plug gives a spark inside the cylimder and the blast of fuel takes the piston down.\nEXHAUST: Piston Moves up and let the smoke or the gas from burnt fuel out from outlet.\nTwo stroke internal combustion: Here the cycle is completed by only 2 strokes the up and down movement of the Piston.\nIt is not the complete Defination of strokes.\nIt is just a simple explanation.\nStrokes is a very big Concept…."}
{"_id": "0574f8e4", "question": "Is there any cure for a brain stroke?", "answers": "Each year, 795,000 people in the United States experience a symptomatic stroke. An estimated 6,600,000 Americans adults have had a symptomatic stroke, with a prevalence that increases with age, and 13,000,000 people in the United States have had a silent stroke that while clinically inapparent at onset might nonetheless impact long-term function. The mean survival after stroke is 6 to 7 years, with approximately 85% of patients living past the first year of stroke. Thus, the majority of patients with stroke survive the acute episode and live with enduring disability for years to come.[1]\nIn fact, at the onset of the brain attack, the body begins a healing process, to the affected area and others within the brain. Intervention, in this case, is essential as early as possible. By working with the patient to “relearn” some aspects, it accelerates this repair.\nErythropoietin, currently under trial, with the entire regimen initiated 1 to 7 days post-stroke, possibly by promoting neural stem cell proliferation. Treatments to Promote Neural Repair after\nStroke\nThere is hope to deal with brain strokes, the after-effects and risk of damage due to silent strokes.\nSome people have strokes without realizing it. They're called silent strokes, and they either have no easy-to-recognize symptoms, or you don't remember them. But they do cause permanent damage in your brain.\nIf you've had more than one silent stroke, you may have thinking and memory problems. They can also lead to more severe strokes. [2] The only way to confirm a silent stroke is by observation and, further studies are done through sophisticated imaging.\nFootnotes\n[1] Treatments to Promote Neural Repair after Stroke\n[2] Silent Stroke: What You Need to Know"}
{"_id": "b5cc5255", "question": "What is the difference between four stroke and two stroke engine?", "answers": "http://S.No\n.\nFirst line of answer is for 4 stroke and second line of answer is for 2 stroke\nFour\nstroke\nengine\nTwo stroke engine\n1.\nIt has one power stroke for every two revolutions of the crankshaft\n.\nIt has one power stroke for each revolution of the crankshaft.\n2.\nHeavy flywheel is required and engine runs unbalanced because turning moment on the crankshaft is not even due to one power stroke for every two revolutions of the crankshaft.\nLighter flywheel is required and engine runs balanced because turning moment is more even due to one power stroke for each revolution of the crankshaft.\n3.\nEngine is heavy\nEngine is light\n4.\nEngine design is complicated due to valve mechanism.\nEngine design is simple due to absence of valve mechanism.\n5.\nMore cost.\nLess cost than 4 stroke.\n6.\nLess mechanical efficiency due to more friction on many parts.\nMore mechanical efficiency due to less friction on a few parts.\n7.\nMore output due to full fresh charge intake and full burnt gases exhaust.\nLess output due to mixing of fresh charge with the hot burnt gases.\n8.\nEngine runs cooler.\nEngine runs hotter.\n9.\nEngine is water cooled.\nEngine is air cooled.\n10.\nLess fuel consumption and complete burning of fuel.\nMore fuel consumption and fresh charge is mixed with exhaust gases.\n11.\nEngine requires more space.\nEngine requires less space.\n12.\nComplicated lubricating system.\nSimple lubricating system.\n13.\nLess noise is created by engine.\nMore noise is created by engine.\n14.\nEngine consists of inlet and exhaust valve.\nEngine consists of inlet and exhaust ports.\n15.\nMore thermal efficiency.\nLess thermal efficiency.\n16.\nIt consumes less lubricating oil.\nIt consumes more lubricating oil.\n17.\nLess wear and tear of moving parts.\nMore wear and tear of moving parts."}
{"_id": "3af105a7", "question": "Do people fully recover from a stroke?", "answers": "Speaking as someone who has had one, I can say that is possible, although the extent of the stroke is probably unique to the individual and largely depends on what areas of the brain are affected and how the brain is able to ‘reroute’ past the damaged areas.\nWith loss of motor control, some alleviation may be possible by moving limbs in a recognised way, mimicking walking for example or raising one’s arm, which might help to stimulate the growth of new connections but this is not always very successful.\nIn my case, aphasia was the main symptom, the inability to speak, write or to regain even a partial command of my native language. However, a daily regimen of vocal exercises in front of a mirror (I always wondered what my neighbours thought of me reading aloud from ‘Winnie the Pooh’ or ‘House at Pooh Corner’ during such exercises) and the constant reference to a good thesaurus meant that I was back up to speed within, I guess, two years.\nI am still dyslexic when I write (but my typing appears to be OK) and have not tried to access my foreign language abilities very much, although I can follow a performed ‘Les Fourberies de Scapin’ in the original providing that I have the text of the play in front of me.\nHowever, the most important thing, in my view, is the support of one’s family and friends, the people who knew you from before the stroke and can offer feedback on how well you seem to them at all points in the recovery process; are you genuinely improving or is it just wishful thinking?"}
{"_id": "45d09db7", "question": "Why aren't 2-stroke engines used in cars?", "answers": "People have already mentioned the the main problems: fuel consumption, pollution, durability, and thermal efficiency. But none of this has to be the case. A two stroke can be designed to eliminate them, but at the risk of additional cost.\nIn a two stroke the transfer ports and exhaust ports are open at the same time. At some engine speeds, portions of the fuel mix go straight from the transfer ports out the exhaust without being burned. This leads to high fuel consumption and the ejection of unburned hydrocarbons. A solution is to use direct injection in which fuel is injected into the cylinder only after the ports close. This drastically reduces both problems.\nThe other source of pollution comes from the total loss lubrication in which unburned two-stroke oil passes directly out the exhaust ports. A solution is to replace the total oil loss system with full crankcase lubrication as found in four-stroke engines. To do this, the crankcase can no longer be used for scavenging, therefore a supercharger needs to be used for supplying the scavenging air. The drawback is that adds weight complexity, and expense to what was a lightweight inexpensive engine.\nEdit… I forgot to mentions something that many people find really annoying. That is the extremely lumpy idle and ring ding ding noise when closing the throttle. This is caused by uneven air and fuel supply caused by indirect injection and crankcase scavenging. . The use of supercharger scavenging and direct injection eliminate these issues entirely.\nIn addition, an oil-control ring needs to be added to the engine to stop oil leaking out the exhaust ports while the piston is close to top dead centre. There are two places to put this ring so oil doen’t leak out the exhaust ports. The first is to place the oil control ring at the bottom of the piston. This is not the best spot because the body of piston only gets a very thin film of oil to slide on. The second and much better solution is to insert the ring into a groove in the cylinder wall just below the exhaust ports. Achates does with their two-stroke diesel and reports very low oil consumption using this approach.\nThe durability issue seems to result from the poor the oil mist lubrication and from the extra heat from one combustion event per revolution as compared with a four stroke. In addition to using full crankcase lubrication, a means for cooling the underside needs to be provided, such as an oil jet. It is interesting that two-stroke ship diesels use full crankcase lubrication and oil-cooled pistons and are very reliable.\nI need to be specific about what aspect of thermal efficiency is problematic with two-stroke engines. The exhaust ports open before the piston reaches bottom dead centre, In many two strokes the port opens as much as 2/3 way down the stroke. At this point, the cylinder still has considerable pressure. This wastes energy and produces that familiar harsh exhaust note you hear from two-strokes. An answer is to use a much longer stroke to bore ratio, to allow fuller expansion before the exhaust port opens. This can have disadvantage of lowering the maximum permissible rpm of the engine due to higher piston and connecting rod loads.\nSo, the reasons two strokes are no longer used can be dealt with, but it may be cheaper to build a four stroke despite the extra valves, springs, and cams and cam chain."}
{"_id": "87f06c84", "question": "Is stroke linked to Alzheimer's disease?", "answers": "No, strokes don’t cause Alzheimer’s.\nHowever, Alzheimer’s is just one type of dementia, and there are quite a few other types, with the largest being “mixed”, or Alzheimer’s and something else. And what a stroke can do- besides causing dementia, itself- is speed up the damage going on in the brain when any kind of dementia is already present.\nAnd, keep in mind it is thought Alzheimer’s is “present” but undiagnosed because it just hasn’t gotten to the point it is interfering with life, up to ten years before such interference, so that, a stroke in that ten or-so year period can make it seem it was the cause of Alzheimer’s. It likely wasn’t; it just sped up the damage.\nAvoiding a stroke is one of the top five ways to avoid any dementia. Doesn’t mean no-stroke-no-dementia, just that stroke is, itself indicted in some forms of dementia."}
{"_id": "bd12310d", "question": "How high does blood pressure have to be to increase stroke risk?", "answers": "I am Kristen Gardner. Let me share some high blood pressure tricks from Bessie Vazquez’s website: Top 8 tips that can help to lower your high blood pressure in just 9 mins. Bessie Vazquez is a famous blogger about blood pressure.\nBessie Vazquez’s Tip 1: Lose weight. Being overweight means that your heart has to pump blood to a larger body mass, which makes the heart work harder. Losing weight reduces the workload. “Plus, your heart will be better able to respond to circumstances that do require more work, like exercise,” says Dr. Zusman.\nBessie Vazquez’s Tip 2: Exercise. Any activity that gets your heart pumping faster and your lungs working harder is one of the best ways to lower high blood pressure. “It improves the blood vessels’ ability to open and close, which improves blood flow,” says Dr. Zusman. Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity activity per week, such as brisk walking.\nBessie Vazquez’s Tip 3: Reduce your stress. Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.\nBessie Vazquez’s Tip 4: Reduce sodium in your diet\nBessie Vazquez’s Tip 5: Control underlying conditions.\nBessie Vazquez’s Tip 6: Stop caffeine.\nBessie Vazquez’s Tip 7: Limit alcohol intake.\nBessie Vazquez’s Tip 8: Stop smoking.\nUseful resources:\n1- Wikipedia: Hypertension - Wikipedia\n2- HypertensionTips68: Exercise tips for high blood pressure\n3- Yoga solution from Quora: What are best yoga to control blood pressure?\n4- HBPtips365: 21 ways to cure high blood pressure"}
{"_id": "69fb8300", "question": "If the power of a two stroke engine is more than of a comparable four stroke engine, why are four stroke engines used more?", "answers": "In 2 strike engine power is produced every 2 strokes or 1 revolution of the crankshaft. Whereas in 4 stroke engine Power is produced every 4 strokes or 2 revolutions of the crankshaft. So theoretically 2 stroke must produce twice the 4 stroke. But practically it is not so due to many reasons, major being the way of fuel utilization.\nIn 4 s there are separate valves which regulate these activities. But in 2 s there is only the port system and the fuel exchange is taking place due to the scavenging effect (fresh charge displacing the used charge).\nSo there is lot of fuel going waste since units method is not very efficient and precise. Also due to this mixing of charges the efficiency of combustion (which relates to more power) is very less. So incomplete combustion is taking place, leading to more poisonous by products. Nowadays with strict emission norms (BS-IV). It is difficult to maintain the norms with the emissions.\nAlso there is more load on the crankshaft (this is nearly 2 times because power is produced every stroke). More wear and tear of the parts. So on.\nWith present technology lot of improvement has been done to increase this efficiency of combustion to increase the power output(like CRDI which literally sprays 4 times during combustion, this would be difficult in 2 s as by that time exhaust valve will be open). So practically with 4s same output can be got as that of 2s with less wear and tear. So 4s is used more."}
{"_id": "54dd8da6", "question": "How long does it take to recover from a stroke?", "answers": "Hi\nI am stroke survivor (Feb 2012) . It is now 5 years and to think it was FIVE long years or\n2628000 seconds or 43800 minutes or 1825 days ,. It is only the mind that matters ,.\nI have the memory of going to the Hospital on the the 7th ,30th,45th day and after that it became every 2 months,. I was BACK the day when I was back at Home.\nThe subject of this note should how QUICK does it take for an average person to get over a stroke ,.It is in micro seconds ….Mind i was a smoker ,used to eat every thing ,.\nGanesh"}
{"_id": "1511c351", "question": "What is the difference between a four-stroke, and a two-stroke, diesel engine?", "answers": "Same as on any IC combustion engine.\nFour stroke have intake and exhaust valves that must open and close at precise points of the different strokes, and have four different phases or “strokes”, inlet stroke (piston goes down, inlet valves open, fuel mix is sucked in) compression stroke (piston goes up and compresses the fuel/air mix) explosion stroke (spark ignites the mix, piston goes down producing power) and exhaust stroke (exhaust vale opens, piston goes up and burned gas goes out). That’s one power stroke each two revolutions. The system used to open and close the valves is complex and heavy, as are the valves and cylinder head.\nFour-stroke engine - Wikipedia\nTwo stroke engines have no valves, only holes in the cylinder wall, which the piston itself opens and closes while going up and down. A moped two stroke does the pre-compression on the crankcase, but a diesel from a railroad engine uses a air compressor to force the mix thru the intake opening. They are simpler and have a power stroke every revolution, thus being more powerful for the same displacement. Being simpler they are also lighter.\nTwo-stroke engine - Wikipedia\nHope this helped. Have a nice day …"}
{"_id": "05bc3989", "question": "Why is the mechanical efficiency of a 2-strokes engine higher than a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": "\"Why is the mechanical efficiency of a two stroke engine higher than a four stroke engine?\"\nThe question asks why or which IC engine (two stroke or four stroke) is closer to being an ideal machine; that is, which comes closer to the elusive ideal of an engine's power input potential actually equaling the power output produced.\nBoth engines types convert heat into motion, and both are only between, say, 20%-40% thermally efficient, (with modern big diesels doing the best) with the other 60%-80% being lost as waste heat.\nAnd the question doesn't constrain the answer with comparing two specific engines, asking only for generalities, and therefore freeing the answer to be expressed simply:\nThe answer is friction.\nFriction converts motion into heat, hence friction removes motion. (efficiency)\nA two stroke engine has a power stroke with every crank revolution, while a four stroke only has a power stroke with every two crank revolutions, meaning the two stroke basically has half the frictional loss to overcome with each power stroke, compared to that of the four stroke, and this frictional loss is compounded by the more complex design of the four stroke engine, which has many, many more internal parts to keep in motion (more work and, consequently, more frictional losses) than that of the much simpler design of the two stroke engine.\nBut that said, lack of positive environmental efficiency is the Achilles Heal of the two stroke engine, and the main reason for its current status."}
{"_id": "3dd1926b", "question": "Where do cats like to be petted?", "answers": "There are way too many variations between one cat and another to be precise, it also depends on how well you and the cat know one another. A matter of trust is involved.\nBut as a general rule with all cats under all circumstances, first check the tail. if it is still then a cautious tickle can be tried behind the ear, and depending on how that is received you can take it from there - always watching the tail, if it starts wagging you have gone too far.\nThe basic rule of thumb is to concentrate on the spots that are the hardest for the cat to reach when grooming herself. So cheeks, top of head, behind ears, under chin are all universal sweet spots, once purring starts, you can experiment a little while always noting the tail. Except for it shooting straight up on stroking, (Nice) any movement of the tail is an advance warning that whatever you just did was not welcomed. (Not nice).\nThis warning if disregarded, will be followed up with action.\nThat may be with a playful nip while holding your hand gently with her claw tips and staring at you with a “I could hurt you if I wanted to” look, to the more advanced swipe with claws and bite followed immediately with an ungraceful scrabble to get away from you, which if you are not ready, can cause severe, even if unintended, damage to any bits of you that may be exposed.\nAlways pay close attention to the tail. It will save a lot of bloodshed and be the facilitator of a closer and more trusting relationship with your cat if kept immobile.\nNote: I have currently two cats both Siamese. One loves having her tummy tickled and would let you do it all day while she floats dreamily on. The other would attempt to amputate your hand if it got within an inch or two of her tummy, a fiercely wagged tail and growling warns you off, but subsides immediately and returns to purrs if attention is returned to her ears and chin.\nOther than that, they are quite the same so never take anything for granted with a cat.\nIf you are still here and want some more pearls, then read on…\nWhile you are making friends with a cat, you should avoid sudden movements as it makes them nervous. Once a level of trust is established you can do as you like but the trust must be there first.\nIf your cat settles on your lap or close by, but in contact, (maybe a head resting on your hand or just touching) note which way they lay especially when sleeping. If they are facing you, it may look nice and friendly, but in reality it is because they don’t trust you and are keeping a wary eye out. If they face away from you, it is not a sign of disrespect, but that they trust you enough to risk turning their back to keep a look out for exterior risks instead. You are now officially a friend and have earned a measure of trust.\nYou can start to play some games now, chasing a bit of string is a good starter, it will illustrate how far along the friendship has progressed. If she catches the string and starts giving it some tooth and claw treatment, does it stop with the string or continue on to your hand with equal vigour?\nIf she continues the savaging on to you, then she isn’t paying enough attention to what she is doing because she doesn’t care, but if the savaging stops with the string, then she recognises you as a friend and doesn’t want to hurt you.\n\nPaying attention to little things like this will help a friendship with a cat along quite a bit, but as naturally solitary animals only time will cement a true deep and meaningful relationship. Try to avoid startling your cat, unpleasant surprises don’t do anything to built trust, they do like to be able to settle into stable unmoving environments where they don’t get surprised - play excepted, where if in the mood, anything goes - cats love a quiet predictable lifestyle, and will love you for it all the more if they can predict how you will act and be judged non-threatening to them."}
{"_id": "54a4327d", "question": "What is a 2-stroke engine?", "answers": "A 2-stroke engine is an engine in which there are 2 phases in a cycle of operation of the engine. Stroke basically, means the sudden movement of piston which is converted into a rotary motion at crankshaft. This rotation is coupled to gear system and differential, which turns the wheel.\nThe engine contains 3 openings as shown- Inlet, Exit and Transfer ports\nThere are basically 4 processes in a petrol/diesel engine- Introduction of fuel, Compression, Ignition and Exhaust.\nIn a 4 stroke engine, these 4 processes happen in 4 different strokes. Here, introduction of fuel and compression happens in the first stroke and the next 2 processes in the other.\n1. In the first stroke of piston, the piston moves from top to bottom. When the piston is at the top, inlet port is open for the fuel to enter. The piston descends and blocks the inlet port and its further descent pushes the air-fuel mixture into transfer port.\n2. Now, the piston moves from bottom to top. The air-fuel mixture coming out of transfer port is present in the cylinder and this is compressed by the piston, which moves upward. At this stage,\nIn a petrol engine, when the mixture is compressed, it is ignited by the spark plug and the mixture undergoes combustion.\nIn a diesel engine, the mixture is compressed to a greater pressure at which the mixture self-ignites.\nThe gases, produced after combustion expands and pushes the piston downwards and the CYCLE REPEATS ITSELF.\nThis is the working of a 2 stroke engine. Some info about this type of engine:\nIn each stroke, crankshaft rotates HALFWAY as opposed to a 4 stroke engine where it rotates ONE-QUARTER. Thus, for a given volume of the cylinder, a 2 stroke engine develops MORE POWER than 4 stroke engine.\nThe combustion is not complete and very noisy.\nIt consumes more amount of fuel and hence, less fuel efficient.\nN.B. This is a continuous process. To start the engine, you have to initiate the first downward movement of the piston, either manually(by kicking the lever) or electronically, by use of motor(power start)."}
{"_id": "86dfe511", "question": "What is the easiest swimming stroke to learn for beginners?", "answers": "First, “Free-style” is not a swimming stroke. It’s a competative event permitting the use of a variety of strokes.\nThe easiest stroke for a complete beginner to learn will depend on body density (float-ability)\nIf someone can float easily on their back, the “Elementary Backstroke” is exceedingly easy to learn, and requires very little coordination to be effective. The only real concern for new swimmers is being able to tolerate water occasionally sloshing over their face and nose.\nIf floating on their back is difficult for a new swimmer, the “Breaststroke” is typically easy to learn because the arm motion at least, is a fairly natural motion. However, it takes a fair amount of practice to develop the coordination to make this stroke effective.\n“Sidestroke” is perhaps a touch more difficult to learn than “Breaststroke”, but once someone has nailed the correct movements, it’s not complicated at all to perform the stroke with reasonable efficiency."}
{"_id": "aac1288a", "question": "How does a 4-stroke engine work?", "answers": "To start off there are a few terms you should know:\nInlet valve\nExhaust valve\nPiston\nConnecting Rod\nCrank shaft\nSpark plug\n1.) Valves: These can be opened and closed to facilitate the movement of the air and fuel mixture throughout inside the engine cylinder\n2.) Piston: a short cylinder fitting closely within a tube in which it moves up and down against a liquid or gas, it’s basic function is to impart motion.\n3.) Connecting rod: A mechanical part that connects the piston to the crank shaft.\n4.) Spark plug : It is used to deliver electric current in an IC engine.\nThere are basically 4 parts into which the working of a four stroke engine can be divided :\nIntake stroke\nCompression stroke\nPower stroke\nExhaust stroke\nINTAKE STROKE :\nIn the intake stroke the air fuel mixture enter’s into the engine with the help of the inlet valve.\nThe piston’s position moves from the top dead centre to the bottom dead centre. (ie: top to bottom)\nThe exhaust valve remains closed in this stroke.\nCOMPRESSION STROKE :\nIn this stroke the piston moves from the bottom dead centre to the top dead centre. (ie: bottom to top)\nThe air-fuel mixture drawn in during the intake stroke is pressurised by the piston. The value of the pressure in the system rises to a value of about 8 bar.\nJust before the end of this stroke the operating plug initiates a spark which ignites the mixture and combustion takes place inside the engine cylinder.\nBoth the inlet and exhaust valve remain closed during the operation of this stroke\nPOWER STROKE :\nWhen combustion takes place, gasses are produced in the engine, these gasses again force the piston to move from the top dead centre to the bottom dead centre.\nThe power generated during this movement is obtained as work\nBoth valves remain closed at the start of this stroke but as the piston moves to the top dead centre, the exhaust valve starts opening.\nEXHAUST STROKE :\nAfter combustion the gasses that are collected inside the engine cylinder become useless.\nThese gasses are made to escape through the exhaust valve in the engine.\nThe movement of the piston is from the bottom dead centre to the top dead centre in this stroke, finally reaching the same position as it was at the beginning of the 4 stroke cycle.\nThe inlet valve remains closed during this stroke"}
{"_id": "437fedae", "question": "Why is two stroke diesel engine rarely used?", "answers": "There are PLENTY or two stroke diesels. GM had a 2 stroke V6 diesel which was used in millions of buses.\nThe WW2 American submarines all use Fairbanks Morse opposed piston two stroke diesels in their submarines. And modern US nuclear subs also have one for auxilliary power if they have to completely shut down the nuclear plant.\nThe Doxford marine engine is a moving cylinder head uniflow 2 stroke diesel of up to about 7,000 kw power.\nThe Junkers Jumo aircraft engine of the 1930s was an opposed piston 2 stroke diesel.\nThe British Deltic diesel - 18 cylinders and 36 pistons in a triangular layout powered trains in the UK for many years.\nAnd the Commer Knocker engine. Three horizontal cylinders with 6 pistons and a single crankshaft connected by heavy rocker arms to the pistons. A large Rootes blower provides the scavenging. A very noisy engine when running, hence its name.\nThere is a Canadian ore ship (I forget the name ) which travels to a remote arctic mine site which uses a huge long stroke 2 stroke engine with maximum revolutions of 74 rpm!\nAnd the largest Diesel engine in the world is the 14 cylinder two stroke Watsila 96C flex engine which powers around 25 Mearsk container ships. It's a little over 107,000 hp at 102 rpm."}
{"_id": "589a207a", "question": "What happens if I mix petrol with oil in 4 stroke engine?", "answers": "Well mixing with oil in petrol can cause major problem.. but if ratio is good thn everything is better. I have my royal Enfield motor bike ;i mix 30ml of oil in 1 liter of petrol. Engine gets smooth. And it's runs very smoothly you can feel it when u add it. Adding oil in petrol in tank have another advantage.. as inside the tank it doesn't get rusted… if you want to check whether your oil mixing ratio is proper, just remove spark plug check for carbon deposit. If it's too black or some heavy carbon deposit. Make ratio of oil from 30ml to 20ml or even low depend upon engine cc.\nPlease note -\nIt's for royal Enfield Himalaya bike BS3 model\nNot recommend for fuel injectors bike (BS4)"}
{"_id": "14daaa18", "question": "Why do people that suffer from migraines have a higher risk of stroke?", "answers": "Yes it can. There are several migraine types that can—one reporter on TV, in fact, about a year ago, had a migraine attack on screen and they thought she had a stroke. It is very common.\nTo test if it is a stroke or migraine is hard because if you have hemiplegic, one side of your body will go off-line and tests for stroke will show stroke even if that’s not what you have. It is best to get into the hospital for a doctor’s examination to see if it is a stroke or migraine.\nMigraine is an electrolyte imbalance caused by the over-activity of the sensory neurons. In a migraineur’s brain, the sensory neurons have much more connections than the same neurons in a typical non-migraine brain. This is why migraineurs tend to be overstimulated by strong bright lights, strong odors, loud sounds, more sensitive to touch, and some (like me) also are super-tasters, so more sensitive to spices.\nBecause of the hyper-reaction of the brain to sensory stimulus, it generates more voltage—voltage is communication in the brain—and that extra voltage uses more sodium. Migraineurs need more salt in their diet to counter this effect. A study showed that migraineurs lose over 50% more sodium in their urine than non-migraineurs—eating the same thing.\nMigraineurs are also glucose sensitive (carbs intolerant) because glucose removes sodium and water from cells—therefore, carbs reduce brain sodium even more for migraineurs, causing a migraine.\nRead this article: http://www.mhfmjournal.com/pdf/migraine-cause-and-treatment.pdf\n, also Functional Prodrome in Migraines\nand this book about migraines \"Fighting The Migraine Epidemic: Complete Guide: How to Treat & Prevent Migraines Without Medicines\" and you will find answers all your questions.\nThere is also this video that is very educational: Episode 109: Angela Stanton - Is Your Diet Giving You Migraines? Episode 109: Angela Stanton - Is Your Diet Giving You Migraines?"}
{"_id": "a67fc978", "question": "Is there any way to detect a stroke or heart attack earlier?", "answers": "Strokes and heart attacks are two entirely different events. I will address some of the lesser known factors in getting treatment for both. This is from personal experience.\nThe symptoms of a heart attack vary widely in a range from a silent heart attack (with no pain), to the classic widow maker heart attack with clear striated pain running down the left side of your chest and left arm. Websites like Mayo Clinic and others will clearly define symptoms for you. Educate yourself with these symptoms, it could save your life.\nA heart attack is “usually” is most commonly caused by an artery blockage which shuts off the blood supply to a section of your heart which results in killing the tissue in that part of the heart and causes scar tissue. Symptoms the person feels may change depending on where the blockage is located. What is not talked about much is that survival rates for females heart attacks are much lower than men. This lower survival rate is due to the “typical” female heart being smaller than the “typical” male heart. Thus, the smaller heart is less able to withstand the rigors of the attack. So, earlier detection and preventative measures are especially important to females.\nFor earlier detection, the health provider can use several means including performing an angiogram a procedure which uses radioactive dye and associated imaging to locate the blockage(s).\nBlockages may potentially be resolved by stent placement which is least invasive or open heart surgery. The stent placement is performed by a surgeon who is sometimes referred to as an “interventionist”. This is a relatively common procedure. Open heart surgery is much more involved and I will not go into the details here.\nFor a stent placement, it is important to get the very BEST interventionist working on you as these procedures require skill and experience. If given a choice of a well known, acclaimed heart clinics like Methodist Debakey or St. Luke’s in Houston, Cleveland Clinic in Cleveland, or Duke in NC go there by all means. Not only do they have top skill levels available there, they have a deep POOL of highly qualified interventionists available. A smaller hospital might have one or two very qualified interventionists, but what happens if the INTERVENTIONIST you need for a heart attack THAT DAY is on vacation or out sick? Poor skills or unanticipated complications can lead to a situation where the only interventionist available in a smaller institution backs out of the procedure (this happened with my mother) or else continues to the point where a rupture of the blocked blood vessel occurs (this happened with a friend of mine). In such a rupture they will have to perform open heart surgery to save you. So, the skill level of the interventionist is key. It is better to have one who is better experienced in the many possibilities they will encounter and that they are equipped to work around these issues.\nDO NOT DRIVE YOURSELF to the emergency room! If you do you will lose many advantages that exist with arrival via EMS and you could find yourself too ill to drive, stuck in a traffic tie up or even faint on the way. DON’T DO IT! If you are having a heart attack it is imperative to get the EMS to where you are fast. Do not lay down while you wait. Sit in a comfortable chair. This assists your failing heart by keeping a little pressure on your vascular system. While you wait on the EMS be sure to take half a dozen aspirin to thin the blood. Tell the EMS how many aspirin you took. The EMS will also give you morphine to increase blood flow to the heart muscle which will aid in reducing the damage. On the way to the hospital the EMS will clear traffic with their flashing lights and be sending your vital signs to the hospital via telemetry. They will be alerting the on duty interventionist that you are on the way and to be ready to take action. They will be your passport STRAIGHT PAST check in and onto the operating table, hopefully with the interventionist and staff there waiting for your arrival. So time spent getting the EMS is not time wasted. It is time saved. Time saved is heart tissue saved!\nStrokes are blockages of blood supply to a section of your brain. This could lead to paralysis on one side of your face or body, slurring of speech and loss of control of your hands, arms, legs, etc. Impacts from stroke can be permanent or temporary. If temporary, it is called a TIA, a transient ischemic attack and may only last a few seconds after which full functioning of the body will return. A stroke is more serious and extremely disconcerting to the victim and sometimes accompanied by confusion or denial. That is, the victim minimizes the problem and does not seek IMMEDIATE emergency treatment which is paramount to regaining use of the paralyzed functions. I know stroke treatment technology has improved in the past few years, but it used to be the case that if the blockage is cleared in less than 15 minutes, permanent brain damage could be reduced or eliminated. Medical technology has been created to defeat the blockage. Take advantage of it. Time is of the essence. Don’t delay!\nIn cases of heart attack and stroke have a plan prepared in advance. If your family history indicates possibility of heart attack or stroke make a plan! Share the plan with your family or spouse."}
{"_id": "c40785a1", "question": "How does a brain stroke happen?", "answers": "To put it as simply as possible there are two types of stroke namely ischemic and haemorrhagic...any factor that causes decreased blood supply to a particular area of the brain leads to ischemic stroke and symptoms pertaining to that particular region of the brain..any factor that increases the pressure of the blood flow through a particular vessel in the brain leads to rupture of the small vessel and causes haemorrhagic stroke...ischemic stroke most commonly caused due to an emboli blocking an end artery...while haemorrhagic stroke is most commonly caused due to uncontrolled hypertension.."}
{"_id": "664bf247", "question": "Why six stroke engines cannot be used in vehicles?", "answers": "There are a variety of engine cycles called “six-stroke engines ,” of which the Dyer/Crower engine is the best known, and thus the one which I’ll assume you’re asking about.\nThe first four strokes are the same as in an Otto or Diesel cycle. After the fourth stroke, liquid water is injected to make high pressure steam, which is expanded (fifth stroke) to make mechanical power and low pressure steam, and the low pressure steam is then exhausted (sixth stroke).\nThe first problem is thermal stress: the surface of the piston and the inside of the cylinder heat up and cool down more quickly than in a normal four stroke engine. Exotic materials (ceramics?) might be needed for such an engine to last a long time.\nThe second is water.\nIf there is no condenser to turn exhausted steam back to liquid, then you’ll need a tank of water, which will probably be used at about the same rate as gasoline. Even if you didn’t mind having this tank, filling it could be a problem. Even if the engine can use tap water, you’ll need to fill it every time you get gas… there’s no convenient water dispenser next to the fuel pump. Did I mention that Bruce Crower didn’t even attempt to use tap water, and only tried running his engine with distilled water? Distilled water isn’t very expensive, but it’s not something presently available at gas stations.\nIf there is a condenser, you won’t need to fill the water tank nearly so often, but this component could be heavy.\nA third problem is balancing to minimize vibration — the only good arrangement that comes to mind is an inline 6 cylinder engine with 3 pistons going up together and the other three going down together.\nA fourth possible problem is that, if a combined air exhaust/steam exhaust is used, then the steam will dilute the air exhaust, throw of the O2 sensors, and interfere with the working of the catalytic converter. Using separate exhaust systems can solve that, but will make your engine look like a mutant octopus, since there will be three manifolds (intake air, exhaust air, steam).\nA fifth problem, related to the first, is that high temperature high pressure steam, even without the assistance of oxygen, can degrade a variety of materials.\nThe final problem is that it is new and strange, and the auto industry doesn’t like radical change."}
{"_id": "4aead36d", "question": "What do you do when someone is having a stroke?", "answers": "3 Things to Do When Someone Is Having a Stroke:\n1. Call 911 immediately\nIf you do nothing else, act quickly to call 911.\n“The hardest thing you have to do is recognize symptoms of a stroke,” Jean explains. “If you do observe any symptoms, you should call 911 immediately. You should also immediately tell the 911 dispatcher, ‘I think I’m having a stroke’ or ‘I think my loved one is.’”\nNot sure what the symptoms of a stroke are? Give someone you think is having a stroke this FAST test\nfrom the National Stroke Association.\n2. Note the time you first see symptoms\nA clot-busting medication called tPA, or tissue plasminogen activator, can be given to someone if they’re having a stroke, potentially reversing or stopping symptoms from developing. But it has to be given within 4.5 hours of the start of symptoms, Jean says.\nPatients may also be candidates for more advanced therapies, such as endovascular treatments, at Penn Medicine. Endovascular treatments can involve surgically removing a clot that caused a stroke, or fixing an aneurysm—which is a swollen blood vessel that bursts and causes pressure in the brain. Endovascular treatments for ischemic stroke, the most common type of stroke, must be administered within 24 hours of symptom onset, and earlier treatment improves outcome so time is critically important.\n“If a witness sees someone having a stroke, it would be helpful if they look at what time the symptoms started,” she says. “That way, the emergency staff can make a more informed decision about treatment options.”\n3. Perform CPR, if necessary\nMost stroke patients don’t require CPR, Jean notes. But if your friend or spouse is unconscious when you find her, check her pulse and breathing. If you find none, call 911 and start CPR while you’re waiting for the ambulance to arrive.\nYou can also ask the 911 dispatcher to walk you through how to perform CPR, which consists of repeated, steady chest compressions, according to the American Heart Association\n(OR)\n1. Let that person go to sleep or talk you out of calling 911\nStroke survivors often complain of suddenly feeling very sleepy when a stroke first happens.\n“A lot of patients come in and say they went to sleep for a few hours before they came to the hospital because they were tired,” Jean notes.\nBut time is of the essence. “The medication we can give a stroke survivor is time-sensitive,” she adds. “They should not go to sleep, and they should not call their primary care doctor 2 days from now. Instead, they should just go immediately to the emergency room.”\nAnd no matter how much someone might try to talk you out of taking them to the hospital, don’t let them, says Jean.\n2. Give them medication, food, or drinks\nThere are 2 kinds of strokes:\nHemorrhagic stroke, caused by a ruptured blood vessel\nIschemic stroke, caused by a clot in a blood vessel\n“80% of strokes are ischemic ones, but if you’re in that 20% and your stroke was caused by a ruptured blood vessel in the head, you don’t want the victim to have aspirin,” Jean says. “And you can’t tell which one it is until you get to the emergency room and you get a CAT scan.”\nTo be safe, don’t give someone who has a stroke any medication.\nYou also shouldn’t give him food or drinks before the ambulance comes. “Sometimes, a stroke affects their ability to swallow,” Jean says.\n3. Drive yourself or someone else to the emergency room\nIt might seem like a good idea to drive a stroke victim to the nearest emergency room. But Jean says, “If someone is severely affected by a stroke, then you’re better off calling 911.”\nEmergency responders can start life-saving treatment for that person on the way to the emergency room, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) says.\nYou also don’t want to drive yourself to a hospital in the event that your stroke symptoms worsen and impair your ability to drive safely."}
{"_id": "89e0b607", "question": "Why is oil used along with petrol in 2 stroke engine bikes?", "answers": "First of oil, most modern and old 2 stroke motorcycle engines have a separate oil tank that pumps special 2 stroke oil to the crankshaft bearings and the cylinder walls to lubricate them “obviously”, it is then burned with the air/ petrol mixture that is sucked in through its crankcase and then burnt after combustion has taken place and this burnt oil is what causes 2 stroke to belch out blue smoke so effectively the oil that is pumped is total loss unlike a 4 stroke/ cycle engine where where the combustion chamber is totally oil free..a 2 stroke engine receives fresh oil on every piston stroke unlike a 4 stroke engine that has to be changed at intervals from 3 to 12 thousand miles depending on the climate of the country, however, some 2 stroke engines like chain saws have to have the oil mixed with the petrol/ gasoline before it is put into the fuel tank, most 2 stroke engines will require a new cylinder or a rebore with fresh new pistons a long way before a 4 stroke engine where the engine oil is not Total loss.🏍"}
{"_id": "804c9520", "question": "Which produces more power 2 stroke or 4 stroke?", "answers": "Two stroke gives more power than four stroke. Reason being in 2-stroke there is one power stroke for each revolution of crankshaft (1 complete cycle) and in 4-stroke engine there is one power stroke for two revolutions of crankshaft (1 complete cycle). P.s: now we cant compare a 100cc two stroke with 1200cc four stroke. Keeping the parameters same we can say that 2-stroke provides more power than 4-stroke."}
{"_id": "9fd3dbeb", "question": "Is it possible to have a stroke while you are asleep and not know it?", "answers": "As a survivor of basilar strokes I will say in general strokes don’t pick a particular time to happen. Your physical, emotional and mental circumstance will add or take away to have it happen. A basilar stroke is probably the leading cause of those who die in their sleep. This type of stroke isn’t talked about because it would scare the general public wittless! It kills 97% per event. I had three of them in the same week. I know this because I didn’t sleep well the night before I went to the Urgent Care. If I had slept? I more than likely I would not be responding to this answer. I was finally given an answer of what was my survivability percentage. I am a .01% survivor. If I had not gone to the hospital, and had all the wonderful medical teams? This very answer would not be on Quora."}
{"_id": "655e2bdd", "question": "What, if anything, can or should someone who is high risk to suffer a stroke do to prevent a stroke?", "answers": "Disclaimer: I am not a doctor.\nIf you are at risk for a stroke or any cardiovascular disease you should regularly consult with your doctor.\nIn addition some lifestyle changes and herbs mentioned at Stroke\nprevention and treatment with vitamins, herbs, supplements | Natural remedies - Five Remedies\ncan be tried.\nGinkgo biloba\nTake 180 to 240 mg daily of a 24 percent flavone glycoside extract. Ginkgo has blood ­thinning and antioxidant properties.\nGarlic\nTake 300 to 500 mg of aged garlic twice daily. lt reduces cholesterol levels and increases HDL cholesterol.\nFish oil\nTake a daily dosage of a fish oil product containing l,000 mg of EPA and 500 mg of DHA. Fish oil reduces inflammation in the arteries and lowers cholesterol and triglyceride\nHigh-potency multivitamin\nTake as directed on the container. It contains a variety of antioxidants. as `well as minerals that are associated with reducing the risk of stroke.\nTake 500 to l,500 mg of the capsule form. Look for a product standardized to between 80 and 90 percent polyphenols and between 35 and 55 percent epigallocatechin gallate.\nGreen tea\ncontains a rich source of antioxidants and substances that assist detoxification.\nVitamin E\nTake 400 IU daily of a mixed complex. It prevents cholesterol oxidation and is a natural blood thinner.\nPolicosanol\nTake 10 to 20 mg each evening. Numerous studies show that policosanol reduces LDL cholesterol and increases the good HDL cholesterol.\nPantetheine\nPantetheine is a metabolite of vitamin B5 that has been shown in studies to reduce total and LDL cholesterol. as well to increase HDL. lt can be effective particularly for people with diabetes. Take 600 to 900 mg daily.\nSoy protein\nSoy protein has been shown in studies to reduce total and LDL cholesterol and to increase HDL. Take 25 to 50 grams daily.\nReishi\nReishi is a mushroom extract that reduces cholesterol. Take 800 mg two to three times daily.\nOmega-3 Fatty Acids\nIn a 2003 study, scientists discovered that eating fish several times per week reduces risk of thrombotic stroke (a type of ischemic stroke that occurs when a blood clot forms in arteries in the neck or brain). An earlier study also found that high consumption of fish and omega-3 fatty acids may be linked to decreased risk of thrombotic stroke.\nCalcium\nCalcium is very important in rectifying all circulatory diseases and disorders including stroke. Because calcium is the most alkaline mineral in the mineral family, it helps to counteract acidity and bust up accumulated debris that stick to the arterial walls and thus open up clogged and obstructed arteries. Natural calcium-rich herbs include: Comfrey Root, Oatstraw, Horsetail, and Alfalfa.\nOther beneficial herbs for stroke prevention and remedy include: Cayenne, Ginger, Cinnamon, Butcher’s Broom, Gotu Kola, Cranesbill, Goldenseal Root, Manjistha, Holy (Blessed) Thistle, Gingko Biloba, and Mullein Leaf."}
{"_id": "2493622d", "question": "Is scooty a four stroke or two stroke ?", "answers": "2 stroke not in use anymore nowadays and there is no production or sales of them since years because two stroke engines with petro-oil lubrication(oil mixing with petrol) is only banned in India and they are unable to comply with emission norms so today if any one designs a engine which does not use petro-oil lubrication and complies with new standards of emissiom then it will be allowed on road, regardless of number of strokes. Also in two strokes mechanical efficiency is higher on the other hand four stroke thermal efficiency is higher so now four stroke engine is mostly used.Two strokes engine causes more pollution with less efficiency. 4 stroke engines over 2 stroke engines be it milage, or heating issues 4 stroke are better. Also the 2 strokes are used in lawn roller, Luna, moped etc. But scooty uses 4 stroke."}
{"_id": "e10f484b", "question": "How would you compare a 2 stroke and a 4 stroke engine?", "answers": "A 2 stroke engine doesn't have camshaft like a 4 stroke engine. Air intake and exhaust outlet are operated by ports, unlike valves in a 4 stroke engine. So a 2 stroke engine is less in weight up to 40% compared to 4 stroke engine and also there are no losses due to valve openings and closings like in 4 stroke since they don't have valves. So two stroke engines have greater power output compared to four stroke engines.\nYou can look out for working animation of a two stroke engine at this link\nRedirect Notice"}
{"_id": "7ecf0ff4", "question": "Swimming: What is the best way to learn the butterfly stroke?", "answers": "I speak from my daughter's perspective who specialized in butterfly and had many lessons including lessons from Olympians and she made fun of Michael Phelps style (not great style but much superior strength and muscle mass compensate...he breathes every stroke).\nStay flat to the water...all up and down is wasted energy and induces drag. Literally suck the water when breathing. Don't pull your head way up to breath....it is heavy and the rest of your body will go down you get it just above the water to breathe.\nIt is not a stroke that can be done slowly though in great shape you can pace yourself for the longer races. For a period she attended a K-12 school and the rules allowed her to high school swim (yes she was a year round swimmer) in 6th grade. At grade 9 we were contacted by a recruiter assuming she was in 12th grade. There were a lot of rules for this call (speaker phone, both parents, etc). He was shocked that she was not a senior in high school but a freshman. He said her times would lead a D3 school, be in the middle of a D2 school and barely make a D1 school. He said he would call back in a 2 years.\nUnfortunately as many competitive swimmers in butterfly do, she developed shoulder problems and quit the sport. Her coach had no dry land training to counter balance the muscles she used excessively\nHere is a picture in the middle of a 200 fly event"}
{"_id": "c5c5c96b", "question": "Can I use car motor oil in my 2 stroke in an emergency?", "answers": "Can you use motor oil in two-stroke continuously? Most likely. Can you use it in a pinch? Definitely. I use a mixture of 20w50, marine 2-stroke oil, and a little bit of fuel as a thinner to make my own two-stroke oil for my chainsaw. I’ve had no issues besides a little more smoking on startup, due to the motor oil’s higher flash point - it just doesn’t burn completely, and I tend to use more oil than I need anyway.\nNow, you probably shouldn’t use plain marine two-stroke oil in something like a string trimmer or chainsaw; marine engines are water-cooled so they run cooler than air-cooled engines. Heat drops oil viscosity, which decreases the film strength of the oil. So, I add 20w50 to increase the viscosity of the oil when hot.\nOne thing that comes up in similar discussions is that motor oil won’t mix in gasoline. This is absolutely untrue based on both theory and my personal experience. Gasoline and motor oil are composed of organic compounds, with the oil just having longer carbon chains than the gasoline. It will probably require more mixing, but once dissolved, you won’t have multiple phases forming.\nIt’s probably not ideal to mix used motor oil into your fuel, even if you filter it first. Used oil contains heavy metals from the bearings, and those will end up in the two-stroke’s exhaust. It’s not good to breathe that stuff in.\nAs a final note, I’d like to mention that two-stroke engines have been around for a ages, way before these fancy, overpriced two-stroke oils came around. People have used motor oil for this purpose for a long time, so I think it’s just fine."}
{"_id": "9b7d9e82", "question": "Why high blood pressure could leads to stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a6d09681", "question": "What are the main differences of four stroke petrol engine and four stroke diesel engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "de6a2610", "question": "What are some applications of six-stroke engines?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "09f176c4", "question": "What is the biggest stroke of genius you have ever had?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "657fd70d", "question": "Will eating a big meal cause a stroke or is that just a myth?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "975603bc", "question": "Why should you never stroke your dog on its head?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b0338439", "question": "Why do we use 2 strokes, not 4 strokes, in slow speed diesel engines (in ships)?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "56c28e87", "question": "Are 2 stroke bikes getting banned in India?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5846e4ae", "question": "What is the difference between a heart attack and a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c6bdd260", "question": "Does a two stroke engine develop twice as much power as compared to a 4 stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "71cdecf2", "question": "What are the disadvantages of a 2-stroke diesel engine over a 4- stroke diesel engine?", "answers": "My experience is with old 871 Detroits\n, so it may not really apply any more. Disadvantages: The roots blower was a big expensive thing. If it went south, it deposited lots of bits into the engine. The cylinder liners sometimes cracked at the intake ports. And they where loud. Nicknamed the Screaming Jimmy\nfor a reason.\nThat being said, I thought they where a clever design, and the one I drove and maintained was really old. I think it was doing pretty well all things considered, and at a fraction of he cost of an equivalent Cummins."}
{"_id": "1d9c991a", "question": "Why do 2-stroke engines make more power than 4-strokes with the same displacement?", "answers": "The clue is that a four stroke engine requires four strokes and complicated valve gear to complete a combustion cycle, while the two stroke only requires two as has already been mentioned.\nThe difference is the induction and exhaust phases.\nEarly two stroke gasoline engines universally required a deflector top piston to direct the incoming charge away from the exhaust ports. Anyone who has worked on the old two-stroke industrial or the marine engines manufactured by Evinrude/Johnson or Mercury is familiar with this configuration.\nLack of intake and exhaust porting sophistication led to the horsepower/displacement deficit in favor of the four stroke engine, even in flat head designs, due to the more efficient control of the gas flow which led to greater fuel economy.\nThe East German MZ GP twin cylinder 250cc bikes of the early ‘60s demonstrated that possible sophistication. They had Schnurle porting that carefully directed the intake flow to fill the cylinder while minimizing unnecessary dilution by the combustion gases. Timing was controlled by intake disc valves and piston ports using the maximum crankcase compression possible to supercharge the intake gas flow.\nExhaust gas flow control was achieved by calculating the exhaust flow that first scavenged the cylinder then reflected a pressure wave back to the cylinder’s exhaust ports. This prevented further flow and also stopped the intake charge coming through the exhaust ports before the piston travel could close them. This was accomplished with a tuned exhaust system consisting of an initial diverging cone (like a cheerleader’s megaphone) followed by the calculated volume of a connected cylinder that ended in a converging cone evacuated by a small diameter exhaust pipe of carefully calculated diameter and length.\nWithout valve gear, these engines could rev a blue streak and develop previously unimaginable outputs. They also had a power and torque curve like a cliff (hence multi-multi gear transmissions), and consumed fuel at a prodigious rate commensurate with the output.\nOne observer noted a factory GP rider, practicing on a 50cc bike, tuck in behind a customer available factory over-the-counter 125cc club racer bike, then accelerate away when clear of the tight corner. The three cylinder engine was rumored to develop well over twenty HP from three cubic inches. My four-stroke ’61 Honda Cub developed four and a half HP from its pushrod 50cc.\nThese GP bikes were also using constant-loss oil injection to the mains and rods to avoid contaminating the intake charge with the usual fuel/oil mix.\nUnfortunately, they still smoked and so could never pass a restrictive hydrocarbon limit. On that basis, two-strokes were banned from the track and the street.\nI still remember my Kawasaki ‘70 H2. Though it was only a piston port charged engine, the porting was good and the engine was rated at sixty HP. It was a wheel-standing demon in first through third gear if you were careless, or showing off. It was still light on the front end when shifting to fourth with the standard gearing.\nMy ’61 Matchless G50, also 500cc, was rated at fifty HP and could loft the front wheel in first and second and unload the front fork on shifting to third. Even with short or twisty course gearing, it was always a gentle evolution unlike the explosive Kawasaki."}
{"_id": "4101175a", "question": "Which engine is easier to crank? A 2-stroke or a 4-stroke?", "answers": "The ability of engine is dependent on its volume and compression ratio.\napparently 2 stroke CV engines are meant to be easily cranking engine compared to 4 stroke engine for the same volume and compression ratio."}
{"_id": "9bbf2d3f", "question": "Can I use 2-stroke engine oil for a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": "No You Cant,\n]1. 2T engine oils which is used for engines are of mostly single grade and are mixed with the fuel to give the lubrication to various parts and it will be burnt after lubrication.\n2.But incase of the four stroke the oil will be stored in an sump and will be pumped to various parts to give lubrication.\nViscosity,Flash point of the oil,viscosity index Density are all the important factors for the lubricating oil.\nWhen we take operating conditions of the 4T engines especially the SI engines the temperature will be of high during operation. So in order to withstand these conditions the oil should have high viscosity at certain temperatures and high flash point.\nBelow is the property of an 2T engine oil\nAnd Below is the properties of an well known 4T engine oil.\nSo here when we compare flash point of both oils the 2T oils have low flash point and as well as the viscosity at elevated temperatures.\nIt shows that 2T engine oil will not withstand temperature above 135 degree celsius. And the viscoity is also less. So it cannot be used in the 4T engine oils"}
{"_id": "a8b4790f", "question": "How does a four-stroke diesel engine work?", "answers": "Diesel engine which is also known as compression ignition engine is widely used in automobile industries. Many big vehicles such as truck, bus, car etc. used diesel engine as the power unit because of its higher torque and greater mileage than petrol engine. Diesel engine is very popular in Indian market as well as in other countries because of lower price of diesel than petrol in many countries. So the requirement of diesel engine is much more than petrol engine.\nThe ignition temperature of diesel is lower than petrol so the working of diesel engine is slightly different than petrol engine.\nWorking of Four Stroke Diesel Engine\nThe power generation process in four stroke diesel engine is also divided into four parts. Each part is known as piston stroke. In IC engine, stroke is referred to the maximum distance travel by the piston in a single direction. The piston is free to move only in upward and downward direction. In four stroke engine the piston move two time up and down and the crankshaft move two complete revolution to complete four piston cycle. These are suction stroke, compression stroke, expansion stroke and exhaust stroke.\nSuction stroke:\nIn the suction stroke or intake stroke of diesel engine the piston start moves from top end of the cylinder to bottom end of the cylinder and simultaneously inlet valve opens. At this time air at atmospheric pressure drawn inside the cylinder through the inlet valve by a pump. The inlet valve remains open until the piston reaches the lower end of cylinder. After it inlet valve close and seal the upper end of the cylinder.\nCompression stroke:\nAfter the piston passes bottom end of the cylinder, it starts moving up. Both valves are closed and the cylinder is sealed at that time. The piston moves upward. This movement of piston compresses the air into a small space between the top of the piston and cylinder head. The air is compressed into 1/22 or less of its original volume. Due to this compression a high pressure and temperature generate inside the cylinder. Both the inlet and exhaust valves do not open during any part of this stroke. At the end of compression stroke the piston is at top end of the cylinder.\nPower stroke:\nAt the end of the compression stroke when the piston is at top end of the cylinder a metered quantity of diesel is injected into the cylinder by the injector. The heat of compressed air ignites the diesel fuel and generates high pressure which pushes down the piston. The connection rod carries this force to the crankshaft which turns to move the vehicle. At the end of power stroke the piston reach the bottom end of cylinder.\nExhaust stroke:\nWhen the piston reaches the bottom end of cylinder after the power stroke, the exhaust valve opens. At this time the burn gases inside the cylinder so the cylinder pressure is slightly high from atmospheric pressure. This pressure difference allows burn gases to escape through the exhaust port and the piston move through the top end of the cylinder. At the end of exhaust all burn gases escape and exhaust valve closed. Now again intake valve open and this process running until your vehicle starts."}
{"_id": "656e4d86", "question": "What are your thoughts on Stephen Miller expressing outrage at Biden for suspending “pages of immigration law with the stroke of a pen,” which had been enacted by the stroke of a pen (Sharpie)?", "answers": "I love it.\nIf Stephen Miller had hitched his wagon to a man who was smart, liked to work, and wanted to learn new things, we would be in deep doo-doo. Such a man would’ve rammed through immigration laws in a compliant Congress, as the GOP had control of both houses of the legislature from 2017 to 2019. Trump also had GOP congresspeople running scared, so he could’ve definitely rammed through whatever he wanted with regards to immigration.\nLaws passed by both houses of Congress and signed by the President, as we all know, are much harder to dislodge or overturn by subsequent presidential administrations and Congresses. That’s why people with government experience concentrate almost exclusively on passing laws.\nThankfully for us, Stephen Miller got Donald Trump, the laziest, most dense mofo this side of “Idiocracy.”\nTrump didn’t care to fix the immigration system in the way his followers wanted him to. That would’ve required hard work and, you know, learning how the government actually worked. So Trump, like has been his wont his whole life, did two things: 1) he made a lot of noise that he was “the busiest president ever!” and 2) found the easiest way to change policies that would least disturb his habits—which included watching hours upon hours upon hours of TV, tweeting about those hours of TV, and then yapping with his friends on the phone hatching elaborate revenge schemes against those who had crossed him. (Otherwise known as “executive time.”) And when he got tired of his “executive time,” he golfed. There was also a tremendous amount of golfing. So the easiest way that Trump found to unilaterally and lazily pass policy changes that he liked and that required the least amount of consultation and horse-trading with others (i.e. less work)—executive orders.\nNow the Trumpists are quickly finding out that electing a highly entertaining, incurious, lazy fat-ass for president does have its downsides—like all of Trump’s policies being rescinded unilaterally by Biden within a few months. Biden, like Trump, doesn’t even have to bother asking Congress for anything. All he needs is an army of constitutional lawyers to churn out those executive orders as efficiently as possible, and as fail-proof in the courts as possible. (Trump didn’t even bother to set up such an army of lawyers, which meant that the courts kept striking down his executive orders and policy changes at quite an embarrassing rate.) We’re in almost at week and Biden is about to pass 40 executive orders, which is more than Trump managed to pass in all of 2017.\nThere will be little left of Trump’s legacy within government except his very wasteful tax cut laws passed in 2017 and those judges he rammed into the judiciary with the help of Moscow Mitch.\nSo now Biden, with this decades of government experience, knows how to strike well, quickly, and efficiently, and has gathered a highly seasoned team that will make it happen. He’s not depending on his dense son-in-law and an inexperienced and addled twit—otherwise known as Steve Bannon—to make executive orders stick with the courts. For a “senile old man,” Biden is proving to be quite quick witted.\nLet the dismantling of Trump’s legacy begin! :)"}
{"_id": "8a00ffcc", "question": "What is the point of the butterfly stroke?", "answers": "There is no utilitarian purpose to the butterfly stroke, it is purely a competitive stroke. To understand this, you need to understand the history of the stroke. At one time (1950's I believe), the competitive swimming rules did not specify that an above water arm recovery stroke was disallowed in the breaststroke, and some sharp Olympic level competitor experimented with it and determined that it was faster. So he swam with a butterfly arm stroke with a frog kick in breaststroke events. Within a short time, the butterfly stroke became it's own and the dolphin kick permitted, and the original intent of the breaststroke was preserved by requiring an underwater arm recovery. As others have stated, butterfly is the most physically demanding stroke, and well executed, a thing of beauty.\nSince the butterfly is purely a competitive stroke, there's also a certain exclusivity to it, since very few people can swim it well who were not at one time competitive swimmers. So it brings with it a certain cachet, or \"pride of ownership,\" much like being a scratch golfer."}
{"_id": "bf2cd412", "question": "How is it determined if a stroke is ischemic or hemorrhagic?", "answers": "When a patient comes do the Emergency Room with an acute neurological deficit and the probable diagnosis is a stroke, the first exam to be performed is a CT scan to exclude intracranial haemorrhage, which would preclude thrombolysis; to look for any \"early\" signs of infarction; and to exclude other intracranial pathologies that may mimic a stroke, such as tumour.\nThe first signs of an ischemic stroke may be very subtle and include:\n1. A hyperdense segment of a vessel, most communly observed in the middle cerebral artery. It's the earliest sign visible in the CT.\n2. Loss of grey-white matter differentiation, and hypoattenuation of deep nuclei, as well as cortical hypodensity with associated parenchymal swelling with resultant gyral effacement. Visible in the first 1-3 hours.\n3. Progressive hypo-attenuation and swelling In the first week.\n4. And finally, after months, we can see an image of low density, with no mass effect, such as the following:\nOn the other hand, acute brain haemorrhage appears hyperdense (white) on CT scans, as we can see in the image below:\n\nThere are many kinds of intracranial haemorrhage and a long list of images you can get based in the artery affected by an ischemic stroke (all with different clinical onsets). The basic image differences between those two are described above, but if you decide to take a deeper look into the subject, Neurology can be very fascinating.\nImages from Medscape."}
{"_id": "47ef4c9f", "question": "What is considered stroke level high blood pressure?", "answers": "Stroke level high blood pressure is a term that is used within the medical field to denote an abnormally, astronomically (at least in terms of what is normal in blood pressures) blood pressure. It’s also a fairly relative term, if I’m being completely honest with you. I’ve heard blood pressures of 180/100 being called “stroke level” even though I don’t consider a blood pressure to be stroke level until we get into the high 200s to 210s systolic (that’s the top number).\nI’ve actually had a patient in my ambulance before with a blood pressure of 233/133 she had run out of her bp meds and hadn’t had time to get them refilled. She had a headache and her blood pressure was sky friggin high, but otherwise she was fine. How long she would have been fine for I don’t know, but while she was in my care, she was fine.\nThe take away here is that different providers will call different pressures stroke level. Usually they start at least concert at about 180 systolic and go up in number and level of urgency from there. Basically, the term “stroke level blood pressure” is a way for healthcare providers to communicate two things. One, that the patient in question has a higher than normal for anyone blood pressure and two, that that patient needs to be given treatment for that pressure soon or he/she could go from just having a headache to being rushed to ct because they hemorrhages and are now having a stroke."}
{"_id": "55bd3c39", "question": "What is the risk of stroke for a healthy person?", "answers": "lifetime risk of stroke is 1 in 5 for women, 1 in 6 for menSources\nSeshadri S., Wolf P.A. (2007). Lifetime risk of stroke and dementia: current concepts, and estimates　from the Framingham Study. The Lancet Neurology 6(12), 1106-14. http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1474-4422(07)70291-0\nSeshadri S. et al. (2006). The lifetime risk of stroke: estimates from the Framingham Study. Stroke 37, 45-350. http://stroke.ahajournals.org/cgi/content/full/37/2/345%20/%20%22%20/%20_blank\nParticipants\n(n=4897) who were stroke- and dementia-free at 55 years of age were\nfollowed biennially for up to 51 years. ... A total of 875 participants\n(522 women) developed a first-ever stroke; 749 (448 women) had an\nischemic stroke. LTR of stroke was high and remained similar at ages 55,\n65, and 75 years, approximating 1 in 5 for women and 1 in 6 for men.\nParticipants with a normal BP (<120/80 mm Hg) had approximately half\nthe LTR of stroke compared with those with high BP (=140/90 mm Hg)\nWe observed that the LTR of stroke for middle-aged and \"young-old\"\nadults (55 to 75 years of age) was substantial at 1 in 6 or higher. This\nrisk was higher in women (1 in 5) compared with men, largely because of\nthe greater life expectancy in women, which increased their period at\nrisk.\nBushnell, C.D. (2008). Stroke and the female brain. Nature Clinical Practice Neurology 4(1), 22-33.\nStroke\nis the third leading cause of death in most countries, and is one of\nthe leading causes of long-term disability. Women have a higher lifetime\nrisk of stroke than men (1 in 5 vs 1 in 6), a statistic that is\ninfluenced in part by the longer life expectancy in women. The female\npopulation not only carries a higher burden of stroke during their\nlifespan - women also account for the majority of stroke deaths.\nEvery two seconds, someone in the world suffers a stroke\nEvery six seconds, someone dies of a stroke\nEvery six seconds, someone’s quality of life will forever be changed – they will permanently be physically disabled http://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/570106%20/%20%22%20/%20_blank"}
{"_id": "ceb5c51a", "question": "What is the six-stroke engine?", "answers": "Generally the thermal efficiency of a four stroke engine is about 40% which means only 40% of the total heat input to engine by burning the fuel is converted into useful work. The remaining 60% heat is lost to the surrounding in terms of exhaust gas and the heat carried away by the cooling water of the radiator. Six stroke engines attempt to recover those waste heats and improve the efficiency of the engines.\nThe six strokes are-\nSuction\nCompression\nExpansion\nExhaust\nWater injection\nSteam exhaust\nThe first 4 strokes of a six stroke engines are similar to four stroke engines i.e., suction,compression, expansion, exhaust. After the fourth stroke, the temperature inside the cylinder is still much higher than that of ambient. So, in the fifth stroke, small water droplets are injected into the cylinder. Due to the high temperature, the water droplets evaporate readily and the steam does the additional work by expanding inside the cylinder and pushes the piston down. In the sixth stroke of the piston, the expanded steams are exhausted into the condenser in which it is condensed into water for reusing it in the further cycles. Thus, one six stroke cycle is completed in 3 revolutions of the crank shaft. The efficiency of the six stroke engines are about 60%. By using 6 stroke engine in place of 4strokes, the fuel consumption can be reduced upto 40%.\nThe working of the six stroke engines are shown below\nFig: working of six stroke engine\nThe main challenge in case of six strokes engine is the design of the cam shaft. Because we need to inject water droplets as soon as the exhaust gases leave the engine."}
{"_id": "ff44d64f", "question": "What's the best course of action when recovering from strokes?", "answers": "Immediate treatment is the Number One course for successful stroke recovery. The source of the injury must be identified (is it a clot or a bleed?) and the appropriate treatment to abate that event applied. Since most strokes seem to be ischemic (clot) at first glance, anti-clotting medications can \"bust\" the clot and restore blood flow to the affected areas of the brain. If this treatment is accomplished within a few hours (used to be a three hour window, but that window's been opened a bit wider: Time window for\nstroke\ntreatment should be extended\n) damage cane be limited and usually treatable.\nThe second most-important factor in stroke treatment is swift, aggressive and global therapies, physical, occupational and speech. Physical therapy addresses the need to \"re-teach\" muscles how to work, and to provide the opportunity for damaged neurons to re-route signals around damaged areas. Occupational therapy does this, also, but in the teaching of strategies to accomplish every day tasks, occupational therapy has a terrific track record in that \"re-teaching\". Speech therapy is not limited to speech, itself, but to cognition, also, in addition to swallowing issues. All of the therapies and techniques used help the brain recover from the insult of stroke.\nIn the event of a suspected stroke:\nGet the victim to a hospital ASAP\nThe hospital administers the correct treatments to bust the clot or stop the bleed ASAP.\nTherapies start early and continue until there is no further progress, at which time strategies are worked out to accomplish tasks in weakened areas.\nSometimes, some areas of the brain are so damaged they cannot \"come back\", and the victim needs assistance for the rest of their lives. But advances in treating stroke have become routine in Western medicine, and the outcomes have improved by a very large measure. What would have killed a victim even 25 years ago, is nearly completely recoverable now, as long as swift medical and therapeutic intervention is provided."}
{"_id": "d4aed9c7", "question": "What is the hardest swimming stroke?", "answers": "The butterfly is the most difficult stroke for many reasons. In free style, you are only moving one arm at a time and your shoulders and most of your body are rocking side to side so that whenever you take a stroke, your body twists on it's side and your arm reaches out farther, therefore giving you more power to move the water. In butterfly since you are using both arms, there is absolutely no side ways rotation so both arms having to pull the wait of your body throughout the water. Although you can kick, the kick you use in butterfly (often called dolphin kick) is basically just a result of your body going up and down. The kicking does make a difference, but if you tried doing butterfly with out kicking, your legs would move on their own. Basically, butterfly is the hardest strome because your shoulders and upper arms are doing most of the work, and there is essentially no rest time of either of your arms."}
{"_id": "a38c91dc", "question": "What precautions should be taken to prevent a heat stroke?", "answers": "Most parts of India are boiling at this time with heat waves and high temperatures. To be able to live upto the extreme temperatures, I recommend doing the following:-\nWear light and cotton clothes preferably lighter shades\nIf possible wear sunglasses and a cap to prevent you face and forehead from catching the wave\nAvoid cold drinks completely, not even are they a store house of bad chemicals and pesticides, the chilled cola would give you a sore throat also.\nIf possible, keep a pack of Glucon-D with you and keep on drinking it in short intervals.\nStay hydrated as much as you can, in the scorching sun we shed enough sweat that we don't feel the need to *pee but discharging it is also essential.\nEat freshly cut salads like cucumbers,tomatoes etc which are rich in water content and have the right minerals required to keep you body cool in this summer\nDon't sit/be too close to the AC, direct contact with the cold AC air can be harmful if you are on a mixed climatic environment of hot and Cold."}
{"_id": "99539b6a", "question": "What causes heat stroke?", "answers": "Heat Stroke is a term too loosely used. Properly defined it is a stroke caused by the heat. So this means brain tissue actually dies (often the patient does as well).\nSo what causes it? Heat. Too much heat. The body has several mechanisms to cope with heat;\nnumber 1 is avoidance- So we move out of the sun into the shade. Jump into a pool or shower, A/C on, hat, fan. What if you can’t? You are an infant in a car, prisoner in a cell, passed out due to drugs or alcohol, alzheimers patient, bed ridden nursing home patient. Well then the temp of your brain raises. Once it gets in the 104–5 range it starts to die and unless someone intervenes so do you\nnumber 2 is sweating. So on a hot day you swet. You swet a lot. Swetting keeps the body temperature down however only until you run out of swet. Then you develope heat exhaustion and you either faint or revert to #1 avoidance.\nnumber 3 is vasodilation. You blood is shunted to the skin and the skin blood vessels dilate. So the skin becomes a large radiator. It helps but if the sun is beating down on the skin or there is not enough fluid in the system then well it can’t improve things."}
{"_id": "06d4455f", "question": "What are the best songs by The Strokes?", "answers": "It really depends on the person, but here I go:\nHeart In A Cage has great lyrics and killer riffs and a touch of the strokes’ brand. It’s catchy, rocks out, and grabs your attention. This is my personal favorite song of theirs from their best album (you heard it here first).\nSomeday. I have never met a person who doesn’t like Someday and it’s just one of THE Strokes’ songs.\nReptilia. This is their most popular song and has a widely recognizable hook. “Please don’t slow me down, if I’m going too fast!” And has catchy guitars. It twists and turns like a room on fire and ends too soon."}
{"_id": "936f1cee", "question": "Can a lot of stress cause a stroke?", "answers": "Yes, In “Why Zebras Don’t Get Ulcers” author, Dr. Robert Sapolsky explains how chronic stress can cause hypertension and atherosclerosis, aka the accumulation of plaques in the blood vessel. Dr. Sapolsky writes about the incredible findings of physiologist Jay Kaplan from Bowman Grey Medical School.\nAccording to Kaplan and his colleagues, primates will form atherosclerotic plaques after social stress. If you turn a monkeys stable dominance hierarchy on its head the end result is enough social stress that provokes a stress response and an overactive sympathetic nervous system.\nOverall, the monkeys under the most social stress were most likely to form these dangerous plaques.\nLast but not least, once these plaques are formed in the blood vessels, chronic stress may cause increase blood pressure. The increase of blood force is more likely to tear the plaque loose. The now mobile plaque can then make its way to a blood vessel in the brain and cause a stroke!"}
{"_id": "e2c4b04e", "question": "Which swimming stroke is fastest?", "answers": "Front crawl, or freestyle, is the fastest method for all distances over 15 meters. Maybe over 8 meters.\nIn shorter swims, breaststroke is the fastest. This is because breaststroke has lots of acceleration but the wide leg stance of the kick keeps its high end speed down.\nIn the between distances, 8–15 meters, one or two breaststroke pulls, followed by freestyle arms and breaststroke kick, followed by freestyle is fastest. To hedge my bets a little, eggbeater kick might work better than whip kick in that middle distance.\nFor swimming around 25 meters from a dive, underwater dolphin kick might be fastest, with no surface swimming at all. From a push off (already in the water, pushing off a pool wall or I guess a rock or pier in open water), underwater swimming will be fastest for around 15 meters. The gravity assist of a dive makes a big difference!\nAs a lifeguard, I gotta say the fastest swimming method in doing a rescue is to run on the deck as far as possible and swim the smallest distance. Or canoe or row as close as you can, then get in and swim. I was a fast swimmer but paddling or rowing a boat or running is so much faster than swimming minimizing swim distance is very important."}
{"_id": "64489b1e", "question": "Is a heat stroke the same as a regular stroke?", "answers": "A stroke happens when the blood circulation to the brain suddenly stops, it can be caused by a block (ischemic stroke) or a bleeding (hemorrhagic stroke). It is as if the man is stricken by a hit on his head. He falls unconscious in the worst case scenario or is unable to speak or move a limb, at the best.\nIn 1960 scientists observed that when you put ‘drosophila’ cells in a warmer culture, some areas of the chromosome (genes) show a tendency of ‘puffing’ which is not a direct effect of the heat but a effect of transcription. Years later the culprit was identified as ‘heat shock’ protein (HSP). HSPs not only get released because of heat, but as the result of a host of stress. They tend to ward off the effect of stress by trashing defective proteins, but often end up in multiple effects much beyond that, including effects of tissue healing and immune response. Surprisingly, HSP is also a pathway involved in apoptosis (programmed cell death).\n(Pic Puffed genes) Google.\nHSP is a complex pathway of protection and destruction.\nHumans are equipped with an excellent air-con system; which makes us live happily in the scorching heat of Sahara desert as well as the icy glaciers of arctic.\n(A industrial AC Plant)\nThe human air-con system is far more complex, more adaptable, highly portable and far more sensitive than the AC plant you see above.\nBut sometimes in extreme heat, the human system fails. The sweating stops, the skin becomes red hot, the body core-temperature rises to beyond 104 degree F. The person can collapse, become breathless, puff and pant and go into multi-organ failure and die. Heat Stroke. The HSP play a crucial role in the pathobiology.\nNeither the drosophila chromosome in the Lab petri-dish or the tourist in the Kalahari desert tolerate extremes of heat. Exposure to heat and expression of HSP once again proves how biological pathways of survival and death are mysteriously interwoven."}
{"_id": "40c9bd0c", "question": "What are the disadvantages of two-stroke engines over four-stroke engines?", "answers": "The Main drawback of two stroke engine over four stroke engine is More Pollution..\nFour stroke engine technology now following Bharat Stage -IV (BS-IV) norms, In 2020, BS-VI will expected, (BS-V is skipped).\nTwo stroke engine have better Power to Weight ratio and produces one power for one rotation of Crankshaft. But it produces more emission hence two stroke engines are restricted.\nIt requires oil mixed with petrol for better lubrication.\nIt releases black oil through silencer along with exhaust smoke.\nExhaust smoke is in white color, because during combustion fuel burns along with oil. Oil Burns and produces white smoke. It cause health problems.\nIt produces more noise and vibrations."}
{"_id": "05bc90f2", "question": "How important is the stroke order of Chinese characters?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9fa9dac9", "question": "What can I do to reduce my risk of heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "73fe9519", "question": "What is two stroke and four stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "566d978c", "question": "What is the difference between a two stroke and a four stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c3dcee21", "question": "Is there any scientific evidence that suggests exoskeleton systems (e.g. Rewalk, Cyberdyne) regenerate neurons to help stroke or paralysis victims regain control of extremities?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "dcc82f83", "question": "How many valves are present in a 4 stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4affb01e", "question": "Which swimming stroke is your favourite?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c1e73687", "question": "Motorcycles and Motorcycling: 2 stroke thumper or 4 stroke refined, which one do you prefer and why?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "418dbc5c", "question": "Why do men stroke their chins or beards when thinking?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "fbf32fc6", "question": "What personal stroke of genius are you most proud of?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4bc1bea1", "question": "What bands are similar to The Strokes?", "answers": "The Hives\nKings of Leon\nThe Kooks\nArctic Monkeys(old)\nJet\nAlabama Shakes\nPavement\nYou can check out The Tourist Map of Music\nwhich is a music recommendation site that works quite well."}
{"_id": "b3e8196f", "question": "Is there any way to prevent brain strokes?", "answers": "There is a high sense of emergence and careful concern for anyone who is suddenly threatened with a condition of stroke irrespective of either ischemic stroke or haemmorhegic stroke.Its more evidential to notice that ischemic strokes have a slower onset of action which starts with commonly experience symptoms like mild headache,dizziness and imbalance of body movement that leads sudden fallout.Thus to counteract stroke immediately for preventing tragic outcome one should call an amulatory care with in fifteen minutes to seek an urgent care from intensivists who are connected to ICCU and qualified health care professional.Hence if ischaemic stroke is predicted by symptoms than its further damage to brain can be prevented by accessing emergency care to any cardiac unit.While on the contrary if it is a haemmorgic stroke than its more fatal because such stroke are resultant of an accidental injuries where rupturing of blood vessel leads to unconciousness and sudden mortality thus only clue is to rush with an ambulatory care to neurosurgeon who can conduct a needful intervention to stop bleeding and damage to internal parts of brain like medulla oblongata.Over and above stroke episodes are more fatal to human beings which leads to paralaysis of body and loss of speech."}
{"_id": "4cc970c0", "question": "What are the workings of a four-stroke petrol engine?", "answers": "Intake: also known as induction or suction This stroke of the piston begins at top dead center (T.D.C.) and ends at bottom dead center (B.D.C.). In this stroke the intake valve must be in the open position while the piston pulls an air-fuel mixture into the cylinder by producing vacuum pressure into the cylinder through its downward motion.\nCompression: This stroke begins at B.D.C, or just at the end of the suction stroke, and ends at T.D.C. In this stroke the piston compresses the air-fuel mixture in preparation for ignition during the power stroke (below). Both the intake and exhaust valves are closed during this stage.\nCombustion: also known as power or ignition This is the start of the second revolution of the four stroke cycle. At this point the crankshaft has completed a full 360 degree revolution. While the piston is at T.D.C. (the end of the compression stroke) the compressed air-fuel mixture is ignited by aspark plug\n(in a gasoline engine) or by heat generated by high compression (diesel engines), forcefully returning the piston to B.D.C. This stroke produces mechanical work from the engine to turn the crankshaft.\nExhaust: also known as outlet. During theexhaust stroke, the piston once again returns from B.D.C. to T.D.C. while the exhaust valve is open. This action expels the spent air-fuel mixture through the exhaust valve.\nThe points 1–4 are the steps of strokes from 1–4 of the engine."}
{"_id": "228c764e", "question": "How do I stroke ego of a person?", "answers": "I write this as a single woman divorced from a sociopath. I gave to him all I could not realising no matter what I did to boost his ego, it could never be enough, he in reality had no feeling of love. Now one would expect me if I found a decent, kind man, I would treat him not badly, but not give of myself as much, but wrong. In a relationship for me anyway I cannot speak for other females, I show love, make him feel special, I give my all because that is who I am. It might never happen for me who knows, but because I had a very bad experience, it doesn’t give me the right to treat another man badly. Love is the best thing ever, to love is to want to put the other before yourself, and love is what makes the world go round, not to have it is dismal, so all of you show it, give it if you are lucky enough to have someone in your life."}
{"_id": "ce46173c", "question": "A man is having a stroke. What do I do?", "answers": "Call emergency services!\nIn many communities VERY HIGH PRIORITY is given to those experiencing a “stroke” With immediate CAT Scan and if appropriate ‘clot dissolving’ medications Intravenously. Can be a life and neurologic function saver.\nCALL EMERGENCY SERVICES EXPLAIN THE SITUATION"}
{"_id": "94f206b7", "question": "Some paintings which look like random strokes by a little kid are auctioned off at huge prices. Can someone clarify what is special about these paintings that makes them so great?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7c4eea74", "question": "Do chickens and ducks like being stroked by humans, like cats and dogs do?", "answers": "I'm going to answer this in regards to chickens, since that's what I have the most experience with (but from the little experience I've had with ducks, it appears to be the same for them). So anyway:\nIt all depends on each individual chicken. You may not expect it, but they'll all have their own personalities, just like dogs and cats and even humans. Some will absolutely love attention and some will hate it.\nFor example, one of my hens (Davina) loves being held and will basically try to jump into my arms if I don't immediately pick her up. But then one of my other hens (Autumn) pretty much completely avoids me. She keeps her distance most of the time which becomes very difficult if I need to grab her for any reason. And my other chickens are pretty much somewhere between those two reactions. My rooster hates being grabbed but then once I catch him, he's so happy being held.\nSo I think the easiest answer to your question would probably just be: Sometimes."}
{"_id": "976aff17", "question": "What is relation between number of working stroke per minute and rpm in single acting four stroke engine?", "answers": "It is pretty simple in four stroke engine\nIn r.p.m - we measure the r.p.m of a crank shaft at how much rotations it takes in one minute\nIn working stroke-let me tell you four stroke engine have only one working stroke that is power stroke and other strokes like suction,compression,exhaust are ideal strokes\nPower stroke is the most important and only working stroke in four stroke engine."}
{"_id": "2dfb0683", "question": "What are some signs of a stroke in a dog (just curious, not an emergency)?", "answers": "I’ve been granted many lovely dogs in my long life, but, as far as I am aware only one actually had a stroke. I noticed that Jodie, one of our Standard Poodles, was suddenly walking in a strange fashion. I could only call it lopsided. She was leaning over, like a ship listing. Her eyes were dull. She didn’t seem to know quite where she was. She tried and failed several times to jump into her chair, but just couldn’t make it. She appeared to react very slowly to anything, almost as though she had been drugged (need I say she wasn’t!). She was a very good age for a S.P., having reached 15, and had slowed down a lot in recent weeks, but this was more than old age. I took her out to pee and had to hold her up (no easy task with a heavy dog!) Then she wanted to poo and before I could steady her, she fell into it. and just lay there struggling to get to her feet. I was crying as I somehow lifted her up, because I knew she was very distressed and the end was coming.\nOnce I got her back inside, cleaned up, and back into her favourite chair, I phoned our very reliable vet. She knew all our dogs very well and said it sounded as though Jodie had had a stroke. I was also of that opinion, although stupidly, I was very surprised, as I hadn’t considered the fact that dogs could have strokes!\nWe sat petting her until the vet arrived. The other dogs were strangely quiet. They all loved gentle Jodie who never pushed or hassled any of them. The vet. confirmed that it was indeed a stroke and said that, in her opinion, being such an old dog, Jodie would only get worse and we should consider her distress not ours. The vet. had thoughtfully brought the necessary equipment, so tearfully, we agreed what, after all, was best for Jodie. She drifted off in her chair with all the family around her. Our beautiful gentle giant, once so full of the joy of life. Still greatly missed and thought about so often.\nJodie 1988- 2003"}
{"_id": "1ec0ec6f", "question": "How do you swim butterfly stroke in swimming?", "answers": "With difficulty.\nButterfly is a tough stroke to master - in fact, when you're really good at it, it's the least tiring when you're going very fast. So the slower you go the harder it gets.\nIf you want to go it alone, master your dolphin movement first, and do this underwater with your arms outstretched as straight as they can be as high above your head as possible, as if you were going into a dive.\nBegin the dolphin movement at your fingers and imagine a shallow but powerful wave travelling down along your body - so every joint moves a little, but not much. Your knees won't bend any more than a degree - keep your quads and glutes tight.\nAnother way to imagine it is by kicking with your core muscles - as if you're doing a sit-up. Practice this by laying on your back with your arms outstretched and toes pointed as per a dive, then do a very short-range crunch - moving your head away from the floor by a few degrees only. Now flip over and do this laying on your front - contract your lower back muscles to reflect the movement. When you hold a plastic ruler in the middle and wobble it up and down, this is a close approximation of what your body should be doing.\nMaster swimming underwater like this, try face up and face down. Get used to inhaling water and don’t panic.\nNow - arms.\nYour arms are not windmills - they need to follow an hour-glass like pattern underwater as your hands constantly seek water that isn't already moving. Your hands should start in the water directly ahead of your forehead just narrower than shoulder width apart. Then as they pull down, draw outward, then in again toward the bellybutton, then out again toward the waist, exiting the water at the hip with a slight bend in the elbow before the recovery part, which should be as high as possible.\nPractice a few arm strokes at a time to get the motion rightly timed with your body movement. Your hands should travel through the water in line with the wave travelling along your body, so your hands exit the water at the hip just as your powerful legs begin their part of the movement - your arms should push you up and forward, as high out of the water as possible. Imagine a push-up where you must also leap forward. When your hands re-enter the water they should be at 45′ with palms facing outwards, ready to push water. Your bum should be high in the water at this point.\nBreathing.\nI put this last because, bizarrely, the less you can manage to breathe, the less tired you will be - putting your head up to breathe breaks the momentum of your body somewhat, so if you can manage a 50m sprint without breathing you will tire less and be much faster. That said, sooner or later, you will need air, so how to do it?\nAs your hands are making the second part of the hourglass motion, and beginning to push water down and backwards, this should force your upper body high in the water, as your hips should be lower and your feet in turn high. As your hands catch still water, nudge your chin forward and push up - this should be enough for you to just about clear the water with your mouth to intake a good lung of air. You want to either nudge your chin forward without really changing the level of your head - or - if you're getting powerful, try to raise your whole chest from the water, meaning you don't move your neck at all. Do not tilt your head back from the neck - this will upset your wave-like motion and slow you down, making it super hard to return to an efficient stroke.\nBreathe as little as you can, but ensure your stroke is such that you can take in enough air to continue going at pace.\nIf you manage to fit all that together, you're doing better than I ever did!"}
{"_id": "8a89b8df", "question": "Which are the 4 stroke bikes in India?", "answers": "Today all the bikes which runs on Indian road are 4 strokes. In exception there are some old bikes which are two stroke like RX-100, Rajdoot, Vespa etc. these are the ones which are old but still used by some people are two stroke. Otherwise all the new bikes are four stroke. For example\nPulsar\nDiscover\nSplendour\nCD deluxe\nKarizma"}
{"_id": "d314f4ce", "question": "Can ischemic strokes & hemorrhagic strokes be differentiated without MRI & CT scan? Should a stroke patient be given aspirin by the emergency department?", "answers": "For the first question\nAnswer- Yes\nDetails- Yes, only if you can-\nShow us through a video call/ bring the patient to the ER immediately to show, the progression of onset of stroke.\nAnswer all our questions while we ask for the history and you do not get pissed off for probing at minute details\nWe actually can't trust you to do any of these, and jumbling up of treatment protocols for ischaemic and hemorrhagic stroke can be catastrophic. Hence, we do the CT or MRI (depending on indications and contraindications) before deciding on definitive treatment/doing course correction in emergency management.\nFor the second question\nAnswer- NO\nDetails- No, because we don't know the type of stroke, and giving aspirin to a patient of hemorrhagic stroke can be catastrophic. Aspirin is given only in ischaemic stroke."}
{"_id": "13866a76", "question": "Will a brain MRI reveal past strokes? If a stroke robust enough not to be considered a TIA were to occur, would it be visible in an MRI years later?", "answers": "I had a stroke, grand mal seizure which broke my back (L1 and L2) on 10/10/10….not a good day.\nMultiple CAT scans and MRI’s showed “moderate brain damage” from “prior strokes”. I had no knowledge of the prior strokes, but my Neurologist showed me the scans and said…”see all that white area….that’s damaged brain cells”….and there was a lot of white. I had a contrast MRI done which showed “recent” damage, based, I was told, on the amount of contrast that was taken up. Oddly, it was not as large as the original damage, but specifically located in the occipital region. This made sense since my stroke caused strange and scary visual disturbances.\nI was able to walk out of the hospital the next day, with aphasia, but otherwise seemingly OK. I asked the neurologist if I would be getting therapy for cognitive issues and he said “but you show no cognitive deficit”. In my addlebrained state, I accepted it…but I knew I was not the same.\nAnd here is the important part to people who may have had a stroke. Since only I seemed to be concerned about damage and it was not too apparent to others, I knew that I had to handle my recovery on my own (now I know I should have pushed to get professional help at that time, but I was not thinking clearly).\nI decided that I would meditate, play word games and play the guitar every day, since I had read that they help. Every day for about a year I spent 3–4 hours doing both and I am totally convinced that I am 98% recovered due to those efforts. I found Silva Systems tapes to be particularly soothing and helpful to my recovery.\nToday, nearly 7 years later most people can observe nothing that would be indicative of a stroke. I’ve developed “coping” mechanisms like double checking everything I write since I can no longer recognize homonyms (some results are humorous), I ask people “have I told you this before” and the answer is “yes” often, so I don’t repeat it. But I have no memory of having said it.\nI now also take about every “brain” supplement there is and I do find that some make a difference.\nSo my prior strokes, (and perhaps recent ones) are not apparent to me, but they are visible on MRI’s. But I believe that, in my case at least, that there are positive outcomes from a difficult situation."}
{"_id": "9f43ac9f", "question": "Do bad teeth cause diabetes, and strokes?", "answers": "How can diabetes affect my mouth?\nToo much glucose, also called sugar, in your blood from diabetes can cause pain, infection, and other problems in your mouth. Your mouth includes\nyour teeth\nyour gums\nyour jaw\ntissues such as your tongue, the roof and bottom of your mouth, and the inside of your cheeks\nGlucose is present in your saliva—the fluid in your mouth that makes it wet. When diabetes is not controlled, high glucose levels in your saliva help harmful bacteria grow. These bacteria combine with food to form a soft, sticky film called plaque. Plaque also comes from eating foods that contain sugars or starches. Some types of plaque cause tooth decay or cavities. Other types of plaque cause gum disease and bad breath.\nGum disease can be more severe and take longer to heal if you have diabetes. In turn, having gum disease can make your blood glucose hard to control.\nWhat happens if I have plaque?\nPlaque that is not removed hardens over time into tartar and collects above your gum line. Tartar makes it more difficult to brush and clean between your teeth. Your gums become red and swollen, and bleed easily—signs of unhealthy or inflamed gums, called gingivitis.\nWhen gingivitis is not treated, it can advance to gum disease called periodontitis. In periodontitis, the gums pull away from the teeth and form spaces, called pockets, which slowly become infected. This infection can last a long time. Your body fights the bacteria as the plaque spreads and grows below the gum line. Both the bacteria and your body’s response to this infection start to break down the bone and the tissue that hold the teeth in place. If periodontitis is not treated, the gums, bones, and tissue that support the teeth are destroyed. Teeth may become loose and might need to be removed. If you have periodontitis, your dentist may send you to a periodontist, an expert in treating gum disease.\nDiabetes Medication - Click Here To Read"}
{"_id": "60450260", "question": "How did you know that you were having a stroke? What were the symptoms? What did it feel like?", "answers": "Thank you for your question.\nFollowing two weeks of chronic neck pain which I was told was probably just a sprain, one Sunday night I decided I couldn’t take it any more and I took myself to hospital. I was checked over and although nobody had any idea what was wrong with me, they kept me in overnight for observation.\nBy this time, it was about 2am and I hadn’t eaten, so I sneaked out of the ward to to buy snacks a can of lemonade from a vending machine. I took it back to my bed, opened the bar of chocolate, and that’s when it happened. I was suddenly overcome with the most nauseating dizziness I’ve ever known in my life. I lunged for the panic button shortly before losing 99% of my motor skills. Nurses quickly appeared and helped me back into bed. I was violently sick, I had no sense of direction, and I was disoriented to the extent that I threw myself off the bed, onto the floor again, thinking I was steadying myself. Then I passed out.\nWhen I woke up the following morning, I felt like I had the most epic hangover, but basically OK - nothing more than a really, really heavy night out on the piss would cause. Still, nobody had a clue what had happened. Over the course of the day, I began to go numb down the right hand side of my body, and this symptom yielded an immediate CT scan. I tried to stand to go the CT, and discovered that I couldn’t stand up; my legs buckled and I crumpled to the floor. The nurses helped me back into bed and instead they pushed me, still in the bed, to the scan.\nAfter being wheeled back from the scan, about half an hour later, a consultant appeared, and showed me a printout of my brain scan; he pointed to the areas in my cerebellum which had died, and then pointed to the withered artery that had caused it. Five minutes later, I was surrounded by paramedics, moved to a stretcher, and transported by ambulance to another hospital with a specialist stroke unit.\nOver the next three days, with physiotherapy and sheer bloody-minded determination, I managed to figure out how to stand up again, and to walk after a fashion. I was discharged, and because I felt that I had something to prove, I turned down the offer of a taxi, and instead went home by bus. It was a very difficult bus ride, but I felt better having done it.\nThe next day, I was watching TV, and it happened again. The same symptoms, except this time it was accompanied by both my hands closing up like those naff crane grip games you get at the seaside. This time around, I knew what was happening - and I remained completely lucid for a time.\nIt’s the most uncomfortable feeling I think you’re capable of feeling; to know that you are feeling, first hand, parts of your brain physically dying. You can almost feel the metaphorical lights going off in your head. You can feel yourself mental capacity andcontrol over your own body diminishing.\nI remember looking down at my hands and watching them shake, spasm, and close like grotesque arthritic claws. I remember the look on my mother’s face as she sat in front of me, her eyes piercing mine as she watched what could have been my last seconds on earth.\nI completely understood everything that was happening. I know what it feels like to actually become brain damaged; I wish I could explain it. I felt as though I was losing my mind; literally and figuratively - and at the same time I was somehow still aware enough to actually notice it happening.\nI did remain conscious but shortly after this point, my memory becomes a little blurry - I have a recollection of paramedics again lifting me onto a stretcher. My mother told me later that I had tried to make a lame joke about the ambulance being brand new - but I barely remember anything at all. But my recall of the event is like a foggy dream; fragments of imagery and colour and sensations and very little else.\nBy the time I regained my awareness, I was back at hospital and in resuscitation. A nurse I recognised from before was passing me a cup of water. I remember a flurry of activity, more scans, various injections, a succession of tests, and then awakening the following afternoon back in my original ward (though two beds along) to the sight of my entire family gathered around my bedside.\nFurther tests and another brain scan that day revealed more extensive damage to my cerebellum, and I was once again bed-ridden.\nI remember lying in that bed, that night, thinking about how my life would look from then on. At the time I was in a group with eight friends in a Go-karting tournament, and I worried that I wouldn’t be able to drive again. Then it occurred to me that I might not be able to walk again. I cried - and the next morning I forced myself to stand up, and over the next week, the physiotherapist helped me a lot, and though I couldn’t do much for more than five minutes at a time, I was able to stand up and walk - albeit slowly - unaided by the time I was discharged.\nWhen I was discharged, I did take a taxi - mainly because my doctor walked with me to the door and insisted - and I spent the next two months trying to figure out how to do perfectly ordinary things - making a cup of tea, turning on the television, walking up and down the stairs were all crazily-complicated and when I achieved them, I felt as though I’d just won a gold medal at the Olympics.\nAt the end of the two months, at my own request, I was allowed to go back to work - albeit for only three hours a day (that gradually went back up to full time) and I began slotting my life back together.\nFour years later, I’m still here. Lasting symptoms are largely gone, although there are a handful of “reminders” of what happened; I still have patches of (predominantly) the right-hand side of my body I can’t feel - including my right hand, the top of my head, and a patch of skin about the size of a credit card just above my navel. The doctors discovered a minor difference in response time between my left and right hand sides, which made typing difficult as my brain was sending all the signals at the right time, but my right hand was doing things a fraction of a second later than the left - but I learned to type all over again and six months after the stroke, I was back at my original speed and accuracy.\nI’m a little clumsier than I used to be, and sometimes when I wake up in the morning, I can’t feel my arms and legs - but they wake up pretty quickly and I’m off to get on with my business.\nWhat’s odd is that people have described subtle changes in my personality since the stroke; that I’m substantially the same person, of course, but that I am a little shorter of temper, and seem to appear more confident in social situations. To compliment that, I feel different - and that’s another feeling I’m going to have a hard time explaining. I feel like me, but a different version, a different “hardware revision” I suppose - Richard 1.0 had a stroke and woke up as Richard 1.1. I’m the same person, I look the same, I sound the same, but my circuits are wired up a bit different now.\nAnd it’s true - less than 40% of my cerebellum survived, but my brain just re-routed around the problems and I can walk, I can run, I can write, I can speak, I can drive, I can bowl, I can cook, I can write music; I can do everything I did before - but since 2015 I feel like my brain downloaded Waze; I can still go to the same destinations, but the route is a bit different now and there’s still some roads along the way I’m really not familiar with.\nI’m still getting to know myself again - but the new version of me is enough like the old version that I’m comfortable.\nAll things considered, I escaped with a bloody nose. Others aren’t so lucky.\nMy uncle had a stroke a couple of years before I did, in his mid fifties, and on paper it was less serious than mine - but he didn’t walk at all for a month and his right hand is now almost paralysed.\nI could’ve easily died; or possibly ended up confined to a wheelchair and lost my ability to speak. I count my lucky stars that I made it as intact as I did.\nFolks, please remember - the common symptoms of a stroke are only the common symptoms - not the only symptoms.\nIt’s possible to have a stroke and absolutely none of the common symptoms manifest.\nThis is yet another reason why, when something serious happens to you, the absolute worst thing you can do is self-diagnose yourself. My situation was so odd, not even a hospital full of specialist doctors could diagnose me for a few days.\nYou need to call an ambulance."}
{"_id": "41d110b4", "question": "What is the next master-stroke of Modi on 2019?", "answers": "Master stroke of Modi before 2019 elections is his slogan “Saaf Niyat Sahi Vikas” which describes his clean intention to have a great development.\nThe promise of 'Achhe Din' has been replaced by a new motto- 'Saaf Niyat, Sahi Vikas' (clean intent, right development).\nThe party has probably realized that with Demonetization, Goods and Services Tax (GST), ever-soaring fuel prices and a raging unemployment rate, Achhe Din will probably draw more jibes than votes.\nSo, they are going to hide behind the age-old curtain of 'good intentions', in the upcoming elections, a slogan that was released in a tweet by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on the occasion of the fourth anniversary of the BJP-led Union Government."}
{"_id": "93872944", "question": "How does a 2-stroke diesel engine work?", "answers": "Two stroke Detroit Diesel engines were once popular here in the USA, but they failed to advance fuel economy and emissions fast enough to be practical going forward. They were discontinued in the seventies.\nFor the two stroke 53, 71 and 92 series engines, a roots type blower was a mandatory part of the engine. Later on, turbochargers were available as well.\nThe Detroit diesel worked like this. There was a circle of ports all the way around the bottom of the cylinder. The ports were uncovered near bottom dead center and the blower blew a very strong draft through this area, clean air in one side and clean air and exhaust out the other. When the piston came down the fresh air evacuated the exhauat and filled the cylinder with freah air to be compressed. Just beyond top dead center, duel was injected and as i n all dieaels, combustion was imediate.\nThe Detroit Diesel was unique in that almost 25% of engine coolinh was derived from thia airflow. A great deal of the charge air blew right throigh the engine without ever being compressed or mixed with fuel and burned.\nAt any rate, theae engines were never cleaned up to current standards. Detroit Diesel instead dropped their name on a clean sheet design 4 stroke dieael, the Series 60 engines which turned.out to be a very good design, right out of the box at 430 HP. Mike Heaton"}
{"_id": "dda9b9ae", "question": "In a four stroke engine where does energy come from to move the piston up and down?", "answers": "That is tricky... in a four stroke engine, the only source of energy being the fuel , the energy to move piston comes only from the burning of fuel !!\nWell I assume that your question goes a little detailed as what is the driving force that makes the piston move in every stroke.\nTo initiate the engine , we run the crankshaft with a motor run by a battery ,which was charged when the engine was running.\n\nDuring the first cycle the crankshaft run by the motor opens the inlet valves\nconnected by gears to the crankshaft such that the fuel charge is sucked in.\nthe pressure of the air fuel charge itself helps the piston complete the suction stroke.\nDuring the second stroke, the inertia of the crankshaft makes the piston move upward and compress the charge.\nDuring the third stroke is where the combustion is initiated and the sudden burst of the fuel pushes the piston down rotating the crankshaft.\nDuring the last stroke again the inertia in the crankshaft pushes the piston upwards to push the exhaust gases out with the opening of the exhaust valves.\nthe crank wheel is by itself designed to make the piston move by the factor of inertia in the IC engine."}
{"_id": "b3a031f6", "question": "In countries with universal “free” healthcare, how can the government afford to pay for long term care for chronic conditions such as MS, dementia, stroke, children with congenital defects, etc?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3d707766", "question": "What would happen if I put 2 stroke petrol in a 4 stroke engine?", "answers": "Theres no such thing as 2 stroke fuel. A 2 stroke engine uses regular gasoline to which you add a small amount of oil. The difference beteen 2 stroke and 4 stroke is a 2 stroke has no pressure oiling system so it has to be added to the fuel for cylinder lubrication. You cant run a 2 stroke engine long without added oil or it will seize. You can run a 4 stroke motor with fuel youve mixed for a 2 stroke. You may have oil smoke from the exhaust or foul plugs over some time, but it wont hurt the engine. You cannot run diesel fuel in a gas engine or vice versa either."}
{"_id": "c00bd058", "question": "What is 4 stroke engine and parts?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "114f21db", "question": "Does alcohol cause strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f6407010", "question": "What is the valve timing diagram for a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "af9a63c5", "question": "Which bikes are 2 stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b2d2e3f0", "question": "Why do we mix oil directly with petrol in 2 stroke IC engines and not in 4 stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3c6fa8e2", "question": "How can you tell if a lawnmower is two-stroke or four-stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bb7bb6fe", "question": "How long for someone to die that has had a massive stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2164bd2c", "question": "Why do big machines usually work in two-stroke engines, and small machines work in four-stroke engines?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "55a82b42", "question": "What is the best natural treatment for stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8fa30330", "question": "Is a diesel 2-stroke engine impossible?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1b39e175", "question": "What is the practical application of 2 stroke CI engine?", "answers": "Practical examples of a 2 stroke CI or Diesel engine that I know is the engine in a British Army Chieftain tank and a model of British Diesel Electric railway locomotive. I believe the tank engine was a design captured at the end of the Second World War and was actually a Dornier bomber engine. This was a dual crankshaft 6 cylinder with 12 pistons coming together in the centre of the cylinder to make compression and hence fire the fuel. The fuel was injected through the wall of the cylinder and a gear chest was then used to transmit the drive. In the tank the intake is supplemented by a Rootes type supercharger to increase power. This was very unreliable and was only pursued because of a mandate at the time(60’s) of a need to have a multi fuel engine. The engine was mounted horizontally in the wing of the aircraft but vertically in the tank. The main flaw was that the plane would take off and after a climb would then stay at a set throttle for hours, this combined with a modest output gave a reliable use. In the tank it was boosted to 650 plus horsepower and the constant changing of RPM during mobile use caused the cylinder liners to move and distort leading to coolant loss and catastrophic failure. The railway engine powered a generator for the motive power and again tended to run at a set rate for hours giving good reliability. There were no valves like a 4 stroke and the timing of the intake and exhaust was by radially placed ports in the cylinder wall which were uncovered in a sequence of crankshaft timing."}
{"_id": "868ac0b9", "question": "Why had to develop a 4-stroke engine in place of 2-stroke?", "answers": "Pollution mostly. two stroke engines burn their fuel very poorly compared to a four stroke. You are burning two stroke oil, you have to put the two stroke oil in with the fuel on a two stroke engine and the result of this is smoke once it has been burnt causes pollution and as has been mentioned their exhaust gases are smelly.\nFor the same engine capacity you tend to get more power out of a two stroke engine than you do out of a four stroke. For example a 5.7L two stroke V8 would actually be more powerful than a 5.7L four stroke V8.\nThe thing is the high levels of pollution is why two strokes are not popular. Imagine if everyone drove a two stroke."}
{"_id": "2ec04d79", "question": "Why don't we have an 8 or a 16 stroke engine? Is there a possibility to have such engines in the near future?", "answers": "Each engine stroke performs a certain action. In the case of a 4-stroke engine, that's:\n1. intake (pulls in fuel and air)\n2. compression (compresses the mixture)\n3. power/ignition (explosive expansion of the fuel)\n4. exhaust (exhaust gasses expelled\nA two-stroke engine combines these steps, something like:\n1. intake/compression (first half of the cycle does intake, second half compresses)\n2. ignition/exhaust (first half of the cycle does ignition, second half exhaust)\nWe don't have an 8 stroke engine because there just aren't any more than 4 steps that are necessary to accomplish combustion and release of waste gasses. We also don't WANT to have any more than a 4-stroke engine because it's inefficient - only one of the four strokes of the engine is producing any kinetic energy; even if you could, having any more is either wasteful or just a multiple of an existing two/four stroke engine."}
{"_id": "e88bb0f2", "question": "How many strokes are there available in an engine?", "answers": "There are 2 stroke and 4 stroke engines available today with 4 stroke engines being the most common.\n2 stroke engines nowadays are only found in small machinery.\nThe processes that occur in a 4 stroke engine are sucction, compression, expansion and exhaust. Here power is produced in expansion stroke where the fuel gets ignited.\n2 stroke engines have ports instead of valves i.e., exhaust port and transfer port. After the combustion of fuel, the piston moves downwards, opening the exhaust port. Further downward movement of piston, uncovers the transfer port and as a result the air fuel mixture which is fed directly to the crankcase is forced up through the transfer port into the combustion chamber. This fresh incoming charge helps in removing the exhaust in the cylinder.\nIn this type of engine, there is a tendency for mixing of exhaust with fresh mixture."}
{"_id": "67f48f83", "question": "Which is the most beautiful cricket stroke?", "answers": "These are the best shorts in my POV.\nRahul Dravid Cut shot\n\nA very late cut which makes the bowler think that they got him bowled but at the very last moment he cuts the ball to the boundary. That disappointment in bowler's face is enough to show the brilliance in the technique\n\nSangakkara Cover drive\n\nThere are many best cover drives from many players across the world. But when it comes to Sanga it reaches the peak elegance. One foot on the ground and his right leg pointing exactly on the direction of the shot played and the way he does this so easily makes this the best.\nPonting Pull shot\n\nThe term hook shot is used when the shot is played against a ball bouncing at or above chest high to the batsman, the batsman thus \"hooking\" the ball around behind square leg, either along the ground or in the air. He literally rotate in his back foot to complete that shot which makes that a glorious visual even to the opponents\n\nSachin straight drive\n\nNo explanation needed for this shot. God with his perfect weapon.\n\nand some other shots are...\n\nPietersen reverse sweep\n\n\nSteve Waugh Slog sweep\n\n\nSachin Upper cut\n\nPietersen switch hit\n\n\nDilscoop by Dilshan(formerly Marillierscoop)\n\n\nDe villiers leg side slash\n\n\nMatthew Hayden Step Six"}
{"_id": "88c587f7", "question": "What Chinese character has most strokes?", "answers": "Probably this word:\nIt contains 56 strokes, and was pronounced \"Biang1\". It's a name for a special noodle in Shaanxi province, called Biang Biang noodle.\nHowever, this word was not recorded in Kangxi dictionary or Xinhua dictionary, indicating this word (although famous now) might be a local dialect word, not \"official Chinese\".\nOfficially, it would be this word:\nIt's pronounced \"Da2\", to describe the way dragon flys. the word contains 51 stroke and was recorded in both Kangxi, xinhua, and modern Chinese dictionaries."}
{"_id": "38fde42f", "question": "Why do railways prefer two-stroke diesel engines in locomotives over 4-stroke engines?", "answers": "Despite what everyone has stated the railroads do not prefer the two-stroke diesel it was more a factor of what was supplied by the locomotive manufacturers of which there are two in the US, EMD, and GE. The EMD diesel was always two-stroke but the GE’s were always four-stroke. It was true that the EMD locomotives were more popular historically but that began to change in the early 90’s with many new innovations by the GE dash series locos. At some point (after I retired) EMD actually added a four-stroke engine but I believe they still supply the 710 series two-banger engine which was a good one. The rail service continued to demand more and more H.P. and the manufacturers tried to deliver. This eventually led to a problem with the crankshaft bearings on the EMD 2-strokes 645 engines. This was caused by the welded steel construction (in part) of the frame which was flexing under heavy loads, with the new power rating. This caused even more purchases of the GE’s equipped with the FDL series engines 4-stroke. I personally liked the 2-strokers better because I considered them easier to work on. The EMD’s did not use pushrods but they still needed 2 camshafts with extra gears to drive them so the two engines were not significantly different as far as running gear. By the way, some have confused 2-stroke diesel with small engine operation. Diesels never use crankcase pressure at all in their cycle."}
{"_id": "24d11b66", "question": "Do you know about stroke?", "answers": "It depends on the severity of the stroke. If it’s a massive stroke it will likely kill you, instantly. If it moderate or a TIA, your chances may be 50:50 if you know what your looking for. What follows is a short list of noticeable symptoms to look for if you’re having or just had a stroke.\nYou suddenly become extremely dizzy, one side of your face droops or sags, one corner of you mouth turns downward, have a sudden weakness in your limbs , trouble standing or walking, difficulty speKing , slurred speech. Numbness in two of you limbs on the same did.\nIn 2014, I had a TIA sitting at my kitchen table reading the morning paper. Suddenly , in a microsecond, I knew something had just happened but I didn’t know what. The first physical thing I noticed is when I reached for my water bottle, instead of grasping it I didn’t open my tight hand and just knocked it over. For whatever reason I started to do some hand exercises and quickly realized I couldn’t do with my right what my left had did easily. I sat there for a few minutes, still trying to figure out what had just happened. I certainly wasn’t considering a stroke. So I got up from the table, took a shower and drove to the medical school where I worked. Walking to my office I encountered the Dean, and stopped to ask him a question. He suddenly stepped in front of me, looked me square in the eyes and asked “do you feel alright”?. I started to answer that something strange had happened at my home when he interrupted and said matter of factorly, “ I know what happened, you’ve had a stroke, the right side of your mouth is dropping”! In less than 10 minutes they had me in the ER being examined for a stroke. That was later confirmed by my neurologist reading an MRI I had just been given. He told me it was a non-hemorrhagic TIA I suffered in my left brain hemisphere, in an area consistent with the symptoms I had been describing. So like most individuals who suffer a mild stroke, I was aware something had happened but I never considered a stroke."}
{"_id": "56085231", "question": "Can an MRI show a stroke?", "answers": "Absolutely! MRI is an excellent tool for detecting, localizing and stratifying severity of strokes that happen anywhere within an hour of ictus (the moment that the clot occurs and symptoms begin), and any time thereafter. It can identify regions of damaged brain which shrink over time (“encephalomalacia”) that occur with chronic infarcts and are present for the rest of one’s life. Neurologists and other doctors can use this information to better understand the resultant damage from a stroke, neural deficits (e.g., facial droop, difficulty speaking, arm\\leg weakness) and possible medical management to decrease risk of future strokes.\nAtherosclerosis and arterial plaques are common sources of strokes (little pieces break off the bigger vessels in the neck then flow with the blood ainto the brain, wedge into the smaller downstream arteries supplying the brain and block it from getting oxygenated blood, resulting in tissue ischemia, ie “stroke” or infarct. This mechanism is so common for stroke that most people with strokes will also get some sort of extra imaging with the CT or MRI to look at these vessels. “CTA” (CT Angiogram) or “MRA” (MR Angiogram) are the names of these “addon” exams that can be performed at the same time as the CT or MRI which is looking at the brain tissue itself.\nMRI can also identify the presence of blood products in a stroke (e.g., “hemorrhagic stroke”) which can be helpful in intervention of acute strokes - although CT can identify acute hemorrhage just as well or sometimes better than MRI. MRI is better for old or chronic blood products. A smaller portion of strokes with hemorrhage are not due to atherosclerosis but are due to hypertension. These types of strokes occur in characteristic areas of the brain and, when identified, will clue the clinician to get better control of a patient’s blood pressure to prevent similar events in the future.\n2 small points getting back to the original question. A TIA (transient ischemic attack) is a condition with symptoms identical to stroke, but resolve within 24 hours. By definition, the MRI (or CT) should not show any brain damage to account for the symptoms (otherwise it is a stroke). This is important because it can be a key intervention point to medical management for prevention of an ACTUAL stroke down the road. For example, a doctor may prescribe anti-platelet drugs like aspirin or plavix to decrease the risk of plaque rupture if present in those neck arteries.\nThe other point is that contrast (gadolinium) enhanced MRI is not necessary for simply identifying whether or not a stroke has occurred at some point in a patient’s life. Further, contrast is not needed to differentiate an acute from chronic stroke. But there is one situation where contrast may be helpful and that is when trying to figure when a recent stroke might’ve occurred. Without getting into too much detail, a region of brain that looks damaged from a stroke can be identified as “subacute” if it shows gadolinium enhancement on MRI. That means the stroke is neither super recent or super old, but happened somewhere betwee 1 day and 3 weeks ago. The different ages of stroke are generally broken down as follows (although small variances in the timeframe depend on who you ask, and from patient to patient): hyperacute (0-6 hours), acute(6-24 hours), subacute (1 day to 3 weeks), chronic (>3 weeks)."}
{"_id": "28a6c3e0", "question": "What is a four stroke diesel engine?", "answers": "In Four stroke diesel engine, each cycle completed two revolution of crank. Each cycle mean suction, compression, power, exhaust.\nDiesel engine is also known as compression ignition engine. Because inside the cylinder (combustion chamber) only air is compressed. So air goes to maximum temperature. Fuel is injected as fine droplets through the fuel injector. From this fuel is ingnited by the air which is in maximum temperature inside the combustion chamber. i cant explain whole thing of diesel engine so,\nYou can refer this in following links,\nDiesel Engine Principle and Working Cycle Explained -\nFour-Stroke Cycle Diesel Engine"}
{"_id": "9bf17db3", "question": "Which types of diesel (2 stroke or 4 stroke) engine is more efficient?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4717f2c5", "question": "What is the critical appeal of The Strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0d0fe88f", "question": "What is the difference between piston of two stroke engine and piston of four stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "37bea7fa", "question": "What kind of diet should a person go on if they've had a stroke and heart attack? Is a vegan diet necessary for him to prevent another stroke and/or heart attack?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b550a02c", "question": "How is the following equation possible: 83.25 + 17.75 + 19,220 = 2,021?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bb34744e", "question": "How doesn’t a 6-stroke engine create as much pollutants as a 4-stroke engine creates? Can this engine be fuel-efficient? Can it create more power than a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "89ca75fa", "question": "Can a stroke cause a personality change?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b293e1af", "question": "For the same engine weight and size, which engine is more powerful; a two stroke or four stroke and why?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b50e6075", "question": "How do you explain the working of a four-stroke diesel engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b6f8d285", "question": "For what purpose are two stroke cycle engines mainly used?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1df6c2b1", "question": "Why isn't a two-stroke engine efficient even though it uses more power strokes than a four-stroke engine?", "answers": "Several reasons, I’d refer you to the earlier answers by Ahmed Samii, Willy Roentgen, and Michael Heaton for the exact reasons for the 2-stroke internal combustion engines being inefficient, but these would have to be considered to remedy many of the problems and allow the 2 cycle ICE to actually be decently efficient.\nYou need a means of controlling the intake port so it can suck all air in when possible, then close off while the transfer port can be opened after the air gets compressed, you could use a rotary intake valve for doing this.\n\n2. You may consider plating the rotary valve with black diamond ceramic so it’ll be able to last as long as possible.\n\n3. You may also have to consider fuel injection into a small swirling prechamber like they did for them Toyota cars in the 1970’s, possibly air-assisted fuel injection like that company Orbital UAV has worked on and made since its orbital engine concept in the 1970’s didn’t pan out and the company’s people kept improving on that injection system to this day.\n\n4. Timing these parts would have to be considered and be kept up.\n\n5. Using a magneto powered cdi like on the Rotax engines would also be nice and allow minimal maintenance while ensuring a proper spark to ignite the fuel air mixture properly."}
{"_id": "1d0ae146", "question": "How do I convert a 4-stroke petrol into a 2-stroke engine to run on compressed air?", "answers": "I guess you would call an engine run on compressed air a 2-stroke, but I'm not sure its all that meaningfully. I also can't think of a reason to convert a 4-stroke gasoline engine to run on compressed air.\nThe way you would do it is to change the camshaft sprockets or gears so that they had a one-to-one ratio with the crankshaft and then have a cam ground so that it openes the intake valve at the top of the stroke and the exhaust valve at the bottom. You likely would need to change the intake valve spring to one with a higher rate to compensate for the air pressure that is trying to open the valve. I suspect that you will have to modify the intake manifold to deal with the pressure.\nI think a 4-stroke will turn if you were just to apply air pressure to the intake. You likely will have turn anything less than a 4 cylinder over with a starter or crank to get it started as its possible or maybe likely it will be at a position with all the intake valve closed or maybe on open with the piston before TDC."}
{"_id": "8223e452", "question": "Which needs more lubrication 2 stroke or four stroke engine?", "answers": "FOUR STROKE ENGINE\nFour-stroke engines are lubricated by oil held in an oil sump. The oil is distributed through the engine by splash lubrication or a pressurized lubrication pump system; these systems may be used alone or together.\nSplash lubrication is achieved by partly submerging the crankshaft in the oil sump. The momentum of the rotating crankshaft splashes oil to other engine components such as the cam lobes, wrist pins and cylinder walls.\nPressurized lubrication uses an oil pump to provide a pressurized film of lubricant between moving parts such as the main bearings, rod bearings and cam bearings. It also pumps oil to the engine’s valve guides and rocker arms.\nTWO STROKE ENGINE\nTwo-stroke engines collect some oil beneath the crankshaft; however, two-stroke engines employ a total-loss lubrication system that combines oil and fuel to provide both energy and engine lubrication. The oil and fuel are combined in the cylinder’s intake tract and lubricate critical components such as the crankshaft, connecting rods and cylinder walls.\nOil-injected two-stroke engines inject the oil directly into the engine, where it mixes with the fuel, while premix two-stroke engines require a fuel-oil mixture that is combined before being installed in the fuel tank. In general, two-stroke engines are known to wear more quickly than four-stroke engines because they don’t have a dedicated lubricant source.\nI hope u get the answer :)"}
{"_id": "5790221d", "question": "How do I identify a person suffering from a stroke?", "answers": "STROKE: Remember the 1st Three Letters.....\nS. T. R.\nSTROKE IDENTIFICATION:\nA neurologist says that if he can get to a stroke victim within 3 hours he can totally reverse the effects of a stroke...totally. He said the trick was getting a stroke recognized, diagnosed, and then getting the patient medically cared for within 3 hours, which is tough.\nRECOGNIZING A STROKE\nThank God for the sense to remember the '3' steps, STR. Read and Learn.\nSometimes symptoms of a stroke are difficult to identify. Unfortunately, the lack of awareness spells disaster. The stroke victim may suffer severe brain damage when people nearby fail to recognize the symptoms of a stroke.\nNow doctors say a bystander can recognize a stroke by asking three (3) simple questions:\nS *Ask the individual to SMILE.\nT *Ask the person to TALK and SPEAK A SIMPLE SENTENCE (Coherently)\n(i.e. Chicken Soup)\nR *Ask him or her to RAISE BOTH ARMS.\nIf he or she has trouble with ANY ONE of these tasks, call emergency number immediately and describe the symptoms to the dispatcher.\nNew Sign of a Stroke -------- Stick out Your Tongue!\nNOTE: Another 'sign' of a stroke is this: Ask the person to 'stick' out his tongue. If the tongue is\n'crooked', if it goes to one side or the other that is also an indication of a stroke."}
{"_id": "7bc4b5c1", "question": "Why is the stroke length twice that of the crank radius in a piston engine?", "answers": "The motion of a non-offset piston connected to a crank through a connecting rod (as would be found in internal combustion engines), can be expressed through several mathematical equations.\nFirst of all we would understand about the crank radius and how it covers the distance of stroke.\nPistons motion animation with same rod length and crank radius values in graph above :\n\nPistons motion animation with various half strokes.\nPositionEdit\n\nPosition with respect to crank angle (by rearranging the triangle relation):\n\n\n\n\n\n\nVelocityEdit\n\nVelocity with respect to crank angle (take firstderivative, using the chain rule):\n\nAccelerationEdit\n\nAcceleration with respect to crank angle (take second derivative, using the chain rule and thequotient rule):\nBecause of all these factors stroke length is always twice of crank."}
{"_id": "095d05a8", "question": "How are guitar chords made (in physics)? Why does stroking five strings make an A chord in terms of frequency?", "answers": "From a musical point of view, you make an A major chord with the notes A, C# and E. These are musically significant because C# is approximately the fifth harmonic of A (a 5:1 frequency ratio) shifted down two octaves (a 1:4 ratio), i.e. 5:4. And E is the third harmonic (3:1) shifted down one octave (1:2), i.e., 3:2.\nYou have a fair bit of flexibility musically to choose exactly which A, which C# and which E, and different \"voicings\" give different effects. You can move any of them up or down an octave (a 2:1 or 1:2 frequency change), and the A doesn't necessarily have to be the lowest note. If the musical context it strong you might be able to leave one out and just imply it. If you want a rich sounding chord you might double one or more of them in different octaves.\nThen when you know what you'd like, you need to wrestle with the practicalities of approximating it on the guitar without tying your left hand in knots. You have 6 strings, E, A, D, G, B, E, and each of them has frets placed so as to shorten the strings and raise the pitch in units of musical half steps (a.k.a., semitones), which are twelfths of an octave. Physically that's to say that each higher fret raises the frequency a factor of the twelfth root of 2, 2^(1/12)=1.0594630944. (That's the same interval as between adjacent notes on the piano.) 5/4 is close to four half-steps, or 2^(4/12)=1.25992105. 3/2 is close to seven half-steps or 2^(7/12)=1.498307077. All the musical notes are close enough to some number of half-steps apart. So you have to start with each open note and try to get a finger to a fret that will make it an A, C# or E. If that's not feasible for a particular string given the other choices you've made, then you may have to avoid sounding it."}
{"_id": "d5a8b0e2", "question": "Why does cracking one's neck increase the risk of stroke?", "answers": "This pops up in the news frequently and has been proven false. In all cases, the stroke was in progress prior to the visit to the chiropractor. Multiple studies have been done that were unable to find a link between the two. Researchers from the Departments of Neurosurgery, at Penn State Hershey Medical Center, Loma Linda University Medical Center and The Pennsylvania State University, in conducting a systematic review and meta-analysis of chiropractic neck manipulation and cervical artery dissection, found no convincing evidence to support a causal link. Further, the authors conclude that the unfounded belief in causation may lead to episodes of litigation.156Church et al. (2016) CureusWhedon et al. in a 2015 cohort study published in Spine Journal found that, “among Medicare beneficiaries aged 66 to 99 years with an office visit for a neuro-musculoskeletal problem, risk of injury to the head, neck, or trunk within 7 days was 76 percent lower among subjects with a chiropractic office visit than among those who saw a primary care physician.”157Whedon et al. (2015) Spine JournalIn a separate 2015 cohort study, Whedon et al. found that “among Medicare B beneficiaries aged 66 to 99 years with neck pain, incidence of vertebrobasilar stroke was extremely low. Small differences in risk between patients who saw a chiropractor and those who saw a primary care physician are probably not clinically significant.”158Whedon et al. (2015) Journal of Manipulative andPhysiological TherapeuticsThe results of a case-control study in U.S. commercial and Medicare Advantage patient populations by Kosloff et al. concluded, “We found no significant association between exposure to chiropractic care and the risk of vertebrobasilar artery (VBA) stroke. We conclude that manipulation is an unlikely cause of VBA stroke. The positive association between primary care provider (PCP) visits and VBA stroke is most likely due to patient decisions to seek care for the symptoms (headache and neck pain) of arterial dissection. We further conclude that using chiropractic visits as a measure of exposure to manipulation may result in unreliable estimates of the strength of association with the occurrence of VBA stroke.”159Kosloff et al. (2015) Chiropractic Manual TherapyIn a 2008 population-based, case-control and case-crossover study published in Spine Journal, Cassidy et al. concluded that “Vertebrobasilar Artery (VBA) stroke is a very rare event in the population. The increased risks of VBA artery stroke associated with chiropractic and primary care medical provider visits is likely due to patients with headache and neck pain from vertebrobasilar artery dissection seeking care before their stroke.”The authors found no evidence of excess risk of VBA stroke associated chiropractic care compared to primary care.160Cassidy et al. (2008) Spine JournalJason, I hope this helps to clear up any doubts that you have concerning the safety of chiropractic. With the current events concerning the opioid situation, Harvard and Yale are recommending chiropractic as the first place to go for pain. If the stroke issue had any validity to it, our malpractice insurance rates would be 10x higher. The insurance company actuarial stats don’t lie. Cheers"}
{"_id": "8316a4d2", "question": "Can teenagers get a stroke?", "answers": "There are many causes of stroke in children , teenagers and adolescents… For example a child with congenital heart defect (VSD, TGA etc) is more likely to develop thromboembolism causing stroke… a child having hypercoagulable states like protein C, protein S deficiency has the tendency to get blood clots (thromboembolism) causing stroke… there are many other causes like angiopathy, sickle cell disease, moya moya, infantile hemiplegia etc which may be responsible for stroke.. a child with glomerulonephritis may develop severe hypertension and if not controlled then may cause hemorrhagic stroke… a child with renal artery stenosis may have severe hypertension and stroke… a child with severe dehydration may get venous sinus thrombosis and stroke… There are many causes."}
{"_id": "6c91d416", "question": "What is a two stroke engine?", "answers": "The below information could be found in this link with Images and animations also : How does two\nstroke\nengine works ?\nThe 2 stroke engine is a type of Internal combustion engine where one power cycle is completed with two strokes of the piston during only one rotation of crankshaft.\nThe 2 stroke engine performs all the same steps which are performed by 4 stroke engine i.e intake stroke, compression stroke, power stroke & exhaust stroke; but the 2 stroke engine performs all the 4 process(stroke) in only 2 stroke.\nThe first commercial two-stroke engine involving in-cylinder compression is attributed to Scottish engineer Dugald Clerk, who patented his design in 1881\nApplication : Two-stroke engines are generally less expensive to build compared to four-stroke engines, and they are lighter and can produce a higher power-to-weight ratio. For these reasons, two-stroke engines are ideal in applications such as chainsaws, weed trimmers, outboard motors, off-road and motorcycles.Two-stroke engines are also easier to start in cold temperatures, making them ideal for use in snowmobiles\nComponents of two stroke engine\nMain Components of Two stroke engine :\nSpark plug : A spark plug delivers electric current to the combustion chamber which ignites fuel.The spark produced is used to burn the fuel in the cylinder.\nPiston : Piston is the reciprocating part of the engine. It is used for transferring the energy of the expansion of gases to crankshaft using connecting rods\nConnecting rod : It connects the piston and crankshaft. It transfer the power from the piston to the crankshaft.\nCrank case : It acts as the base of the engine. It supports the crankshaft and camshaft in suitable bearings and provides the arms for supporting the engine on the frame.\nCrank shaft : It is that part of the engine which is used to convert the reciprocating motion of the engine into the rotating motion with the help of a connecting rod.\nInlet port & Exhaust port : The fresh charge enters into the cylinder through inlet port and transfer the burnt gases out of the engine through exhaust port.\nCounterweight : Counterweight on crankshaft are used to reduce the vibrations due to imbalances in the rotating assembly\nCounterweight are used to prevent bending of crankshaft by offsetting the weights of rod and pistons. For a crankshaft to be balanced, at any point in the assembly’s rotation, the sum of all of the forces are roughly equal to zero. If the crankshaft is not balanced, it will deform especially at pressure points and eventually fail.\nIn two stroke engines, there is no suction and exhaust strokes. There are only two remaining strokes the compression stroke and power stroke. These are usually called the upward stroke and downward stroke. Also, instead of valves, there are inlet and exhaust ports in two stroke cycle engines.\nWorking principle of two stroke engine is explained in as shown in diagram below :\n1. Upward Stroke\n2. Downward Stroke\n1. Upward stroke:\nDuring upward stroke, the piston moves from BDC to TDC and compresses the charge (air-fuel mixture) in the combustion chamber of the cylinder.\nBecause of the upward movement of the piston a partial vacuum is created in the crankcase and this allows the entry of the fresh charge into the crankcase through uncovered inlet port.\nThe exhaust port and the inlet port remains covered when the piston at the TDC.\nThe ignition of the fresh charge is takes place by the spark plug.\n2. Downward stroke:\nAs soon as the combustion of the fresh charge takes place, a large amount of the pressure created due to combustion of fuel exerts a very high pressure force on the top of the piston. Due to this high pressure force, the piston moves downward and rotates the crankshaft\nDuring this stroke the inlet port is covered by the piston and the new charge is compressed in the crankcase.\nFurther downward movement of the piston uncovers first the exhaust port and the transfer port and the exhaust starts through the exhaust port.\nAs soon as the transfer port opens, the charge through it is forced into the cylinder.\nThe charge strikes the deflector on the piston crown, rises to the top of the cylinder and pushes out most of the exhaust gases.\nThe piston is now at BDC position. The cylinder is completely filled with the fresh charge but it is somewhat diluted with the exhaust gases.\nFinally the cycle event is then repeated. We get two strokes for the single revolution of the crankshaft."}
{"_id": "cf3a9fdd", "question": "What is the best swimming stroke/exercise for your core?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6bf41eae", "question": "What happens if we use water instead of diesel and petrol in two stroke and four stroke engines?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ce163b41", "question": "What is the best swimming stroke to build muscle?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "34e96440", "question": "What is the best hospital for stroke treatment in India?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7bff7f38", "question": "Why are motor neurons most often affected during a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b9aa84d8", "question": "Which is the most difficult stroke in swimming?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "58b57424", "question": "Since every downstroke is a power stroke on a 2 stroke engine, then does that mean they are twice as powerful as a 4 stroke and would need half the cylinders to give the same amount of power?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f6ea4245", "question": "Has anyone made a one-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4f22a885", "question": "Does any manufacturer produce 2-stroke bikes currently?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5501cf02", "question": "What kind of oil can I use on a two stroke go-kart engine? Can I use 2 stroke motorcycle engine oil on 2 stroke karting engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f702ba4c", "question": "Why is thermal efficiency greater in a 4-stroke compared to a 2-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ac5648e7", "question": "How long does it take for a blood pressure of 140/90 to cause a heart attack or stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1afb16a5", "question": "Why are the piston rings of a 2-stroke engine chamfered but not for a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "95af611c", "question": "Why in Chinese is the stroke's order important? Is it a huge mistake to write a stroke by not following any order?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7af3252c", "question": "What's the better outboard, 2 stroke or 4 stroke gas engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9651e203", "question": "What is silent stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "84d6dbb6", "question": "Do snakes enjoy being petted/stroked?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "30bd6754", "question": "What is the best political master stroke by Modi?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a74da207", "question": "Why can smoking cause a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4e3edb95", "question": "Are 8 cylinder engines 4-stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1b671f72", "question": "In a four-stroke cycle, does the minimum temperature inside the engine cylinder occur at the beginning of the suction stroke or the end of the suction stroke?", "answers": "Because you have your intake cycle immediately after your combustion cycle, the cylinder head (internal) and valves are hotter now than at any other moment after the ignition flash.\nThe piston has just pushed out the hot exhaust gasses, which although less hot than the initial flaming of the air fuel mix are leaving a lot of their heat in the wall and head of the chamber, your engine is now, at inlet valve opening, sucking in “cold” air fuel mix, which has an immediate cooling effect on both the cylinder head and the cylinder wall, and also the piston head. Luckily it does, other wise your engine would melt.\nAt the Begining of the suction stroke, everything is hot, the air fuel mix comes in but has a lot of work to do cooling everything down. By the time it has sucked in a whole cylinder of air, the chamber cylinder temperature will be at its lowest point at the bottom of the cycle, the air fuel mix has been progressivly absorbing the heat as it comes in, as it does so, it expands, filling the cylinder more quickly than is desireable and resisting the in coming air fuel mix. So you will find that despite the suction of the piston as it descends, it is not getting a uniform amount of air coming in throughout the cycle.\nIn a badly set up engine, or one that is suffering from hot cylinders, you might even get the air fuel mixture to auto ignite, causing a “backfire” (more than one reason for backfires)\nSo, I’m pretty confident that you can take the moment of least temperature in the cylinder as being at bottom dead centre, where the air fuel mix has absorbed all of the heat energy from the cylinder that it can.\nThis is not a good thing for the efficiency of the engine, but a good thing for its cooling.\nThanks for the asking."}
{"_id": "9604b8a8", "question": "What is the working principle of a 4-stroke diesel engine?", "answers": "Basically, there are two types of diesel engine types - the Four Stroke and Two\nStroke\n. The 'Diesel Cycle' uses higher Compression-Ratio\n. It was named after German engineer Rudolph Diesel, who invented and developed first Four-Stroke diesel\nengine. The four strokes of the diesel cycle are similar to that of a petrol engine\n. However, the 'Diesel Cycle' considerably defers by the way the fuel system supplies the diesel the engine and ignites it.\nA conventional internal combustion diesel engine works on 'Diesel Cycle'. In the simple diesel engines, an injector\ninjects diesel into the combustion chamber above the piston directly. The 'Compression-Ignition engine' is also another name for the Diesel engine. This is mainly because it burns the diesel\nwith hot and compressed air. The temperature of the air inside the combustion chamber rises to above 400°c to 800°c. This, in turn, ignites the diesel\ninjected into the combustion chamber. Thus, the 'Diesel Cycle' does not use an external mechanism such as a spark-plug to ignite the air-fuel mixture.\nThe Four-Stroke diesel engine works on the following cycle:\n1. Suction Stroke – With pistons moving downwards and the opening of the inlet valve creates the suction of clean air into the cylinders.\nDiesel Suction Stroke\n2. Compression – With the closing of Inlet valve the area above the piston gets closed. The piston moves up resulting in compression of the air in a confined space under higher compression-ratio\n.\nDiesel Compression Stroke\nCombustion Process - At this stage, the injector\nsprays the diesel into the combustion chamber. The rise in temperature of the air caused by its compression; results in instantaneous burning of diesel with an explosion. This causes heat to release which generates expanding forces known as power\n.\nDiesel Engine Combustion\n3. Power Stroke – Furthermore, these forces again push the pistons downwards resulting in their reciprocating motion.\nDiesel Power Stroke\n4. Exhaust Stroke – On their way up, the pistons push the exhaust gases above them thru’ the exhaust valve which opens during the exhaust stroke.\nDiesel Exhaust Stroke\nThis cycle repeats itself until the engine turns off, resulting in the continuance of engine’s running.\n4 Stroke Diesel Engine Animation\nA diesel engine is mainly classified into two types - Indirect-Injection\n(IDI) & Direct-injection\n(DI). The Direct-Injection\ndiesel\ncycle was an earlier generation technology. It later evolved into its successor & more advanced CRDi\n. Earlier generation utility vehicles, trucks, buses & generators still widely use the simple DI\nengines. Furthermore, sophisticated & refined CRDi\nengines became very popular in the Sedans, MPVs, SUV\ns and Luxury cars in the recent past."}
{"_id": "2b4e28af", "question": "Many doctors urge you to take your blood pressure medications to prevent a stroke, but new studies seem to indicate that blood pressure pharmaceuticals cannot prevent a stroke but can even induce strokes. What are we to believe?", "answers": "Excellent question!\nOkay, lets unpack this a bit because your conclusion is based on a very common mistake laypersons make when interpreting scientific data.\nYou didn’t provide a link to your source info. But, the data I believe you’re referring to comes from the Reasons for Geographic and Racial Differences in Stroke (REGARDS) study from 2015 that came out of the University of Alabama at Birmingham (UAB).\nThe study included a cohort of 26,785 black and white patients with hypertension, aged at least 45 years old, who were followed over a period of 6.3 years. At the start of the study, 12,327 participants had blood pressure successfully treated by anti-hypertensives (SBP < 140 mmHg) and 4,090 participants unsuccessfully treated with anti-hypertensives (SBP > 140 mmHg). At the end of the follow-up period, over 820 participants experienced a stroke.\nHere’s where you’re getting confused…\nAccording to the data, the risk of stroke went up by 33% with each blood pressure medication required to treat blood pressure to goal.\nAfter reading this sentence, it might be natural to think:\nPeople who took more medicine had more strokes. So, the additional blood pressure medications caused the stroke!?\nIf you thought that, you’d be wrong.\nThe medicines didn’t cause the stroke.\nThe severity of hypertensive disease is what contributed to increased stroke risk.\nAnd because more severe hypertension is associated with more medicines required to treat the disease, we see that people taking more medicines had more strokes.\nWe know this because, if those patients had not received those medicines for hypertension, their risk of stroke would have gone up astronomically. This indicates that the degree of good hypertension control is what mediates stroke risk, not the medicine itself.\nWe could also show this by giving these anti-hypertensive medicines to people without severe hypertension and observing that stroke risk does not increase in the absence of severe hypertension. However, this would be unethical as giving anti-hypertensives to people with normal blood pressure would result in an unsafe drop in blood pressure.\nUltimately, your best protection against a stroke is to keep from having high blood pressure in the first place. And, if you do develop high blood pressure, you can reduce your stroke risk with a combination of medicine and lifestyle changes to make sure your hypertension doesn’t become more severe.\nTL;DR\nThe REGARDS study out of University of Alabama showed that the more medicines you need to control your blood pressure, the higher your risk of stroke.\nFrom this data, it is easy to mistakenly conclude that the medicines caused the stroke. This is incorrect.\nStrokes are caused by high blood pressure, not by the medicines that treat high blood pressure.\nWe know this because patients who do not receive anti-hypertensive medicines to control their high blood pressure have astronomical stroke risk. Why? Because they would have crazy high blood pressure.\nTherefore, it only appears that hypertensive medicines increase stroke risk because people with more severe hypertension take more of these meds. In reality, the mediating factor is hypertension severity.\nIf you want to prevent stroke, you need to prevent high blood pressure."}
{"_id": "64acc0c8", "question": "Which engines are more powerful, 2 stroke or 4 stroke?", "answers": "For the same displacement, a 2-stroke has twice the max HP to a 1st approximation. A bit less since less efficient combustion. There is not a clean separation between the exhaust and intake air-fuel mixture like in a 4-stroke. They also may not be able to run quite as high rpm (HP = torque x rpm). Before they became illegal due to emissions regulations, there were some hot 2-stroke motorcycles. The Yamaha 350 2 cylinder was termed a “pocket rocket” by one magazine the last year it was sold (1974?). Two guys at my engineering college had Kawasaki 750 3 cyl bikes. The engine looked tiny since no overhead valve hardware, more like an old flat-head engine. One could kill themselves fast on those bikes.\nThe main problem operating a 2-stroke is that they only run well above a certain speed, say 1500 rpm. That has to do with how the intake air-gas must flow to push the exhaust out the ports (termed “scavenge”). Owners would have to constantly rev the engine at a stop light to keep from dying. One also had to rev the engine and feather the clutch when taking off, which causes more wear. Unlike a H-D 4-stroke where you let out the clutch and just twist the throttle to get all the torque you want. Even long ago in off-road motorcycles, 4-strokes were used when low-end torque was needed for slow crawling, like in “Trials” competitions (woodland paths over logs, more popular in Europe)."}
{"_id": "0619ee1d", "question": "What are the advantages and disadvantages of four strokes?", "answers": "Advantages compared to a two stroke engine:\nFar better fuel economy\nalmost no oil consumption\nFar better emissions\nHigher reliability in thermally difficult situations\nDisadvantages:\nfar more complex to manufacture\nworse weight to power ratio\nless smooth operation, because each cylinder fires only every second revolution\nrequires frequent oil changes\nThe main drawback of the two stroke engine is the principle of blowing exhaust gas out of the cylinder by pressing fresh air-petrol gas into the cylinder. This always causes losses. So, somewhere in the 1960’s this concept was widely put down. 4 stroke engines have seen an enormous technological development sine then. Maybe you could make a good 2 stroke engine if you really used the technology of today."}
{"_id": "db6f3d70", "question": "Do vegetarians have a higher risk of stroke than meat eaters?", "answers": "If you read the article, and the study upon which the article is based, you will easily be able to answer this question for yourself.\nThe article NEVER states that vegetarians are at a higher risk of stroke. It states that people with severe deficiencies in certain essential nutrients are at higher risk of stroke. Chief among these being B12 complex, and even then, neither the article nor the study explicitly state that B12 deficiency is the CAUSE of this increased risk.\nI am a vegan, and I take B12 supplements because the vegan diet does not naturally contain B12. Anyone that tries to make huge dietary changes with zero prior research, is an idiot. You will get sick, and you will feel like garbage. If you go vegan or try any other non omnivorous lifestyle, you must take supplements, period."}
{"_id": "63abdde9", "question": "Can someone recover completely from a stroke? If yes, how long does it take for a person to recover from a stroke?", "answers": "That is an impossible question to answer. Each stroke is different and in a room full of 100 stroke victims, no two strokes will have been the same. How much of the brain died? Where exactly did the brain cells die? Strokes aren’t a hit and it’s over. A stroke continues for 24–48 hours with more brain cells dying every minute.\nI had a major ischemic stroke. My right side was totally paralyzed head to foot and my speech was gone. Despite the years of therapy, I have not had a complete recovery. I recovered my speech after some time and with speech therapy, it’s not the same as before. But! I’m so glad I have it! I had occupational and physical therapy in the hospital for six weeks then at home 6 days/week for most of the year. Therapy is ongoing, for me, for the rest of my life. So recoveries are all different too. But therapy is forever. Or you can lose some of your past gains.\nSo the question asks about a complete recovery but with no details of the initial damage and losses or the kind of therapy and whether it was begun immediately. No one can give you the kind of answer you are looking for. Hasn’t the doctor discussed the prognosis with you? He alone would have the information needed for that assessment.\nI wish you or the patient the best of luck!"}
{"_id": "4d4825d0", "question": "If I saw a wild tiger or lion, would it attack me if I tried to stroke it?", "answers": "Lions are much more social in general than tigers.\nTheir habitats are vastly different.\nTo the lion, you would show up from a much longer distance.\nThe tiger of course you would get fairly close to before you see it, but rest assured it knows where you are coming from. You’re still not likely to surprise a tiger in its own habitat.\nBoth will stare at you, for it is not unusual for either to have a human approach them. At this point in time, your intent to pet is not really relevant.\nYour body language does play a role, and their curiosity may be piqued no matter what you do. If you don’t suddenly get scared and start to run, you may invite an immediate attack. This is purely instinctive.\nThe lion is a little more likely to see what you’re up to. If it is there, it rules there. Same with the tiger, but the tiger is a bit more shy, and might simply want to avoid you, and it can disappear very quickly. If you’re persistent and kept moving towards the lion, at one point, you’re going to cross the threshold of curiosity and step into the threat perception. One roar should be enough to paralyse you. If you do get paralysed, that may be your best chance to get out alive, for the lion may lose interest in you, and move off, a bit annoyed. If you’re not paralysed, the next step or two you take will be the last, no matter in which direction. I would very much doubt the lion is there alone, and there is very little more suicidal than taking on a pack of lionesses.\nWith the tiger, the most important thing, as advised by a tracker who I knew who was killed by a tiger, is to keep your eye contact. It won’t drop its gaze, and it will read your moves. Stare at it, stand still, and you might see it leave after many long minutes, for it may decide this is some unknown non food related intrusion. If it starts coming towards you with that crouching gait, I would bet you will react. One leap - 8 metres. I don’t think you will be in a petting position when it gets to you, paws extended to slap your head.\nPet peeve worth it?"}
{"_id": "34b4a77a", "question": "What are the advantages and disadvantages of a 2-stroke engine?", "answers": "Advantages of 2-Stroke Engines\nTwo stroke engines do not have valves which are easy to construct and lowers their weight\nTwo stroke engines fire once every revolution. Power is produced once during 2 strokes of the piston .This gives a significant power boost.\nThis two stroke engines lower output in horse power\nTwo stroke engines can work in any position, since oil flow is not a concern with any valves to worry about.\n2 stroke engines are lighter comparatively.\nSince the power produced by the two-stroke engine is higher, these engines are small and compact in size.\nThe torque produced on the crankshaft is more uniform because the power is produced during every alternate stroke of the piston.\nThese Engines often provide high power-to-weight ratio, usually in a narrow range of rotational speeds called the “power band”.\nDisadvantages of 2-Stroke Engines\nTwo stroke engines do not last as long as four stroke engines; there is no lubrication system in a two stroke engine so parts wear out a lot faster.\nTwo stroke oil is expensive; you would burn a gallon every 1000 miles if it were in a car\nTwo stroke engines are Less Efficient.\nTwo stroke engines produce a lot of pollution, and the way the engine is designed that part of the air/fuel leaks out of the chamber through the exhaust port.\nThe exhaust gases often get trapped inside the combustion chamber. This makes the fresh charge impure. Therefore maximum power doesn’t get delivered because of improper incomplete combustion.\nSince in two-stroke engines power stroke is produced after every stroke, a large amount of heat is generated within them. To reduce the temperature of the engine and keep the moving parts well-lubricated, good lubrication and cooling systems for the engine are required."}
{"_id": "9be210ce", "question": "What are the remedies for sun stroke?", "answers": "It may usually be apparent to doctors if you have heatstroke, but laboratory tests can confirm the diagnosis, rule out other causes for your symptoms and assess organ damage.\nHeatstroke treatment centers perform tasks on cooling your body to a normal temperature to prevent or reduce damage to your brain and vital organs.\nImmerse you in cold water. A bath of cold or ice water has been proved to be the most effective way of quickly lowering your core body temperature. The quicker you can receive cold water immersion, the less risk of death and organ damage.\nUse evaporation cooling techniques. If cold water immersion is unavailable, health care workers may try to lower your body temperature using an evaporation method. Cool water is misted on your body while warm air is fanned over you, causing the water to evaporate and cool your skin.\nPack you with ice (Never put ice above chest or axillary region, can induce a topical cold arrest of heart (stop the heart) which is not mentioned in their protocol) and cooling blankets. Another method is to wrap you in a special cooling blanket and apply ice packs to your groin, neck, back and armpits to lower your temperature.\nGive you medications to stop your shivering. If treatments to lower your body temperature make you shiver, your doctor may give you a muscle relaxant, such as a benzodiazepine. Shivering increases your body temperature, making treatment less effective.\nHeatstroke - Diagnosis and treatment - Mayo Clinic"}
{"_id": "7a6a5562", "question": "Which is more dangerous, an ischemic or a hemorrhage stroke?", "answers": "All strokes cause brain damage. tPA can reduce damage from ischemic strokes. When I had a stroke, I was taken directly from the ambulance to the CT, where they told me I had a bleed in the brain. No tPA for me.\nI’ve heard that survivors of ischemic stroke who had hemi-paralysis arriving at Emergency, and promptly received tPA then walked out of the hospital a few hours later. Amazing! I couldn’t take a step without falling for weeks. I fell in ER and in ICU. In rehab, I finally understood — alcoholics and addicts in rehab need to accept that they are powerless over their substance. I had to accept that I was powerless over my left side.\nI was shocked to read (months later) that 40%–50% of hemorrhagic strokes are fatal within the first 30 days. The neurologist told my husband and daughter that if I survived the first night, I’d probably be ok. Thank goodness, I didn’t hear that! The neurologist said that blood is toxic to brain cells. The blood-brain barrier is why the brain is “grey matter”, not red. In my stroke, the blood flowed into one of the ventricles, so the damage to my grey matter was limited.\nI’ve read that hemorrhagic stroke is more common in younger people. In this context “young” means under 60. That made me smile — it has been quite a while since anyone said I was young. :)\nExercise almost every day. Don’t smoke. Manage your blood pressure and cholesterol. Avoiding a stroke is far better than surviving any type of stroke."}
{"_id": "585e6011", "question": "Is there a way for a person to fully recover from a stroke?", "answers": "It's going to be according to what was damaged in the brain- what areas and how badly- how soon and how much therapy a person receives, and how able they are to utilize the therapy they receive.\nA stroke can cause massive damage to the brains, killing whole swathes of brain tissue and, generally, neurons don't grow back. ( Page on jneurosci.org\n) So, if the clot or bleed which caused the CVA (cerebral vascular accident) was big, full recovery may be impossible.\nIf both drug and physical/occupational/speech therapies are started immediately, stroke victims can recover a surprising amount of functioning; surprising for the state in which they were brought in to the Emergency Room, anyway. Clot-busting drugs along with blood thinners help to clear away lingering debris in the brain's circulatory system and also keep a good, steady flow of blood, oxygen and nutrients in to the damaged area. That helps tremendously.\nThe therapies mentioned above, though, are less efficacious if the damage is severe. PT, which usually focuses on physical strengthening of an affected body part and overall conditioning, and OT, which focuses on every day tasks and abilities, don't do a person who is completely right-side paralyzed much good until the brain heals a bit from the insult of the stroke. There are improvements, certainly, but until the brain starts re-routing itself around damaged areas, these therapies are mostly a holding pattern. Same with speech therapy, although it is speech, with its emphasis on cognition, which can get the ball really rolling. Real improvement starts to be seen about week 3 post CVA, with continued improvement for about 18 months. After that, a plateau is usually reached, and few people can afford to continue the intensive therapy needed to see further improvement.\nTwo and three years later, there can be little improvement in functional abilities, although strength in musculature can help minimize deficits.\nI'm sorry your friend has had to go through this, and will continue with this disability for the rest of her life. The best thing you can do now is to treat her as a friend, help her when she requests it, and not allow her deficits to cause you to see her as someone to be pitied. No one gains from pity."}
{"_id": "248fbe93", "question": "Could vertigo be a sign of stroke?", "answers": "Isolated vertigo is the most common vertebrobasilar warning symptom before stroke11,44; it is rarely diagnosed correctly as a vascular symptom at first contact. Strokes causing dizziness or vertigo will have limb ataxia or other focal signs. The most common causes of vertigo are inner ear infections or diseases of the ear such as benign paroxysmal positional vertigo (BPPV), vestibular neuritis, and Meniere's disease. BPPV can occur when calcium builds up in canals of the inner ear, causing brief dizziness that lasts from 20 seconds to one minute. Ellen Johnson"}
{"_id": "eaa759ec", "question": "Do stroke survivors die earlier in life than those who haven't suffered a stroke?", "answers": "Usually yes. A stroke is caused by a burst blood vessel or a clot blocking an artery. A stroke may kill someone itself and it does not have to be simply damaging a critical area. The ruptured blood vessel is most commonly caused by high blood pressure but the risk is increased by smoking, diabetes and other issues. Clots can be caused by irregular heart beat atrial fibrillation and narrowing of neck arteries which is in turn caused by the same issues causing heart disease eg smoking, diabetes, high cholesterol. The point to this answer is that the causes of the stroke kill people and need to be addressed. One of my patients - a young lady in her 40’s who is very healthy was developing a massive stroke after she had a chiropractic treatment of her neck. Fortunately someone else - not the chiro- spotted it and took her to hospital where she received clot busting drugs that probably saved her life and certainly stopped a stroke which was already affecting her speech, and paralyzed the entire left side. She has fully recovered."}
{"_id": "3de61d6f", "question": "Do most people that have strokes lose the languages they've learned?", "answers": "OK, this will have to be broken down much more than in the question.\nMost people do not have strokes.\nIf you have a stroke, then some brain function is usually lost. But the rest of the brain still functions as usual. Much of the brain is simply motor control—control of your muscles—and this is a much more common problem than language problems after a stroke.\nBrain function does not relate directly to specific knowledge. You will never have a stroke that specifically deleted everything you learned at age 13, or that deleted everything you know about history. (Unless it is so severe that all memory function is affected.)\nIf the brain function you lose is in the areas of the brain that process language, you might lose some language function. You might lose the ability to read, you might lose the ability to name persons (but not to recognise them; this happened to a neighbour of mine who knew very well who I was, and could hold quite coherent conversations about something in our past, but could never recall my name), you might lose the connection between colours and the words for them. You might lose a second language, but you might also lose your first language, while retaining the second language. And a very rare condition is that you suddenly start speaking your first language with a heavy, foreign accent\n. The brain really does work in so strange ways that you cannot predict what will happen.\nIf you have lost knowledge because the corresponding brain circuits are destroyed, you might or might not be able to learn the skills again. If your stroke gives you instant and complete dyslexia, you are unlikely to recover. My neighbour learned the names of his family again, probably by some sort of mnemonics, possibly subconscious. You might have to learn your second language from scratch, but if your first language is unaffected, this will most likely be possible for you.\nYou will have no fundamental difficulties learning anything else, unless the stroke was so large that your short-term or long-term memory is severely affected. (In rare cases, the connection between short-term and long-term memory is destroyed completely, and the victim will not even be able to realise that time passes\n. This might be what you refer to when you say “never learn anything again”. But this is rare.) You can lose a second language and still be able to learn to ride a bicycle, or ancient history. Although in these cases, you have probably also lost motor function, and regaining that will usually be your first priority."}
{"_id": "6aaaf35b", "question": "What is the possibility that President Trump will have a heart attack, stroke or other disabling ailment before his current term expires?", "answers": "As a nurse with 30 years’ experience, and having heard so much about his food preferences, complete lack of knowledge about human physiology, his own strange beliefs about health, lack of exercise, sedentary life, and hair trigger temper, I know there’s no reason he SHOULD be alive now.\nHis doctor admitted falsifying the information from his physical, from his weight to his b/p, etc.\nHe clearly appears to be obese, almost certainly has substantial hypertension, probably some fairly advanced cardiac disorder, pre-diabetic and high cholesterol.\nHis favorite foods are giant cheeseburgers, oversized french fries, and ice cream sundaes in amounts almost anyone would find staggering.\nFor those of you who come from cultures where a healthy digestive system is seen to be the key to health (Italians, Indians…others too many to mention) do you think this guy is constipated?\nBeing constipated goes beyond the present discomfort of having old, rock hard food lodged in your intestines. Many people die while straining to have a BM. Most are already in the same condition he is, and the strain of trying to move the mass can cause a stroke or fatal MI. Remember Trump’s pal, Roger Ailes, who believed he, too, as head of Fox “news”thought health guidelines didn’t apply to him? Or even poor Elvis?\nHe believes humans are only allotted so many heartbeats per lifetime, which is why he says he doesn’t exercise.\nThere’s no reason he shouldn’t have had some serious health problems already. We all know how it is, though. Your friend who never smoked gets lung cancer at 35 and dies at 36. Smoking, drinking, obese people with the world’s worst diet sometimes will live to be 85.\nIt’s hard to say, since he already has so many risk factors in place, yet nothing’s happened (that we know of). He’s just a physiological time bomb waiting to explode."}
{"_id": "4a8f78f8", "question": "Why must a two stroke engine always have an intake pressure boost?", "answers": "Because a 2 cycle engine takes in air at the bottom of the stroke, there is little to no vacuum to draw air in.\nLarge 2 cycle diesels use a blower (supercharger) or turbocharger, or both, to force air into the cylinder during the short time the ports are open in the cylinder.\nSmall 2 stroke engines usually take in the fuel/air mixture through the crankcase. When the cylinder comes down, it pressurizes the mixture in the crankcase because the reed valve between the crankcase and the carburetor closes with the pressure. The pressure in the crankcase forces the mixture through the intake port in the base of the cylinder.\nSo both engines use pressure to charge the cylinder, one uses the small amount of pressure in the crankcase, the other uses more pressure from a mechanical blower."}
{"_id": "d89e65f8", "question": "Why are two strokes engines with direct injection not used in cars, since they're more efficient than four strokes engine?", "answers": "Your basic premise of the question is incorrect. 2-strokes are NOT more efficient than 4-strokes counterparts in burning fuel for every unit of power production.\nThe reason for this lies into the higher overlap a 2-stroke engine has in each working phase of an IC engine - particularly the exhaust and intake phases.\nIf you are talking about spatial efficiency, it's not a concern as performance bottleneck is usually the tire grip rather than engine power.\nQuestion as answered…\nWhy two strokes engines with direct injection are not used in cars, since they're more efficient than four strokes engine?"}
{"_id": "520bab54", "question": "What is the difference between a 4 stroke engine and a 4 cylinder engine?", "answers": "Don't confuse the two things with 4 as a figure\nLet's start from scratch at utter novice level. Some may find my answer absurd.\nConsider you have a cylinder , A cylinder is geometrical figure that is obtained from a rectangle by rolling in a way that one of the parallel edges meet the other.\nIn a cylinder we have a piston.\nConsider something like plunger, a rod having a circle at top\nThis Piston fits into the cylinder, just like legs in slim fit jeans.\nThis piston moves up and down in a cylinder from the top to bottom and vice versa.\nThe Top to bottom and bottom to Top movement makes it one stroke.\nTherefore, strokes occur in a cylinder.\n\nIn a 4 stroke engine, it takes 4 strokes or 4 top to bottom and bottom to top movements to complete a combustion process.\nA 4 cylinder engine is nothing but 4 different cylinders used for combustion.\nThese four cylinders have piston which does 4 stroke to complete a combustion."}
{"_id": "ca3b31c8", "question": "Was the Oprah interview a fatal mistake for Harry and Meghan or a stroke of genius?", "answers": "In my opinion and observations…….Three weeks later………what the world has “learned”……..\nAfter 25 seasons being a talk show host, Oprah Winfrey “choose” to use her position and influences to produce an orchestrated assault on the Royal Family. It was promoted to have some newsworthy oversight, it did not. It was an Entertainment piece, fiction or fictional? Truth or lies? Depends who is talking and asking…shame on you Oprah!\nMeghan Markle, may very well be a sociopath and in need of mental illness intervention. Where is Harry and Doria? Think she has trashed the rest of “her” family beyond recognition. Markles who??\nHarry feels freed, good for him! such a damaged soul he appears to be. Family counseling is available 24/7…….thank goodness you had 7 years of organizing and finding outlets for your mental health therapy, thank your brother and sister in law. #headstogether. Good Luck with your néw walking papers and agreements, try to stay at least upright while awake.\nThe Cambridge’s are beyond amazing! The lights are on at the end of the tunnel, they are helping their fellow countrymen and women feel hopeful and positive. Supporting and bringing joy to both their parents and grandparents…..yep, that is HMTQ and Prince Philip. Thank you for all you both do, you both will be remembered and appreciated for your selfless and dedicated services. Thank your from beyond the pond.\nThe main stream medias are trying to position everyone to be jealous or envious of another’s successes or struggles. This is not based on color, sex or heritage………it is nothing more than class warfare and manipulating discourse among all of us. Money, greed and power, or taking away power or standing. Take your pick.\nLook how much social media has control over our time! Here I am commenting on two people I have never met, defending a Royal Family I have only watched and loved from 6000 miles away. Maybe we all are a bit crazy! :) God Bless, stay well!"}
{"_id": "ff406a7e", "question": "How is it possible that brain damage sometimes makes the brain better, like after a stroke or something he suddenly is gifted in music or math?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b474aeeb", "question": "Why can one never recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d1f36a5c", "question": "Difference between two stroke petrol and two stroke diesel engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d8fd839c", "question": "What is 2 stroke or 4 stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7012acea", "question": "What are the most promising directions in the prevention and treatment of strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b363b90a", "question": "Why do most cars run on a 4-stroke engine rather than a 2-strokes engine while motorcycles run on a 2-strokes engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7413d0b5", "question": "How does a typical four-stroke, spark-ignition, car engine work?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4419f5da", "question": "What would happen if you used 4 stroke engine oil in a 2 stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e7bc496d", "question": "Do Quora users use Quora primarily because it strokes their intellectual egos?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0f8ba289", "question": "How can you pretty much eliminate brush strokes with acrylic paint on canvas?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9f5cc723", "question": "What does it mean if a man looks more like his mother, than his father?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e9a4cff1", "question": "What is the advantage of a six stroke engine over a four stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7fb0de26", "question": "What does it mean when a guy gently strokes your cheek while you are looking away?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3606a185", "question": "I took a shower after 22:00, which is very harmful and can cause a stroke or harm your lungs. Now I feel tired and a bit hot inside. What should I do now?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bdf6c541", "question": "Can I temporarily run my car on 'two stroke' fuel?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9f0dfbb4", "question": "What are the signs of strokes in women?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6e29921e", "question": "What causes heart attacks and strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "36b27cd3", "question": "How does the brain repair/rewire itself after a stroke or traumatic brain injury?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0cbc1da3", "question": "What are constructional differences between 2 stroke and 4 stroke engines?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c378d835", "question": "What is a master stroke to clear the CGL Mains 2017?", "answers": "Master stroke (a very strong word)\nIs defined as :\nIt means “ a final clever act /skill that result into success”.\nSeveral factors can be considered as Master Stroke for CGL tier 2.\nPractice\nWe don't have any alternative to this .\nSSC CGL Tier 2 is entirely based on Practice , so Practice as much as you can in remaining time and try to cover the entire Syllabus. Desperate Practice [1] will embrace your speed . (See in footnote link below)\nPractice previous years question papers in stipulated time frame and work on your weak points.\nAccuracy -\nThis thing also play a crucial role in getting extra marks .Never tick an answer of Question which you are not sure of (atleast 51% sure).You may have done this mistake several times.This mistake reduce your fair chance to clear the examination.\nNow comes the Master Stroke part:\n(I think, most of us ignore this part)\nTreat yourself as a human being.\nYou may be aiming for 24hour study plan.Please ignore this reckless numbers (15 hours ,12 hours …).Focus on Quality study hours.\nYou should take Regular break between Study hours and enjoy some snacks and fresh air .It will keep your brain working.\nDrink plenty of water . It will keep you hydrated and motivated within.\nBe active physically with some short exercise And Sleep well.\nAnd\nKeep yourself Motivated\nAlways focus on brighter side .\nWith Best wishes\nRajeev Kumar\nFootnotes\n[1] Practice Won't Make Perfect, But Deliberate Practice ..."}
{"_id": "9aeffd39", "question": "Can chiropractic adjustments induce stroke?", "answers": "I don’t know where the other two answers got their information, other than perhaps anecdotally. The FACTS are that the likelihood of a person having a stroke in a chiropractor’s office are no greater than having one in a medical doctor’s office. A Review of the Literature Regarding\nStroke\nand Chiropractic\nThe myth that chiropractors cause strokes is (1) based upon a misunderstanding of the difference between correlation and causation, and (2) by the American Medical Association’s organized effort to destroy an honorable profession whose philosophy is to avoid drugs and surgery by finding and correcting the underlying cause of a health issue. (The latter was validated by a Federal Court finding the AMA guilty of those charges.)\nLook, the malpractice insurance premiums paid by chiropractors to insurance companies is orders of magnitude less expensive than premiums paid by medical doctors. Do you think those companies are just being nice, or is it more likely that more people are hurt and/or die in the hands of medical doctors? How do the critics explain that???\nThe elephant in the room is a recent study by John Hopkins University which concluded that on average 250,000 people die EVERY YEAR IN THE USA due to “iatrogenic causes,” meaning incorrect medical diagnosis or treatment. QUOTE: “ Analyzing medical death rate data over an eight-year period, Johns Hopkins patient safety experts have calculated that more than 250,000 deaths per year are due to medical error in the U.S. Their figure, published May 3 in The BMJ, surpasses the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's third leading cause of death—respiratory disease, which kills close to 150,000 people per year.” Johns Hopkins study suggests medical errors are third-leading cause of death in U.S.\nAnd yet, if even one person dies while receiving chiropractic treatment (which is not the same as being CAUSED by chiropractic treatment) it’s front page news.\nOpen your eyes people. Health, in many cases, comes from identifying and correcting the underlying cause of disease not from a bottle of pills or removal of organs."}
{"_id": "84817912", "question": "Who is the most stylish cricketer ever? By stylish, I mean his batting stance, gait, strokes, etc. Are there bowlers who are acclaimed for style?", "answers": "Cricinfo\nHis batting is based on the purest principles: perfect balance, economy of movement, precision in stroke-making, and that intangible quality given only to geniuses - anticipation. If he doesn't have a signature stroke - the upright, back-foot punch comes close - it is because he is equally proficient at each of the full range of orthodox shots (and plenty of improvised ones as well) and can pull them out at will.\nQuotes\n\"Sachin is Picaso among batsman\" ~ Greg Chapell\n\"First and foremost, Tendulkar is an entertainer and that for me is as important factor as any fact or figure. Too often boring players have been pushed forward as great by figures alone. For sheer entertainment, he will keep cricket alive.\" ~ Barru Richards\n\"You might pitch a ball on the off stump and think you have bowled a good ball and he walks across and hits it for two behind mid wicket. His bat looks so heavy but he just waves it around like it's a toothpick.\" ~ Brett Lee\n\"For Sachin the balance is there. He is quick to complete his shot. He covers the crease much better than mere mortals.\" ~ David Gower\n\"In terms of technique and compactness, Tendulkar is the best.\" ~ Desmond Haynes\n\"Technically, you can't fault Sachin. Seam or spin, fast or slow nothing is a problem.\" ~ Boycott\n\"I'd like to see him go out one day and bat with a stump. I tell you he'd do OK…. I just get the feeling because of his mental strength that Sachin will be definitely the best player of his era and probably the best 2-3 of all time.\" ~ Gregg Chapell\n\"For every ball Sachin has two shots in his mind. And he gets out when he plays the third one.\" ~ Harsha Bhogle\n\"I had to remind Gary Kristen often that he was in the covers to field against Sachin not to applaud him.\" ~ Hansie Cronje\n\"The shot played on this ball is only possible for the GOD of cricket.\" ~ Martin Crowe\n\n\nMan who can smash sixes over the head of Mcgrath or Warne\n\nMan who can survive against Steyn and company for one full day in test macth and score a brilliant century when other batsmen keep falling like pack of cards(South Africa v India, Cape Town\n, Steyn, Tendulkar star on intense day\n)\nMan who has every shot mentioned in the Cricketing manual and can play them with super grace and perfection.\n\n\n********************************************************************************************\n\n********************************************************************************************\n\n********************************************************************************************\n********************************************************************************************\n\n********************************************************************************************"}
{"_id": "9ffa4f84", "question": "Why would President Trump lie about having a stroke?", "answers": "For the same reason he wears a girdle and elevator shoes. It’s the same reason he told his doctor to sign a letter proclaiming him “the healthiest” person who would ever be president. It’s the same reason he refuses to wear a mask (which would smear his makeup) or a walk in the rain without an umbrella (which would flatten his comb-over). President Trump is obsessed with looking good in public. To the point where his efforts become ridiculous, and he either doesn’t realize it, or doesn’t care.\nI don’t want to try and diagnose Trump’s emotional state from afar, but everything we know about him suggests that he was raised in an environment in which project an image of power and control was inherent, and showing any sign of weakness was swiftly either punished or used against you. It’s clear that he sees that as the proper structure of the world: a constant battle, and anyone who you can take out must have deserved it. And that’s not an accusation, as much as an observation: he’s said as much about both his businesses and his administration: he likes to pit people against one another and see who comes out on top,\nFor that reason, he has a constant and pathological need to pretend that he’s smarter, stronger, more informed, even taller than he is. You see that in his constant self-aggrandizing lies and assertions, you see that in the way he dresses and grooms and presents himself, you see it in the constant attempts to display dominance over other people.\nThe reality of his aging and ill health isn’t just an unfortunate fact of life, to someone like Trump. It’s a failure that he has to keep under wraps, because he assumes it will be used against him (that is, after all, exactly what he would do to anyone else who had ill health). And so he does what he always does: he lies, he denies, he deflects, he makes up ridiculous and obviously false stories. And most people see right through all of that, but to some core who want to believe in him, well, they can believe just about anything. So, if President says he just decided to, on whim, to put together a motorcade and pop ’round for an unscheduled visit to the hospital, because he felt like getting a jump on his annual physical, well, that’s good enough for me! And if he then, unprompted, starts tweeting that he definitely did not have a series of minor strokes, well, what more do you want? He said “not”!"}
{"_id": "a7254c12", "question": "How important is the Kanji stroke order?", "answers": "That depends… to some students who are learning Japanese especially Kanji, memorizing the stroke order(s) helps on memorizing the characters itself.\nHowever, you also have to include the student’s ethnic background as well such as students who are Chinese that knows their written language since Kanji is “Chinese Characters”.\nThere are some characters that have different stroke order despite the characters are precise.\n「田」\nChinese (Mandarin): tián\nChinese (Cantonese): tìhn\nSino-Japanese Reading (On’yomi): てん /ten/ OR でん /den/\nNative Japanese Reading (Kun’yomi): た /ta/ [だ /da/ is for Nanori (Name Reading)]\nEnglish: “(rice paddy) field”\nChinese Stroke Order\nJapanese Stroke Order\n「王」\nChinese (Mandarin): wáng\nChinese (Cantonese): wòhng\nSino-Japanese Reading (On’yomi): おう /ō/\nNative Japanese Reading (Kun’yomi): おおきみ /ōkimi/ OR きみ /kimi/\nEnglish: “king”; “monarch”\nChinese Stroke Order\nJapanese Stroke Order\n「耳」\nChinese (Mandarin): ěr\nChinese (Cantonese): yíh\nSino-Japanese Reading (On’yomi): じ /ji/ OR に /ni/\nNative Japanese Reading (Kun’yomi): みみ /mimi/ OR のみ /nomi/\nEnglish: “ear”\nChinese Stroke Order\nJapanese Stroke Order\nOverall, I think it is important but at the same time when putting ethnic groups, it’s honestly “controversial” since many have different ways to write them, as long as it is presentable to read, I would agree that it really wouldn’t make any difference (having my own freestyle stroke order which many of my teachers are able to read my handwriting)."}
{"_id": "49a91fb8", "question": "Was Stalin actually a good person, but strokes destroyed him later?", "answers": "The Western elites despise socialism. The reason is because it threatens their wealth and power. Demonizing political enemies is routinely done. For example, Edward Snowden exposed the vast surveillance state used to spy on Americans by the U.S. government. The surveillance apparatus is colossal. Yet Snowden is vilified in the media as a traitor, a snitch, etc. The same applies to figures like Julian Assange, Chelsea Manning, and other whistleblowers and journalists.\nWithin 40 years, the Soviet Union went from an illiterate, semi-feudal, peasant agrarian economy to defeating the Nazis, becoming the world’s second largest industrial power, electrifying the nation, and by 1958, winning the Space Race, having launched Sputnik, the world’s first artificial satellite.\nThe architect of much of this success was a man known by the name of Joseph Stalin. Because he could not be defeated militarily, he had to be vilified. The West has a very formulaic playbook. Sexual predator, pedophile, mass murderer, or racist. If you are a successful socialist, it isn’t long before you are accused of one or all of these things by the West—falsely.\nEnter, Robert Conquest. Conquest was literally a government propagandist for the British government.[1] Early in his career, he would write propaganda articles and these would be disseminated to the major media outlets.[2] Conquest is the author of the early anti-Stalin and anti-Soviet books dressed up as “historical works.”\nHe wasn’t alone. Goebbels was even more effective. It was his notion to lie about the famine in the Ukraine to instead claim it was deliberately caused by Stalin.[3] It wasn’t. [4] And we have the historical documents to prove it, even though Khrushchev did his best to destroy as much exculpatory evidence helping Stalin as possible. Khrushchev hated Stalin because Khrushchev’s son murdered someone and was on trial. Khrushchev asked Stalin to intervene. But the son was guilty as hell, so Stalin refused. Khrushchev also used Stalin as a scapegoat to consolidate his own power with the older members of the nomenklatura.\nStalin was still “with it” in older age. In fact, he was working to introduce new and younger members of the Party to help refresh the ossified leadership in its ranks. As usual, the seriousness of the threat posed by internal enemies was downplayed as “paranoia” by the Western media. In fact, Stalin was apparently not paranoid enough, considering he was ultimately murdered by Beria, his second in command.[5] You aren’t paranoid if people are actually working to kill you. Stalin also had previously survived many attempts on his life.\nWas he a good person? Yes, he was. He chose socialism because he really believed in it. In fact, he was kicked out of the seminary program he was in for spreading Marxist literature. [6] He believed all people should be truly free.\nHis daughter said he was warmer to her than her mother. He loved deeply. In fact, he was suicidal after his first wife died, such that his friends took his pistol away, for fear he might kill himself.\nHe was a good person. We must look at his life within the context of his time. He grew up and rose to power in the midst of an extremely violent and turbulent time. If you look at the actual historical records, you begin to see the portrait of a man who is far more complex, more warm, and less cartoonishly evil than the Western elites would have us believe.\nToday, Stalin has an approval rating in Russia of 70%. [7]\nWas Joseph Stalin a bad person?\nhttps://www.quora.com/Was-Joseph-Stalin-a-bad-person\nFootnotes\n[1] Robert Conquest - Wikipedia\n[2] Robert Conquest - Wikipedia\n[3] The Holodomor Hoax: Joseph Stalin’s Crime That Never Took Place\n[4] https://newcoldwar.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Tauger-Natural-Disaster-and-Human-Actions-in-the-Soviet-Famine-of-1931-33.pdf?0bbe13&fbclid=IwAR3Ycp_wtlUup8Pei3LnuPB-BGf6MRpiEr7UledZcaZKqGhi1o4x37Z26pw\n[5] New Study Supports Idea Stalin Was Poisoned (Published 2003)\n[6] Early life of Joseph Stalin - Wikipedia\n[7] Record 70 per cent of Russians say Stalin played a positive role in their country's history "}
{"_id": "c91a303d", "question": "Which vehicle has a 6-stroke engine? How does it work?", "answers": "Till now there is no application which uses 6 T engine\nBut i will explain you the working .\nIt will have the common four strokes of the existing engine models i.e Suction,compression,Ignition,Exhaust\nBut at end of the 4 th stroke some of the exhaust gases will be retained cylinder.\nOn 5 th stroke water will be injected into the system .\nDue to high temp that is 200+ C at cylinder from exhaust gases the water will suddenly expand to superheated stage and an force is exerted on the piston .\nThis gives an power stroke and aon next stroke the vapours are sent out through exhaust.\nThis requires large flywheel as the no of idle stroke increases."}
{"_id": "6a63f3fd", "question": "Can you get a stroke from having aortic valve disease?", "answers": "Yes but that depends on what sort of aortic arch “disease” your talking about. If it’s a congenital coarctation malformation,Aortic stenosis, aneurism or aortic stricture it can cause areas of restricted or pooled blood flow. Technically yes anytime you slow dwell time in blood vessels tiny emboli can develop. In the case of the Aorta it can cause emboli to get thrown up the carotid artery and cause strokes (Aka emboli or embolic showers) in the brain. Often if this is discovered it’s highly recommended to take long term anticoagulants. Surgery or minimal invasive procedures are often recommended.\nI want to stress that although concerning, this kind of disease can be well monitored managed and followed up on. You may need to see one or more specialists. Find a good health provider doctor,nurse practitioner or physicians assistant and start with a full health physical H&P (history and physical exam) People can live long relatively healthy lives with Aortic arch problems."}
{"_id": "82d2ba3f", "question": "How does a two stroke petrol engine work?", "answers": "The 2 stroke engine performs the following steps – suction, compression, expansion & exhaust; but the 2 stroke engine performs these all steps in only 2 stroke unlike the 4 stroke engine which completes one power cycle in 4 strokes.\nThe parts which a 2 stroke engine has –\nPiston – In an engine, piston is used to transfer the expanding force of gases to mechanical rotation of crankshaft via a connecting rod. The piston is able to do this because it is secured tightly within cylinder using piston rings to minimize the clearance between cylinder and piston.\nCrankshaft – A crankshaft is a part which is able to convert the reciprocating motion to rotational motion.\nConnecting rod – A connecting rod transfers motion from a piston to crankshaft which acts as a lever arm.\nInlet & Outlet ports – It allows to enter fresh air with fuel & to exit the spent air-fuel mixture from the cylinder.\nSpark Plug – A spark plug delivers electric current to the combustion chamber which ignites the air-fuel mixture leading to abrupt expansion of gas.\nWorking of 2 stroke engine :-\nDown Stroke :- First the piston is moved downside from TDC to BDC to let the fresh air enter into the combustion chamber. The fresh air-fuel mixture gets into the combustion chamber through crankcase. Crankshaft rotation – 180°\nUp Stroke :- Here happens all the magic. The piston is pushed up from BDC to TDC. The fuel-air mixture gets compressed & spark plug ignites the mixture. As the mixture gets expanded, the piston moves down. During up stroke, the inlet port is opened. While this inlet port is opened, the mixture gets sucked inside the crankcase. When the mixture is pushed up into the combustion chamber during the previous up stroke, a partial vacuum is created as no mixture is left behind in the crankcase.This mixture is ready to go into the combustion chamber during down stroke but remains in the crankcase until the piston goes up till TDC. Crankshaft rotation – 360°\nTwo strokes get completed along with one power cycle.\nFrom the 2nd down stroke onwards the exhaust gases get expelled out from one side while a fresh mixture enters into the combustion chamber simultaneously due to partial vacuum created in the combustion chamber after removal of exhaust gases. This is the beauty of the engine. Both things happen at the same time which makes it a 2 stroke engine."}
{"_id": "12133df6", "question": "What vitamins help prevent strokes?", "answers": "Here are a few ideas for you, as well as relative links:\nA natural (preferably food-derived multi-Tocotrienol, type of Vitamin E. Especially one with a larger dose of gamma-tocotrienol - which will also give you some cancer protection as well. Not all vitamin E is the same. Most studies that diss vitamin E only use small doses of the weaker and synthetic, single-type. alpha-tocopherol. You want a high quality one or make sure you’re eating organic, foods rich in a spectrum of natural vitamin E types (eg: Alpha, Beta, Gamma, Delta).\nTaurine: Not a vitamin, but rather a conditionally deficient amino acid in some individuals and a powerful neuroprotective and proven\nfactor in preventing ischemic stroke. It’s actually used by veterinarians to prevent stroke and treat seizures in animals.\nMagnesium - A key mineral most of us are missing and AKA Mother Nature’s muscle relaxer. In fact, Magnesium Taurate (see previous entry) is a popular supplement for those with migraine headaches.\nNAC (N-acetyl cysteine)\n, again, an amino-acid. A daily dose of NAC (N-acetyl cysteine) was found to reduce the incidence of cardiovascular events, including ischemic stroke and heart attack, by 40% compared to placebo in people with end-stage renal failure (a high-risk group).\nFolate (but NOT folic-Acid - a common point of confusion). Specifically L-5-MTHF and 6S-5-MTHF﻿ (such as Quatrefolic [6S]-5-methyltetrahydrofolic acid). Of course, food-sources of Folate are even better.\nFish Oil (Omega 3s)\nFish Oil Drug May Prevent Heart Attack and Strokes in High-Risk Patients\nNOTE: There are some supplements that actually increase the incidence of stroke including calcium supplements. Food calcium is fine, but supplements can be a problem.\nSupplements that decrease the incidence of stroke https://www.consumerlab.com/answers/which-supplements-reduce-the-risk-of-stroke-and-which-increase-it/supplements-stroke/"}
{"_id": "5d970210", "question": "Who plays the best forehand strokes in tennis?", "answers": "I’ll go with Federer’s assessment:\nRoger Federer reckons Rafael Nadal has the best forehand in the world\nThere has never been a forehand like Nadal's, and there never will be.\nWhy?\nBecause like Federer's forehand before it, it really was/is groundbreaking to tennis, in more than one way.\nThrough the combination of a lighter racquet, a tinier grip, polyester string technology, and superior reproducible technique, the usual limits of the forehand were breached by Federer in 2004, and then improved and taken forward by Nadal in 2005, making them two of the most successful players ever, in terms of career prize money.\nHere are the main factors by which Nadal's forehand is groundbreaking:\nTop-spin rate\nNet Clearance\nAngular bounce off the court.\nTechnique and Effect: Nadal, with a tiny, semi-western grip\n, uses all his extending arm's force to send the ball spinning at destructive rates—depending on what he needs in the moment—which bounces off the surface on the other side of the net, so much so that it can reach as high as 6 feet on the opponent's baseline!\nThis combination of power and spin is unrivaled in the sport.\nThere are guys who can hit the ball harder than Nadal, and there are guys who can the spin the ball like him too, but none can get the golden balance of both assets—of spin and power—like he does.\nThis is the reason guys 5 years older than him couldn't beat him (even on a hard court) when he burst onto the scene in 2004, as a 17 year-old.\nThey, simply, hadn't ever dealt with something like this before.\nUntil then, the guy with the best forehand was a certain Roger Federer, who could put around 3000 r.p.m.(an abbreviation for \"revolutions per minute\") on a ball—if he was feeling like toying with an opponent, instead of going for aggressive, flatter shots that finished off the opponent faster.\nYet, his shots never bounced as high as Nadal's, or cleared the net as high as Nadal's, because he usually hit the ball at a different angle and followed through across his shoulder, causing a flatter, faster trajectory.\nWhich is why he is a better fast court player than Nadal.\nFederer used his anomalous topspin from the baseline, when he wasn't red-lining his usually-aggressive style, and won matches even when he wasn't at his \"flattened-out-shot\" best, unruffled in the long rallies, and unmatched from the baseline.\nIn those golden 2004-2007 years, he was the best defender when he needed to be, which is a fact many laymen overlook, because he was later overshadowed in the defensive department by Djokovic, Murray, and Nadal, who took the running-around-and-retrieving aspect a bit further.\nFederer's attacking game at that time, was among the best, if not the best.\nBut when Nadal came onto the scene in 2004, with his even-more-anomalous forehand, which had him hitting the ball at a higher angle, and following through behind his shoulder, in a bolo-whip finish (showing how much more spin he tries to generate), analysts measured one that went up as high as 4900 r.p.m!\nAlso, since his forehand ball looped so high, it was never in danger of clipping the net.\nHere's a graphic showing how much higher Nadal's forehand clears the net than the other top players of his era. Also, it shows the top-spin-rate of the shot in the other column.\nBy around 2007, it was generally accepted that Nadal had taken over Federer as the best defender and best counter-attacker (and best attacker on clay) in modern tennis, just because his forehand ameliorated his game so well.\nNadal's game wasn't based on easy points — since he doesn't possess a powerful serve to achieve that like any of his peers, Federer, Murray, and Djokovic — but rather, on precise placement of a slower slice-serve, and then the ensuing big forehand to extract a weaker reply, giving him free reign to hit more forehands from corner to corner, bullying his opponent—until he unleashes his flattened-out, killing forehand.\nWhen he returns a ball from his opponent, his bouncy, high-looping groundstrokes, that take longer to fly through the court than your average flat groundstroke, gave him the precious time to recover his balance, from his own shot, and allowed him to take their consequent shot with renewed readiness.\nAnd since the opponent's shot was taken with considerable difficulty, considering they had to hit it at an abnormal height, the quality of their reply was never up to their usual standards.\nHence, he had many an opportunity to run around his backhand on an opponent’s weak parry, to hit another forehand, if his opponent wasn't very good at adjusting to the high balls generated by his forehand.\nThe high ball also pushed the opponent backwards, and didn't give them an aggressive position in the rally, and they were left gasping from the effort of keeping up with his punishing multiple-forehand barrage.\nYou'll see him running around his back-hand here, in his gaudy pirate pants:\nFederer's amazing forehand could give you those \"OMG\" moments on the rare occasion, but Nadal's forehand is the ultimate weapon: studiously pegging away on every point, with nary as much effort used, due to his tiny-grip mechanics.\nOstensibly tame and defensive, but subtly sapping the opponents's strength with its topspin, and eventually when he senses the opponent is at a negative position, he lets it out at its wholly-aggressive \"OMG\" ferocity, for the flatter, killing blow (which is shown by the across-the-shoulder followthrough)\nThis process is called 'intuitive physics\" or the ability to construct a point around the part where you can unleash your 'fear' shot, to finish it off.\nThis is a trait he shares with most elite players, especially the ones with the best forehands (The Physics of Federer-Nadal | Big Think\n)\nThough this next video may have nothing to do with constructing a point, it certainly shows the versatility of Nadal with his forehand. He can do it at a sprint, just as effectively, unlike powerful hitters like Berdych and Del Potro, who need more balance to optimize their shots.\nLook at the point at 14:54-15:20.\nAt the end of a long, disappointing 2011 season, in which Djokovic had ripped Nadal’s heart out at the 6 big events they contested that year, this match was one of Nadal's toughest best-of-five clay court matches.\nHe lost the first set 1-6, in front of his home crowd in the Davis Cup final.\nI don't know if you're familiar with Nadal's prowess on clay, but the fans and team-mates watching in the stadium were noticeably stunned into silence that the King of Clay was losing on clay.\nIn this point: Nadal sponges the pressure off 2 powerful groundies from Del Potro, after which the Argentine finds himself hoping he can finish the seemingly-overwhelmed Nadal off on the empty part of the court, with a strategically-placed backhand on Nadal's forehand side.\nBut Nadal wings it, and produces a spectacular, running forehand winner that gives Verdasco (the Spanish team-mate cheering after the point) bittersweet memories of this:\nYeah, OMG.\n(I'm going to start calling Nadal's forehand The Fearhand, like Brad Gilbert does, just because it deserves it.)\nOnce The Fearhand was displayed in all its glory, most opponents just gave up, out of the sheer Sisyphean nature of the task of keeping up with the powerful, high ball he generated. Nadal had deconstructed the great Federer's game by, very simply, directing it towards Federer's weaker backhand, and when he overtook Federer as the best player of the decade, most epically and visibly in 2008, all of them just stopped believing that beating him at peak level was possible—until 2011.\nAlso, like I mentioned somewhere above, in anticipation of the famous Fedfan snobs, it's not like he hits loopy, defensive forehands all the time.\nUnlike his 1990s predecessor Sergi Bruguera (who also could average his forehand at around 3,300 r.p.m), he could adjust the forehand to the hard-courts and grass-courts as well.\nHe's flattened it out when he's needed to, based on the environment, like on those faster lower-bouncing courts at Wimbledon and New York.\nIt was generally accepted that he had evolved into an all-court player by September 2010, when he won the US Open and became the youngest man to win a career slam set, beating Hardcourt G.O.A.T. Novak in the final. After that match, people no longer though of him as just the best defender in tennis, but the top man, who would defeat anyone on any surface if he was 100% fit.\nHere's Nadal practising a few of his aggressive, flat forehands, which he used to win the hard-court Indian Wells 2013, and much more, in his insane 2013 comeback season. (Expert text inserts by a tennis instructor, in an otherwise boring video; Nadal usually hits more flat forehands in practice)\nThe Fearhand is the reason Nadal is Nadal, the great 17-slam wonder—otherwise he would just be another great defensive baseliner like Bruguera, Ferrer, Hewitt or Chang, who could never translate their defensive success into immortality.\nYes, Chang and Hewitt are hall-of-famers, but they haven't dominated tennis as long as their aggressive, top-spinning baseliner cousins, Borg and Nadal. Most tennis masters (like Sampras, Agassi, Federer, Nadal, and Djokovic) have to have a top shot that is both defensive and aggressive and Nadal's forehand is the best you can get, on both aspects of the game, because of its raw power, anomalous top-spin, and net-safety factor.\nNo one could handle it over best-of-five matches until Djokovic's acrobatic two-handed backhand and superior conditioning peaked in 2011, and even then, not so emphatically.\nThe Fearhand was an evolutionary step-up in the sport: it's like possessing Charles Atlas' body for Olympic swimming, at the turn of the 20th Century; like having Ronaldinho's ball-sticking-to-body skills in European club football in the 2000s; like successfully controlling Sachin's heavier bat in the 1990s limited overs cricket era; or, most aptly, like having Sampras' serve on nonclay courts in the 1990s era, and as far as I can see, no man will ever emulate it, out of fear of hurting himself."}
{"_id": "67675279", "question": "Do vegetarians have a higher stroke risk?", "answers": "Cause vegetarians consume more eggs and dairy on average then non vegetarians. Eggs and dairy have more toxic substances in them then i care to mention, but just to name a few: Heme-iron, IGF-1, lactic acid, cholesterol, large amounts of estrogen, salmonella, feces, pus.\nEggs and diary cause heart disease, diabetes, hypertension, cancer and of course strokes too. They thicken your blood, clot your arteries, paralyze your arteries. And cause growths to emerge in your body sometimes, because thats what milk and eggs do, they cause growth."}
{"_id": "728ee948", "question": "What should be the firing orders for maximum efficiency of different engines? Like four stroke, six stroke etc for 4, 8, 12 cylinders", "answers": "You have to understand the principles of Crankshaft designing to realize how and why a particular firing order is determined.\nBy the profile of it,\nFor a 4 cyl, it might appear that Cyl #1 and #4 are firing together and cyl #3 and #2 are firing in the next stroke, but they fire individually (Even though they fire off a single Ignition coil in popular -2003 models)\nA few follow 1-3-4-2 as well\nIn Line L6 again follow a similar profile of 1-5-3-6-2-4\nV6 typically follow 1-2-3-4-5-6\nV8 and further do not adhere to a single thumbs rule.\nThere is a huge variety in firing order. Infact, us mechanics too look up for the firing order for individual vehicles.\nHaving said that, with newer 'Coil on Plug' design on all the later than 2003 makes, it hardly matters what the firing order is. The firing sequence is determined by the ECU and it fires just right. (It even gets additional feed-back from those nasty Heated Oxygen Sensors at exhaust to determine whether the firing is rich or poor)"}
{"_id": "93ad626f", "question": "Which is faster, a 4 cylinder 2 stroke 50hp outboard or a 4 cylinder 4 stroke 50?", "answers": "50 horsepower is 50 horsepower. Horsepower is the amount of work being done.\nThat being said, different engines have different power curves, and one might be \"peakier\" than another. In a car, they might be geared differently, which could affect performance - furthermore, different transmissions have different levels of efficiency at transferring power - so that too will have an affect on performance.\nTorque doesn't particularly matter in terms of performance capability, as long as the engine is geared to use the power band well.\nFor example, if an engine produces 100 lb-ft of torque, maximum, and it does this at 2000 RPMs to make 38 horsepower, if you had another 38 horsepower engine that produced only 50lb-ft of torque at peak power levels, it would do this at 4000 RPMs.\nIn terms of driving a car, the second car would be just as fast as the first, as long as the gearing was equivalent. A transmission acts as a torque multiplier. If your engine is producing 100lb-ft of torque at 2000 RPMs (38HP), and you have a 1:1 transmission, you have 100lb-ft of torque at the wheels (I'm oversimplifying slightly). Compare to the 50lb-ft engine at 4000 RPMs - which also equals 38HP. To acheive the same performance, you would use a 2:1 transmission, which would increase torque output at the wheels, to, you guessed it, 100lb-ft.\nMy previous car had an engine that generated 197 horsepower at 7800RPM. My current car has an engine that generated 210 horsepower at 5000 RPM. It weighs about the same. But there are two huge differences between the two: torque and gearing.\nMy old car made 139lb-ft of torque at 6000 RPMs, whereas my current one makes about 260lb-ft of torque at 2400 RPMs. The new car makes a lot more power than the old one did at lower RPMs (You might have guessed that the old car didn't have a turbocharger and my new one does). So if you compared the old car to the new one at the same RPMs, my new one is far more powerful - indeed, even with different gearing, it is significantly quicker without revving the engine up. But the difference isn't quite as much as the torque numbers indicate.\nMy old car had a transmission that was optimized for the less torquey engine. So, in every day driving, I didn't use the same RPM range I do on the new car. In my new car, I cruise on surface streets around 1400-2000 RPMs, and in traffic, for slightly aggressive acceleration I might hit 3000-3500 RPMs without using full throttle. In my old car, I would shift closer to 5500 RPMs for slightly aggressive acceleration.\nMy new car's engine makes more power - and it makes significantly more power through most of the RPM range. But when I used the old car at its peak performance level, maintaining 6000-8000 RPMs, it was nearly as fast as my current car.\nAs for gearing, second gear in my new car is essentially the same as third gear in my old car - roughly 100 RPMs per MPH. Sixth gear (top gear in both cars), had my old car at 3000 RPMs at 67MPH, and my new car a bit under 2000 RPMs at the same speed. My old engine produced ~120lb-ft of torque at 3000 RPMs, which gave me about 74 horsepower on tap, whereas my new car makes about 200lb-ft of torque at 2000 RPMs, which gives me... 76 horsepower. The old car was juuuuust about the same on the highway if I just leaned on it, in spite of the torque advantage of my new car. But come 2400 RPMs, my new car's output is up to 119HP, whereas my old car was only producing 82HP at 3600 RPM.\nThe biggest real world difference is that I don't need to work my new car as hard as I did the old one to get the same level of performance. The biggest difference? My new car is much quieter than my old one!\nThe torque curve on the different engines, combined with any transmission they are attached to, would dictate the real world performance difference between them.\nLastly, simply stating that because you need to run one engine faster than another does not dictate that it would be more or less reliable than the other option. My new car's engine is reputed to be significantly less reliable than my old car's engine was. Mind you, these are both 4 stroke engines, but they were designed differently and it happens to be that the other car with a more high strung engine actually had the more reliable engine of the two."}
{"_id": "c61428cb", "question": "Can I do back arm shoulder press with a bad disc in my neck?", "answers": "So long as you maintain good strict form and if necessary you provide external support to avoid further injury. Make sure to take care of sensitive areas and build strength in surrounding muscles to help support your bodies internal structures. Using a machine will likely give better support as it is a more strict form of movement, requiring less stabilization and reducing your need for spreading stresses over other areas of your body. If it hurts stop and find an alternate movement to work the desired muscles."}
{"_id": "5864ce48", "question": "Should two-stroke engines be forgotten?", "answers": "I’m betting that when you think of a two-stroke engine you are thinking of this\nTwo-stroke gasoline engines in street motorcycles and cars have long gone extinct in many countries. They stay only in the smallest of bikes, off road machines, and in places where emissions regulations and enforcement haven’t yet caught up. They aren’t quite forgotten, but they are getting there.\nTwo-stroke engines in small power tools, like weed trimmers, still persist, mostly because they are much lighter and cheaper than comparable 4-stroke motors. They are losing ground to electric motors there, though.\nThe thing is, there are other two-stroke motors that are alive and well, and not likely to go away any time soon.\nThis is a two-stroke diesel engine. It is a little different from the motorcycle two-stroke in that it has a separate oiling system, but it still is a two-stroke.\nTwo-stroke diesels are commonly used to run pumps and generators.\nThis house-sized monster is also a two-stroke diesel. It is a Wärtsilä marine engine used to drive large container ships.\nThese ships will be around for years yet. There is some movement to switch from diesel fuel to liquefied natural gas, but the engines consuming LNG are also two-stroke.\nWe shouldn’t be forgetting two-strokes just yet."}
{"_id": "5be7e548", "question": "Is there any solid proof that President Donald Trump had a mini-stroke?", "answers": "No.\nBut he does exhibit symptoms that are consistent with TIAs, as well as a handful of other neuro-cognitive conditions.\nNo one can definitely make a diagnosis without doing the appropriate tests (strokes can be seen on MRI, even years later.)\nOne telling issue is the Montreal Cognitive Assessment that Trump bragged about recently (he took it in 2017.) The fact that he was asked to take it in the first place is shocking (or maybe he demanded it because he thought it could prove something unrelated about his mental acuity.) He talked about how he could remember the words [person, woman, man, camera, tv] as though any rational, thinking person would believe him.\nWhen you look up the MoCA, the 5 words you’re asked to remember are not related to each other. They’re random, like [face velvet church red papaya.] Trump was GIVEN those 5 words recently because they are easy FOR HIM SPECIFICALLY to remember. The first 3 are describing the same thing, and the last 2 are relevant to him personally as a guy who was once the host of a series. Those would would NEVER have been on a real MoCA test.\nTrump had to get help to pass a test that evaluates for severe cognitive impairment, and no one in the media will say so. Failing to point that out has given Trump’s story a false sense of validity."}
{"_id": "7f12e2f0", "question": "Is it possible to reverse the damage from a stroke?", "answers": "Yes and no: What died has died … but you can train another part of the brain to take over some or all of that area’s function. The field of Occupational Therapy specializes in helping people become functional again, post stroke.\nIf you only had a TIA (Transient Ischemic Attack) you didn’t lose blood supply long enough to the area to cause permanent damage. Those cells have recovered from a “mini-stroke” by themselves.\nIf you arrive in the ER with stroke symptoms WITHIN 4 HOURS (4–6??), they can give you a CLOTBUSTER (TPA) or Streptokinase to dissolve the clot and restore circulation and save the dying brain tissue. In that case, you have a complete recovery because you acted on it immediately."}
{"_id": "f3670d27", "question": "What wears out a petrol engine the most, ignition or compression stroke?", "answers": "I don’t know that it works like that.\nThe passage of the rings up and down the bore will create almost exactly the same friction on each stroke. A little while after top dead centre there will be a lateral thrust against the translation in the gudgeon pin, but that must be more or less exactly the same in compression on the way up and ignition on the way down, even thought it is applied to the opposite faces. I don’t know that you can spot a brighter wear pattern on either east or west faces.\nThe main bearing thrusts average out with rotation, the big ends would drive on opposite faces during compression and ignition.\nI rather think that the design engineers have equalised all this out, and the symmetries in the Carnot cycle probably have really equivalence in wear on the engine.\nI suspect that any difference might be undetectable, and certainly not significant"}
{"_id": "88db3fa0", "question": "What lifestyle habits minimize the risk of a stroke?", "answers": "Staying healthy overall will help minimize the risk of a stroke some healthy habits you can add to your daily routine include walking/getting your heart rate up and moving for more than 45 minutes a day, drinking enough water so your pee is a light yellow instead of dark yellow, adding a cup of fruit and a cup of vegetables to each meal, and replacing meat with fruits, vegetables or starches like rice and potatoes. All of these healthy habits you can add to your routine will help to minimize the risk of a stroke and keep you healthy and living longer. :) if you are trying to find exercises that are great for a healthy heart some may include swimming, running, and jump roping. I would also recommend standing for at least an hour while doing work instead of sitting to keep your blood moving. ;)"}
{"_id": "61a13255", "question": "How many swimming styles are there?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e5af4bf8", "question": "Is an rpm meter for 2 stroke and 4 stroke engine different?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8a4f29ef", "question": "What if a 4-stroke engine stops in a stroke other than exhaust stroke? How will it start the next time?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c449e0cf", "question": "How can one identify whether the IC Engine is 2-stroke or 4-stroke just by looking at the engine from the outside?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a62b7b1a", "question": "Hubby had a stroke on the right side of his brain, but he is experiencing aphasia and language apraxia. Those are symptoms of a left brain stroke. He is right-handed. Why is this happening?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "258f3ae3", "question": "Why don’t car manufacturers make two stroke engines?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7208976b", "question": "What would happen if I didn’t fill up my 4 stroke engine with oil but I used 2 stroke gas?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6709e91b", "question": "What is the exact purpose of a super long stroke or ultra long stroke in a ship's main engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8b87705d", "question": "Which stroke engine requires heavier flywheel either 4 or 2 stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "02146ee8", "question": "What is an ischemic stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "26ad2ce9", "question": "Why did the production of 2 stroke engine vehicles stop in India? Even when 2 stroke engine bikes and scooters had low maintenance and better acceleration?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d4742756", "question": "How scientifically correct is Jill Bolte Taylor's TED talk \"A Stroke of Insight\"?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8ad72cda", "question": "Is it true that most people have a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4985dd20", "question": "Does having a stroke result in a loss of intelligence?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "680e1b0b", "question": "Why can't we build a 2-cylinder engine motorcycle which has one 4-stroke cylinder and one 2-stroke cylinder so that it can provide good acceleration and better efficiency at the same time?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d5f9ce76", "question": "How do one get strokes or minor strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7ce9971c", "question": "Why does two stroke bikes cause more pollution than four stroke bikes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b55d8245", "question": "This one kid at my school wants to fight me. I have 20 kilos on him. How do you think it will turn out?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c9ab3009", "question": "Will the 2-stroke engine make a comeback?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ba65d929", "question": "Can 4-stroke oil be used in a 2-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9723ff09", "question": "What is the correct way to stroke a cat?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "033c595a", "question": "Is there a genetic factor to strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5577ddeb", "question": "How can we identify whether it is 4 stroke or 2 stroke engine without checking it?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "62da4d58", "question": "Is it possible for most people that have had a stroke to learn new things, like languages?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d1112e17", "question": "What are the similarities between a two-stroke engine and a four-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ffb931fd", "question": "What is the difference between a hemorrhagic stroke, an ischemic stroke, and a transient ischemia stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "88218fac", "question": "Why are two-stroke engines lighter than a four-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "88f39b07", "question": "What are the names of the strokes on a two-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9bd3645f", "question": "How are mini-strokes (TIA) diagnosed?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "88b96867", "question": "What is the difference between a Leica M3 single stroke and double stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "850cb636", "question": "What does \"my left stroke just went viral\" mean?", "answers": "From my understanding, the right and left “strokes” are two supposed diss tracks aimed at Big Sean, the right stroke being “The Heart Part IV” released a week before the subsequent left stroke which was the song “HUMBLE.\"\nBoth were a supposed response to Big Sean's diss in his song “No More Interviews” in which Big Sean calls Kendrick out on his being “The God MC” or “The Savior of Rap”. The no more interviews rap goes like this:\n“And I'm just not impressed by you niggas rapping fast\nWho sound like one big asthma attack but trash when I’m rapping it back”\nWho you put in your top five and claim they the savior of rap”\nIn HUMBLE, it was considered dissing Big Sean in that Kendrick was mocking Big Sean's well known adlib “Lil Bitch” and reversing it on him, telling him to sit down and be humble and in the process, turning it into a viral sensation (and what a viral sensation it was)\nHe then doubles down on his hecklers needing to be humbled in the 2nd verse:\n”Who dat nigga thinkin' that he frontin' on Man-Man? (Man-Man)\nGet the fuck off my stage, I'm the Sandman (Sandman)\nGet the fuck off my dick, that ain't right\nI make a play fucking up your whole life”\nOuch\nThe right stroke, in “The Heart Part 4” was in response to Big Sean's diss again in no more interviews. In the first part of the song he doubles down on his title as the “Savior of Rap”\n[Verse 1]\n“Thirty millions later, my future favors\nThe legendary status of a hip-hop rhyme savior”\nThe 2nd verse, where he jabs at Big Sean, is as follows:\n[Verse 2]\n“My fans can't wait for me to son ya punk-ass\nAnd crush ya whole lil' shit\nI'll Big Pun ya punk-ass, you a scared lil' bitch\nTiptoein' around my name, nigga, you lame\nAnd when I get at you, homie\nDon't you just tell me you was just playin'\nOh, I was just playin', K-Dot\nC'mon, you know a nigga rock with you, bro\nShut the fuck up, you sound like the last nigga I know\nMight end up like the last nigga I know\nOh, you don't wanna clash? Nigga, I know”\nOoooouch :-[\nKendrick got a mean hook yo."}
{"_id": "afc514bc", "question": "How do you tell the difference between a stroke and a hemiplegic migraine?", "answers": "Hemiplegic migraine auras usually evolve in a stereotypical manner. For instance, symptoms may involve the face first, beginning with tingling and weakness around the mouth spreading to involve one whole side of the face over 10–20 minutes after which symptoms may slowly move up or down the ipsilateral arm, and then eventually the ipsilateral leg will be involved. The details of where they start and how they evolve differ, patient to patient.\nStrokes are abrupt and all affected areas are affected simultaneously. The key point, however, is that stroke symptoms involve a specific arterial territory. Generally, the signs and symptoms of a stroke allow precise specification of the affected artery based on the clinical findings; scans just confirm the clinical impression.\nIn contrast to strokes, migraine auras do not respect arterial territories. The aura progression only makes anatomical sense as a process spreading across cortical tissue (Cortical spreading depression - Wikipedia\n). As it spreads, it crosses from cortex nourished by one artery into areas nourished by another artery. In contrast, strokes do not slowly progress nor sequentially involve separate arterial territories.\nTL;DR: The presentations of stroke and hemiplegic migraine aura differ in details that make sense in terms of their underlying mechanisms and brain neuroanatomy. Since the details of auras vary between patients, each patient is best served by learning their particular aura manifestations. Nothing prevents them from learning the cortical and vascular anatomy underlying their symptoms; it might be reassuring to them if they did. It's a big piece of medical education to learn, however. I never met a patient with that level of interest, but I'm sure some exist."}
{"_id": "35fde76c", "question": "Does having a heart attack or a stroke hurt?", "answers": "Most strokes are painless; because the brain has no pain sensors. A heart attack hurts right in the center of your chest. It usually happens the first time on a cold winter day. You are outside working or exercising hard. Breathing the cold air chills the blood in the lungs and when it returns to the heart, it chills the coronary arteries., causing them to contract. If the coronary arteries are already plugged up with calcium and cholesterol deposits, the shrinking coronary arteries will not carry enough blood and oxygen to supply your heart, if you are working hard. The pain is strong enough to make you stop what you are doing. Quit work, go inside and warm up. The pain will go away, until you go outside and try to work again the next day in the cold. You need to stay inside and stay warm. When spring comes and the weather warms up, you can go outside and work again. In the meantime, you need to increase your intake of vitamin C. You need a tablet of 1,000 mgs of C each day. If you take too much C, it will give you diarrhea; but as soon as that clears up, keep taking 1,000 mgs per day. That amount should not give you diarrhea. It will take about a year for the vitamin C to clear up the calcium and cholesterol clogging your coronary arteries. If you are in a hurry to get better, take a tablet each of the amino acids lysine and proline each day with the vitamin C.The lower animals do not have coronary problems, because they make their own vitamin C in their livers; but the gene for making vitamin C is badly mutated in humans. An animal the size of a human, like a sheep, makes about 1,000 mgs of C each day; more when sick or injured. Vitamin C is used as a co-enzyme to cross link the collagen molecules, making them as strong as steel, for their weight. The protein collagen is what holds your body together. One half of the protein in your body is collagen. Collagen holds your arteries together. When you don’t get enough vitamin C, the collagen is weak and eventually starts to break. Calcium and cholesterol are used to reinforce the weak arteries; but eventually they build up and plug the arteries. You cannot get enough vitamin C from your diet, not even if you drink orange juice all day. I buy vitamin C in a bottle of timed-release 1,000 mgs size, 100 tablets at walmart for about $5.00; that is about 5 cents each per day. Read more about vitamin C on the Internet. Google “Why animals don’t get heart attacks; but people do” by Dr. Rath. Dr. Rath is on a mission to eliminate heart disease. On the other hand, you can go to your cardiac doctor and for only about $100,000 or more, he will cut your chest open and replace your plugged up arteries, and maybe a heart valve or two. Most patients survive the operation, but look like refugees from a WWII concentration camp. They recover in about 3 or 4 months. But because they still don’t take their vitamin C tablets, they usually die anyway in another 10 or 15 years, after their heart operation. by Jerry Collins"}
{"_id": "3163d58d", "question": "Why is 2-stroke not available in the market?", "answers": "In the last century development of vehicles accompanied the 2-stroke engines\n(1st stroke for injection and compression then 2nd for power and ejection) were in use.\nEven some bikes in India such as YAMAHA crux or Kawasaki boxer had 2 stroke engines.\nREASONS to upgrade engines from 2-stroke engines are:\n1. less mechanical efficiency\n2. noise pollution\n3. very less fuel efficiency\n4. not at all Eco- friendly\n4-stroke engines which are the most commonly used in whole world because it overcomes the above mentioned demerits because each stoke in the 4-stroke engines\ncarries out only one single operation and that also efficiently:\ninjection\ncompression\npower stroke\nejection\n6-stroke engines have also come up by introducing hot water into the piston for removing the soot particles left after 4 strokes."}
{"_id": "963c4ff9", "question": "Can a stroke lead to spiritual enlightenment like it did for Jill Bolte Taylor (in the video below)?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ec9257e6", "question": "What is the stroking order of a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": "Remember:\nSuck, Squeeze, Bang, Blow.\nSuck. Intake stroke. Intake valve is open, piston starts at top dead center (TDC) and moves down in its bore to bottom dead center (BDC). This creates a vacuum which draws the intake charge into the cylinder through the intake valve.\nSqueeze. The compression stroke begins. As the intake valve closes, the piston rises up in the cylinder and compresses the intake charge, and just before the piston makes it to TDC,\nBang. The ignition event occurs. In a spark ignition engine (gasoline etc), this is where the spark plug fires the air/fuel intake charge. In a compression ignition (diesel) engine, this is where the fuel is injected into the super hot air intake charge, which initiates combustion. The rapidly expanding gases created in the deflagrating ignition drives the piston down the bore, and imparts torque to the crankshaft. This is the power stroke.\nBlow. Once the piston is back at BDC, the exhaust valve opens, the piston moves up the bore and pushes the spent gases out through the open exhaust valve. At TDC, the exhaust valve closes, the intake valve opens and we begin a new cycle.\nThis is the operating principle of all 4 stroke engines, no matter what fuel they burn."}
{"_id": "504a1a72", "question": "How do I take 5 strokes off my golf game?", "answers": "I have two answers for you. The first one is the smart-alleck one: Play one less hole each round.\nThe better answer starts with finding out what part of your golf game is costing you the most strokes.\nPutting. Three-putts can add strokes to your score quickly. Good players only have 20 to 25 putts per round.\nPenalty strokes. These are scorecard killers. Every time you lose a ball in the woods or in the water, you have to takes a penalty stroke.\nSand traps. For the average golfer these are the equivalent of a one-stroke penalty because it takes one extra stroke on that hole to get the ball out of the sand.\nThose are three different areas that add up quickly and can turn a good round into a bad one. You can reduce your number of putts in two ways: become a better putter or start off closer to the hole. This means you have to land your approach shots closer to the hole. You should have no shame in being on a par four in three shots if that third shot leaves you with a putt inside of five feet. You can save a lot of trouble (and time) if you learn to hit the ball better and keep it in the fairway or rough. Sometimes you have to swallow your pride and take less club so that you can keep the ball going straight. Also, there aren’t a whole lot of sand traps in the middle of the fairway or directly in front of the green. If you hit the ball straight the ball tends to stay out of sand traps.\nAll of this adds up to playing smart golf. It may not be as much fun but you will lower your score. Ten years ago I used to average 315 yards off the tee with my driver and I had a 14 handicap. After keeping track of of my stats I found those three areas were the ones driving my scores up. I spent many hours practicing my putting and chipping to get my scores down. Now I tee off with my 3-wood for 230 yds and my handicap is down to a 4 and I rarely three putt.\nFigure out your weaknesses and make them your strengths."}
{"_id": "c7c0379d", "question": "Do you believe a person can recover from a major stroke? My husband suffered a massive stroke, a central main artery with occlusion stroke. I need some good hope as we face whatever is next.", "answers": "OK. Let’s try for some good hope.\nFirst, it’s impossible to say. The brain is quite plastic. It can’t repair itself, but it’s quite good at rewiring itself, working around injured areas and learning new functions when the previous brain areas aren’t able to perform them any more. The younger the person is, the more adaptable the brain is, but it’s still adaptable in people who are older. So there’s a reasonable/good possibility that your husband’s brain may be able to re-learn or adapt to his current condition.\nSecond, intensive rehabilitation can help, It’s best to begin as soon as possible and the most rapid progress is usually made in the first few months. On the other hand, progress can continue for years after the stroke or other brain injury.\nThird, huge advances are being made in bionics, electronics, and other sorts of devices to help brain injury patients both recover and function.\nNone of that is a guarantee of anything. But some people make remarkable recoveries, or at least great progress. And the more work the patient and the family put into it, the greater the likelihood of progress. One piece of advice: Don’t take a physician’s pronouncement of “He’ll never be able to….again” very seriously. While the physician may be correct, you don’t know unless/until you try.\nI interviewed the Pulitizer-prize winning columnist Art Buchwald several years after his massive stroke, and his progress was remarkable. And his isn’t an isolated story."}
{"_id": "b568156a", "question": "Which lightening stroke is more dangerous?", "answers": "Typical cloud-ground CG lightning only lasts for tens of millionths of a second. It gives an intensely loud “bang,” but doesn’t carry enough energy to char or ignite materials, to cause steam explosions inside trees, etc. Certainly it might kill you via nerve damage or by triggering a heart attack. But many people have survived such lightning strikes. (It helps if you’re wearing a wet raincoat! The plasma-streamer then may never actually touch your body.) Dangerous yes. But not that dangerous.\nHowever, the total length of lightning can be much, much longer, and the stroke may last far longer: from a good fraction of a second, up to several seconds at the maximum. These are the long-persisting or “hot lightning” strikes. They’ll set fires. They’ll explode trees and pole-transformers, melt metal, leave charred trails across the ground. At the upper end they’ll spread for miles across the sky. They can move around and change position during the strike, and will inject enormous energy into any object in their path.\nHot lightning can char wood, explode trees, melt cables, blow holes in the dirt. Imagine what it would do to a human body.\nPS\nI finally saw hot lightning! This was during Seattle’s bizarre 2019 lightning storm, thirty miles across and a couple hundred miles long. I saw hundreds of normal lightnings, the kinds which act like flashbulbs. I also saw two ground strikes where the streamer persisted for an entire half a second, took on a tortuous path like river oxbow-bends, and then broke up into a row of small flames of “bead lightning.” Whatever was hit could be charred and flaming, if not blown to pieces.\nPPS\nA colleague at an rf test facility tells a story from his grade-school in Louisiana, where a “hot” stroke melted the school’s aluminum flagpole! Was this exaggeration? Years later I asked a weather researcher about it, and he said that this sort of thing actually is quite common. Holy cow! If you have a small sailboat out during a storm down south, would you rather your aluminum mast be melted into a pool of slag, or instead have a wooden or fiberglass mast which explodes like a bomb?"}
{"_id": "8e42ee2a", "question": "Is a 4 stroke more powerful than a 2-stroke? Which is a faster 2-stroke or 4 stroke engine?", "answers": "If your talking out board engines hp for hp two strokes dominate.\nI have observed this time after time, but the definitive proof for me was on a NZ navy dive course circa 2004.\nWe had access to two identical 5.5 metre alloy boats with more or less new Mercury 90s on the back. One boat had the 2 stroke and the other had the 4 stroke. Same year same size, not to sure on weight of each.\nWhen on the last week (or so) of this course, we spent our time off base, doing single tank dives. We would head out with a boatman in each boat and six divers across both boats.\nQuickly we realised the boat with the 4 stroke on the back could only handle 3 people plus a single set of dive gear, and almost keep up with 5 guys and 5 sets of dive gear on the boat with the 2 stroke.\nWith 2 guys and no gear the 4 stroke caught up relatively quickly and had a better top speed, but it was pathetic when it came to getting up on the plain with a bit of weight on board, when compared to the 2 stroke equivalent.\nSo the 2 stroke has way more usable horse power, and anyone with half an inche of common sense knows that speed is all down to gearing.\nThings may have changed in moder times, but I also can say my modern yamaha f115 has pretty crap useable low end power compared to the old 115hp v4 2 strokes. Way better on gas though."}
{"_id": "6717e89b", "question": "Which engines have been invented earlier a 2 stroke or a 4 stroke?", "answers": "Both were made at almost the same time, but 2 stroke were implemented earlier than 4 stroke due to their simplicity to manufacture.\nAs we know that the Newcomen Atmospheric Engine of 1714 is a two stroke and so is the Watt Engine of 1775. But Watt-Boulton engine or 1817 is the first successful 4-stroke engine. Adding two more cycles to the process was Boulton’s idea to reduce heat per cycle and to improve efficiency, well it did the former quite well but the later wasn't achieved sadly. Adding two more cycles meant that the fuel was to be controlled and hence came the camshaft in 1795. 4 cycles also meant that speed in terms of RPM was greatly increased and so, governors were designed in 1813. Finally allowing the 4-Stroke engines out of a clumsy drawing board in 1817. But, not yet completely. They had a nasty habit of BLASTING. Which wasn't much resolved until 1900’s when for the first time pulsating valves were used in 4-stroke engines. By 1914 we only had a small sound left which is called knocking due to intermitters."}
{"_id": "610140ce", "question": "Can there be a 2-stroke Diesel engine?", "answers": "2-stroke diesels are reasonably common outside of road vehicles. They work by using a low-pressure supercharger to force air into the cylinders and push exhaust gas out. Intake ports are exposed by the piston as it moves towards BDC, allowing air to be pushed in by the supercharger. An exhaust valve at the top opens at the same time, allowing the fresh intake charge to expel burnt gases.\nAs the piston rises, the air in the cylinder is compressed. Diesel fuel is injected somewhere around TDC, which ignites in the hot air and forces the piston back down. The exhaust valve opens, the intake ports are uncovered and the cycle repeats.\nUnlike a 2-stroke petrol, where fuel and air are drawn in together, diesel fuel is added only to the closed cylinder. There is therefore no emissions problem of unburnt fuel escaping the engine in the exhaust. A 2-stroke petrol also uses the crankcase for scavenging, requiring oil to be added to the fuel-air mix and burnt. A diesel 2-stroke doesn't suffer this drawback due to the external supercharger."}
{"_id": "f09f1540", "question": "Have you ever had a stroke?", "answers": "I had a stroke when I was in my 30’s and was a waitress at that time for extra cash. I was counting my money on my bed at about 10am and the next day at 3am woke up on the floor next to my bed. My entire right arm had no feeling and I never went to the hospital or dr. I did rehab my arm with a broom stick lifting it up and down with the help of my left hand. It took months but I did recover. Because of that I can drive a stick shift car with my left hand better than anyone. If you think you have had a stroke see a dr or go to the er asap. If I would have done that I would have recovered faster. I was on the pill at the time and smoked and had high blood pressure. Get medical help. Laurie in Miami"}
{"_id": "26c5d87c", "question": "If you don't get cancer, a heart attack, a stroke, diabetes, or Alzheimer's, how would one die of old age?", "answers": "Simply speaking, every living thing has a defined life and due to prolonged usage, deterioration of various organs leads to death.\nAs you are aware, there are billions of cells in our body, which make up the basic structure. There is an in-built mechanism by which cells die after a specific period and new cells are generated to take its place. This process of generation of new cells is higher than the death of old cells till we are in growth phase. After that, the rate almost equals till late thirties. Beyond that, the rate of new cell generation declines and fewer cells are able to replace dead cells.\nThis cycle leads to deterioration of various body parts, most visible signs are seen in terms of our ability to see, listen, digest, etc. as well as wrinkles all over the body and problems in free movement.\nFurther, with the death of old cells, there is accumulation of free radicals and reactive oxygen in the body. This plays a vital part in aging and ultimately death.\nAging is generated by multiple causes including damage to the structures and functions of the molecules, cells, organs, etc., of an organism. Such causes of aging include but are not limited to oxidative stress, glycation, telomere shortening, side reactions, mutations, aggregation of proteins, etc. In other words, it is the progressive damage to these structures and functions that we perceive and characterize as aging. This damage leads to development of pathological conditions and, as a consequence, to death."}
{"_id": "4ab327a7", "question": "What are four-stroke engines used in?", "answers": "In items being produced now in the following categories four strokes prevail. General Aviation and small Commercial Aviation aircraft up to about 400 horsepower single engined aircraft or 800 horsepower twin engined aircraft. In experimental and ultra light aircraft 2 strokes are often found, but 4 strokes are also common. Most motorcycles larger than 50 cc in developed countries. Almost all automobiles, busses, trucks, equipment for construction, farming, firefighting, logging, portable electrical generation, In marine applications 4 strokes dominate the emission regulated outboard market, the inboard outboard installations and the sub 10,000 hp market\n2 strokes prevail in the hand held power tools, where power to weight is very important, where engine cost must be kept low, where brake specific fuel consumption is less important or conversely, where it is very important in huge engines powering ships and permanent electric power generation.\nTurbine engines supplant piston engines where power to weight is important, maintenance needs to be limited, reliability is very important, purchase price is less dominant, BSFC is less critical and duty cycle is high. Generally this is in the 300 and up horsepower market."}
{"_id": "d7e1b229", "question": "How did the term vinegar strokes come into usage?", "answers": "It seems that the term ‘vinegar stroke (Note singular) goes way way back than thought. As vinegar was a form of contraception control. The mild acidic effect was believed to kill off sperm before conception could take place. Also as a way of hiding the odours. My Father used this term when I was a Lad 60+ years ago. I stand corrected if proven wrong."}
{"_id": "dba26577", "question": "Can I mix 4 stroke oil with petrol for a 2 stroke engine?", "answers": "First of all we should understand the concept of lubrication done on 4 stroke cycle and two stroke cycle engine… let understand 2 stroke first.. In 2 stroke cycle engine lubricating oil is mixed with fuel to lubricate the engine part.. And the oil burn with fuel (some part).. But in case of 4 engines are lubricated by oil held in an oil sump. The oil is distributed through the engine by splash lubrication or a presurized pump system.. So if u r using 4 stroke engine oil and mixing with fuel in 2 stroke cycle.. Technically it would work.. But it strongly depend upon the grade factor of oil…"}
{"_id": "612dcfef", "question": "Why do diesel engines have a higher compression ratio?", "answers": "Recollecting the stuffs that my teacher taught me….!!\nManaged to recollect some technical stuffs…\nOk ,First i will give you a simple theoritical definition about what actually compression ratio means “compression ratio is defined as the ratio of total volume of the engine cylinder (ie..both clearance and stroke volume ) to the clearance volume” You can see the below image to know about it clearly…\nNow i will tell you little practically “The compression ratio of an engine cylinder merely depends upon the size of the engine (If the engine is very bigger it will have more stroke volume obviously the compression ratio also increases(clearance volume is very small compared to stroke volume)…..You can see through the below image to get a simple idea about it…\nNow coming to your question …I will list out some reasons why diesel engines have more compression ratios..\nREASON 1: BASED ON THEIR APPLICATIONS\nDiesel engines are mostly used for high torque applications (for eg…Trucks,Locomotives,Ships etc…)..Hence they need huge amount of power hence which means more combustion rate….I will tell you a simple fact.\nIF ENGINE CYLINDER IS BIG ,MORE AIR GETS COMPRESSED DURING COMPRESSION STROKE AND HENCE MORE AMOUNT OF FUEL NEED TO BE SUPPLIED FOR IT ,HENCE MORE POWER IS PRODUCED INSIDE THE ENGINE WHICH EVENTUALLY LEADS TO MORE BRAKE HORSE POWER ..\nHence for this purpose diesel engines are usually made with larger cylinder sizes which leads to ‘more compression ratio’..\nREASON 2: TO AVOID KNOCKING\nKnocking is phenomenon in which means a abnormal combustion occuring inside the engine cylinder ….\nIt is more common in gasoline engines ‘INCREASING THE COMPRESSION RATIO MAY LEAD TO KNOCK IN GASOLINE ENGINES ‘..You can look at the picture below to know how combustion occurs in petrol and diesel engines(left is gasoline ,right is diesel)..\nBut leave about it ….In diesel engines knocking is actually reduced by having high compression ratios because ‘The combustion that is occuring inside a diesel engine is very abnormal and non-uniform in an diesel engine (this is why diesel engines have more vibrations) hence the cylinder size of the diesel engine is very high and also clearance volume is very less in order to avoid knocking…\nKnocking also occurs when the fuel injected into the cylinder fails to ignite or combust incompletely which leads to knock.\nAlso when the temperature developed inside the engine cylinder may lead to know ..\nImproper atomization of the fuel or time delay (which is literally called as Ignition delay )occurs in the Injectors…\nCOMING TO THE NEXT QUESTION YOU ASKED ….In fabrication side some modifications are done to withstand such more amount of power generated from the engine….\nThe pistons of the engines are usually made with HIGH CARBON AND HARDENED STEELS ,to bear much high impact during combustion even though sometimes the pistons are damaged…\nEngine cooling and lubrications are another big challenge in diesel engines generally for this purpose synthetic oils are used for better lubrication and dust removal purposes…\nThe next thing to do is obviously increasing the size of the engine and fabricating bigger crankshafts (For gaining more torque) and also designing bigger connecting rods of better toughness and wear resistance for bearing such impact power..\nI HOPE THIS ANSWER WOULD HAVE CLEARED YOUR DOUBTS …THANKS FOR VIEWING ,ANY CORRECTIONS IN THE ANSWER AND BETTER SUGGESTIONS ARE WELCOMED….."}
{"_id": "8d926189", "question": "Why is buttermilk good in summer? Is it to prevent heat stroke?", "answers": "With the summer, the temperatures are rapidly increasing. As a result, we sweat more, causing us to need to increase our fluid intake drastically. To begin, buttermilk contains active cultures. This means that it has healthy bacteria that become active in the intestines. These pro biotic properties of buttermilk cause it to soothe the intestinal tract. These bacteria perform functions such as manufacturing vitamins, boosting immunity and manufacturing nutrients.\nButtermilk can also be used as a substitute for milk for people who have high lactose intolerance, since the process of making buttermilk converts the lactose to a more digestible substance — lactic acid. As a result of the higher lactic acid content, it helps in boosting digestion as well. Thus, more minerals such as proteins and calcium (from the milk) can be taken up by the body more easily."}
{"_id": "3a557b63", "question": "What is Amit Shah's plan about PoK? Is he planning another master stroke which might shatter Pakistan?", "answers": "People of Gilgit-Baltistan have already expressed their desire to come & join with Ladakh with whom they share lot of history & culture. If you closely look, one will find that Gilgit-Baltistan & Ladakh share a long common border.\nPakistan had long withdrawn Maharajas 1927 policy of Art 35A kind law & settled Sunni Muslims all across Gilgit -Baltistan, which lead to civil war.\nRecently as late as in 2018 Pakistan annexed Gilgit-Baltistan & placed it directly under Prime Minister of Pakistan without recognising it as a territory within the purview of the Pakistan state under it's constitution.\nSo far India refrained from going to International Court of Justice (ICJ) honouring Shimla Agreement of 'peaceful bilateral resolution of Indo-Pak issues' but if this time around Pakistan heads for ICJ themselves then as far as the legalities & circumstantial evidences available on record, Pakistan is likely to loose any claim on J&K for ever !!!!!\nNow India may either take military or diplomatic action at the World forum & wrest Gilgit-Baltistan from Pakistan, which are legally Indian Territory.\nIf that happens them CPEC OBOR project will go for toss.\nReferences and Footnotes:\nHow Pakistan Annexed Gilgit-Baltistan But Refused To Give Provincial Status: India Today Analysis | EurAsian Times: Latest Asian, Middle-East, EurAsian, Indian News\nAfter Article 370 scrapped in Jammu and Kashmir, calls grow for integration of Gilgit-Baltistan with India | WATCH\nGilgit-Baltistan wishes to join Ladakh\nDispelling the myths of Kashmir | The Japan Times\nPic source: Google\nEdit1: Another interesting fact about Gilgit-Baltistan is that the mother's there prepare 10 extra rotis for Indian soldiers, for the last 70 years, expecting that Indian Army will one day come here & give us independence…….!!!!!! Watch the video\nEdit2: Since the above video deleted by YouTube, after my last update of Sept11, 2019, please see the video with only the relevant content\n24th Oct 2019"}
{"_id": "a5a8aa37", "question": "Why are the 2nd and 3rd strokes in a 2 stroke engine considered only one? Knowing that they happen the same way as the ones in a 4 stroke engine, the 2 stroke engine shouldn’t be called a 2 stroke engine, but actually 3 stroke.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b0e4fbd3", "question": "Why can't someone who's had a stroke learn or even know a language?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ddc2ff74", "question": "Do fish enjoy being stroked?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1df2e45d", "question": "How would I start to manage a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "032e5825", "question": "Is 10% reservation for the economically weaker section of forward castes a master stroke by Modi, which has stunned the opposition parties?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3f7c3990", "question": "When you turn off the engine of a car, at what position does the piston in the internal combustion engine stop in relation to a four-stroke cycle?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3e0b8122", "question": "With a 2-stroke engine, what would happen if I mixed the gasoline with engine oil instead of special 2-stroke oil?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6ddcb8ff", "question": "If pressurized distilled water was directly injected into the top of a 4-stroke engine right as the power stroke begins, would it increase efficiency?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "669aa98c", "question": "What is is it like to experience a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2a4b6599", "question": "In CSS, what is the difference between border, outline, and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "77307e2f", "question": "Why are diesel engines are often designed with a long stroke (as compared to gasoline engines)? What is it about diesel fuel itself that leads designers (generally) to use a longer stroke for diesel and a shorter stroke for gasoline?", "answers": "This is a myth because if you do a survey on diesel engines you will find the ratio between under square and over square diesel engines is around 50/50. If look back through the ages compared to modern engines you will find older engines in both petrol and diesel are predominantly under square ie longer stroke to bore diameter. This also relates to number of valves per cylinder as most engines these days are 4 valve per cylinder and need the room for the extra valves.\nAnother myth is torque. Many believe that a long stroke engine has more torque. A small diameter piston has less lbs force total pressure on the piston surface area but a long stroke with more mechanical advantage. A short stroke engine has a large piston diameter so high force due to large piston surface area and short stroke so less mechanical advantage. What is true though is speed range of the engine where peak torque is achieved. A long stroke or under square engine by having a small bore and thus smaller or less valves has breathing difficulty at high rpm so the engines valve timing and manifold design is optimised for lower speed. The reverse is true for short stroke over square engines."}
{"_id": "f495bb75", "question": "If a person commits a horrible crime and then suffers a stroke that causes them to totally forget having done it, should they be punished anyway?", "answers": "If a stroke is severe enough to cause retrograde amnesia severe enough to erase all memory of a purported crime, the criminal should be punished, assuming that he or she was convicted and sentenced prior to the stroke. Culpability remains. If the stroke is so severe that the patient has a \"locked-in syndrome\" in which communication is virtually or literally impossible, the court may choose to conditionally release the individual to a care facility or home care, on compassionate grounds, as a prison setting is wholly inadequate for managing the stroke sequelae.\nIf, on the other hand, the stroke occurred after the alleged crime, but before the trial, the defendant should, most likely, not be prosecuted unless or until he or she is cognitively and physically capable of assisting in his or her own defense. With such a severe stroke, recovery would be unlikely. This situation would be very rare, but certainly conceivable.\nA stroke that causes complete global amnesia for a long period of time (more than a few hours before or after the stroke), but spares even limited speech or cognition is exceedingly rare. Vanishingly so. There are case reports scattered through the literature, but most doctors will never see such a devastating stroke during their careers. The stroke would need to totally destroy the medial temporal lobe and the Hippocampus. This would be strikingly obvious, even to a layperson, on brain scan. My wife, a very experienced board-certified neurologist MD, has not seen such a stroke in several decades of practice."}
{"_id": "86794dc6", "question": "What are the applications of a four-stroke petrol engine?", "answers": "Four stroke engines have higher fuel efficiency in comparision to two stroke engines.\nThe four stroke petrol engines are the most commonly used engines in today’s automobile sector and vehicles, both in cases of single cylinder and multi cylinder applications.\nFour stroke petrol engine commonly used in petrol cars, motorbikes, scooters, small propeller aircrafts, formula one, small motor powered boats, auto-rickshaw, water spray systems, etc.\nThe petrol four stroke has a wide application since the higher value of the low end punch capabilities of the engines ."}
{"_id": "db83e162", "question": "Why do strokes often happen in the bathroom?", "answers": "I spent a number of years driving an Ambulance back when I was very young - 20’s. Three of those years were spent on the “night car” - we came on duty in the evening and handled all the calls at night. We went off duty around 7:30. It was very common to get a “body removal” just before being called in. Invariably, we would find a body in the bathroom dead from natural causes. It was so common it became expected. We were tired and wanted to go home and such a call could keep us on duty for hours longer than planned. We held our breath as the time came nearer.\nWhat happens is Papa wakes up feeling terrible - chest pains, nausea, whatever, he staggers into the bathroom to deal with it - sit on the toilet maybe, or lean over the sink and splash water on his face, get some medicine, who knows? And dies. Why? Any of the reasons old people succumb to old age - stroke, heart attack, etc. Anyway, Mama sleeps on. She wakes up in the morning to go to the potty and finds Papa dead. She calls us or the Police. Somebody then calls us to remove the body, or show up in emergency condition to try and save the guy.\nWe hated those calls. Picking up a 200+ pound, five foot or six foot sprawling mass wrapped up around a toilet or stretched out by the tub. in a tiny room is back breaking hard work. And in the morning when you’re tired and ready to go home after a long shift, doubly hard."}
{"_id": "b92be225", "question": "Is having a stroke more dangerous than a heart attack?", "answers": "Both are dangerous, both are life-threatening. In the Western world, mortality rate for stroke is around 17% and for heart attack is around 14%. Rates maybe higher in developing countries.\nBoth can lead to disability— stroke can lead to neurological damage, weakness and paralysis. Heart attack can be complicated by cardiogenic shock, arrhythmias, stroke and other sequelae. Also, they can vary hugely in degree - a mild stroke cannot be compared to a severe myocardial infarction, and vice versa.\nAnyways, it's not as if we can choose one over the other. Ischaemic stroke and myocardial infarction have the same underlying pathophysiology. Lifestyle changes to address inflammation, blood pressure, weight and other risk factors, can lower the risk of both myocardial infarction and stroke."}
{"_id": "f7201548", "question": "If you found out your uncle had had a stroke three weeks ago and remained in the hospital due to paralysis, what would you do to help?", "answers": "So sorry to hear of your uncle's and his family's plight.\nLiving in Western Europe, having universal health care, I can't comment on the problems your aunt would face paying for the hospital bills since this would all have been covered by our mandatory (compulsory) health insurance. But I imagine your aunt wouldn't be the only one who isn't able to pay for a patient's medical care after such a calamity.\nI sympathize with your fears about the family not being able to service their mortgage, losing income, and such consequences of your uncle being chronically sick in the long term and not being able to work.\nIn the place where I live and worked the family would long have contacted the hospital social worker, to figure out what support they could claim.\nIt might be that that is almost non existent in the US, but that the family will only know after contacting the hospital social worker. These people would have extensive experience dealing with uninsured people unable to pay for their hospital expenses too.\nIt's not clear to me why someone who had had a stroke after three weeks is still in a hospital, since for the majority of patients there wouldn't be much one could do in hospital better than elsewhere (rehab center, nursing home, home), the care being preventative drugs to prevent further vascular damage (e.g. heart attack, peripheral arterial disease) usual a statin regardless of his serum cholesterol level, see Page on thelancet.com\nstrict blood pressure control, not smoking, and rehab including exercises to learn to swallow better in our place done by a speech therapist.\nWhy is he still an in patient in the (expensive) hospital?\nYou personally can't do much other than support the family, like suggested by Chelsea Smith, helping them with whatever you can: clean the house, walk the dog, get groceries, maybe even cook for them, if you want to ask if they'll agree to you visiting your uncle. Don't think you would be able to help them out financially, although you could offer to help them pay for some of their smaller expenses if that's within your means.\nPlease do visit this site National\nStroke\nAssociation\nand What are some common outcomes of\nstroke\n& some common treatments for these outcomes?\nand Ischemic\nstroke\nprognosis in adults\nAll the best!"}
{"_id": "4ec1c927", "question": "Can I use car engine oil on my 4-stroke motorcycle?", "answers": "Of course you can. Since the dawn of motorcycling until very recently there was only different grades of motor oil, not vehicle specific oils. And since at least the late 1950’s bikes with multiplate clutches that ALSO acted as centrigugal clutches have had regular motor oil specified.\nThere ARE certain oils produced specifically for certain cars these days which have friction modifiers but these are marked as such, and are usually very low viscosity (like 0w-20) and designed to cut internal resistance to improve the vehicle’s economy to make the figures look better.\nPeople will tell you that synthetic oils won’t work in your bike because somehow, they are so slippery the wet clutches won’t grip. THAT is also utter bollocks. I personally have been running Mobil 1 fully synthetic in ALL my motorcycles since 1985.\nThe bikes were/are\nHonda CD200…Wet clutch and pretty worn out and slipping a bit BEFORE I put Mobil 1 in…which made no difference.\nYamaha SR500….Wet clutch…Mobil 1 fully synthetic 5w-50\nHusqvarna 350 Enduro 35 bhp MX motor…Wet clutch, and engine rebuilt at time of purchase by Husky Sport\nin the UK who would ONLY guarantee the engine if it was fitted with Mobil 1 fully synthetic 5w-50\n1963 Honda C100 Wet centrifugal clutch… Mobil 1 fully synthetic 0w-40\nHonda C90 Cub…wet centrifugal clutch…Mobil 1 fully synthetic 0w-40\nHonda cd185 Wet clutch, Mobil 1 fully synthetic 0w-40\nHonda CD200 Wet clutch, Mobil 1 fully synthetic 0w-40\nHonda CB125T , 12.000 rpm twin, Wet clutch, Mobil 1 fully synthetic 0w-40\nKawasaki W650 bought new in 1999…. Wet clutch…Mobil fully synthetic 1 0w-40.\n2010 Honda 125i Innova…TWO Wet clutches, one centrifugal multiplate, one normal multiplate…daily commuter Mobil 1 fully synthetic 0w-40… (stolen)\n2010 Honda 125i Innova…TWO Wet clutches, one centrifugal multiplate, one normal multiplate…daily commuter Mobil 1 fully synthetic 0w-40…\nBMW R75/6 dry clutch….\nHonda sh300 scooter….Some weird variator thing, but the engine has Mobil 1 fully synthetic in\nSR500…Wet clutch…Mobil 1 fully synthetic 0w-40\nAll the bikes have regular Mobil 1 fully synthetic motor oil…Exactly the same oil that is in my Mazda MX-5\n…And I work in a National motor Service Centre as an Assistant Manager so I talk to oil manufacturers\nThe ONLY time a fully synthetic oil might cause problems is if the bikes clutch is so worn out the only thing providing friction is burned oil because the friction material has worn away. true fully synthetic has cleansers that will remove that burned oil.\nYour bike’s manual will specify the oil. It will probably say a 10w-40 …a 1989 spec ‘G’ oil. that is the MINIMUM quality to get the expected service life. Note that it doesn’t say Motorcycle specific oil…that isn’t an omission. No one would accidentally forget such a potentially litigious thing if it were true."}
{"_id": "bb19153a", "question": "How is Xavier's University Bhubaneswar for a B.Tech in CSE? How is the placement?", "answers": "I really liked this answer I found on another similar question. It’s detailed and covers everything.\nSomeone anonymous's answer to How is Xavier University Bhubaneswar for btech CSE?\nAbout placements : Since the BTech CSE programme started in 2017, 2021 will be the first year that we see placements happen."}
{"_id": "198491c3", "question": "Can a massage cause a stroke?", "answers": "To give an honest well informed answer to this question is hard because lot of post massage incidents go unreported .\nThere are random sporadic incidents of adverse events caused by Massages ( given by non professionals ) . The possibility of Stroke can not be ruled out if neck is the site of massage in a person who has Carotid artery Stenosis or someone with hyper coagulable blood with a clot sitting somewhere in the neck .\nInadvertent pressure on the Neuro vascular bundle in the neck can have its own complications since they are very superficial and Can have direct impact like shearing and tearing of the blood vessels in case of excess or inappropriate pressure application . Not forget the Pressure of carotid sinus can have its on effects . So having said even though this all is a possibility in theory some side effects are well documents but with low incidence . On the other hand benefits of massage therapy are also well documented .\nIn a nutshell - side effects are rare but possible .\nCareful selection of trained massage professional is a must .\nFull medical history , any medication intake and any medical or surgical concerns must be shared and risks disclosed between both giver and receiver of the massage .\nFor academic purpose here is an article of interest. A must read .\nSixteen case reports and four case series of adverse events after massage therapy were found. Massage was frequently used for rheumatological conditions. In the majority of these cases causality is established con- vincingly, for instance, through the sequence or nature of events. Some of the adverse effects relate to serious complications.\nConsidering the popularity of massage therapy, the number of reported adverse events seems minute. How- ever, this could be due to under-reporting. In a related area (spinal manipulation) we have, for instance, shown that under-reporting of serious adverse events is close to 100%\nClearly, one should differentiate between various approaches. The above findings suggest that massage by non-professional and forceful techniques like shiatsu, urut and Rolfing are relatively often associated with adverse events. The reports reviewed above are often incomplete. For instance, the background of the therapist and the type of massage therapy are not always described. This further limits the conclusiveness of the evidence.\nSeveral systematic reviews of controlled clinical trials testing the effectiveness of massage therapies have been published and have arrived at cautiously positive conclusions . However, too few clinical trials of massage therapy exist and many of its claims are not backed up by evidence. Thus adequate risk–benefit evaluations are not feasible.\nIn conclusion, massage therapies are not totally devoid of risks. The incidence of adverse events is unknown, but probably low.\nhttps://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/1a78/74937ebe08d54fc4e195fdacf838399f4ffe.pdf"}
{"_id": "6f71f5ba", "question": "Could having a terrible argument with someone cause a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b920c1b1", "question": "How do you survive a stroke and recover completely as fast as possible?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6a83548e", "question": "What is the \"window of opportunity\" regarding therapy for a stroke victim, and what is the time limit set by insurance companies or Medicare?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1725f051", "question": "What is the use of transfer ports in a two-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d1e1c611", "question": "Where can I get solutions of final stroke of Aakash?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2650b4bd", "question": "How are 2 stroke and 4 stroke carbs different?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "cb03c451", "question": "Who defines the correct stroke order for a Chinese character? Can there be multiple correct stroke orders for a character?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5fb4bb52", "question": "Do stroke victims know they are having a stroke? Are they aware at all that something is wrong?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b39ffd10", "question": "Why do beach lifeguards use the butterfly stroke to swim to a struggling victim when the butterfly stroke is so exhausting?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2e7ad48a", "question": "Do stroke survivors remember their stroke, and if so, what did they feel in the hours or minutes leading up to it?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "024270cb", "question": "What is a 4-stroke petrol engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3afe9ad5", "question": "What are the exercises to prevent heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1e487aca", "question": "Can I fit the camshaft of a 2-stroke engine into a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6a778bfe", "question": "Why shouldn't the fear of one day having a stroke prevent someone from learning a language?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1536fe23", "question": "What is the simplest way to distinguish between a two stroke and a four stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bd0732dd", "question": "What do I do? I’m a new guitar player and I’m confused if I should stroke down or up? There are symbols for the down strokes but what about the notes with no symbol on top? Do I stroke down or up?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7d50843b", "question": "Why are a couple brush strokes on canvas considered “abstract art”?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "41bd8225", "question": "What is stroke and stroke length?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "73605648", "question": "Which are the 2 stroke bikes in india?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2820cdc9", "question": "Can cannabis help a stroke patient recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "212baa80", "question": "How do you stop a stroke while it’s happening?", "answers": "Ah! I can answer this! You can’t.\nIt was 0555; Lukas was awake and wanted out. I got out of bed, put my robe on and headed for the front door; open, out, close- and, since it was Saturday, I decided a cup of coffee slowly enjoyed as morning broke was a good idea. I headed for the kitchen.\nAnd wondered why my left foot kept sliding along- couldn’t lift the thing- it was dead asleep- all pins and needles. Huh. Made a cup of Kuerig coffee (fast) while tapping my foot trying to get it to wake up. Reached for the sugar bowl with my left hand and watched my arm swooping around- that’s weird. Got hold of the sugar bowl, spooned some into my coffee, still swooping, took a gulp of it, and realized this wasn’t weird, this was a stroke.\nDH heard me call, called 911; I was in a CT scanner within 30 minutes of that, and fifteen minutes after that was given the option of TPA since no bleed was found on the CT. I spent a day in ER, a day in SCU, a day in Med/Surg and then 10 days in a darned good rehab hospital. Currently, I can walk, type, do it all, just slowly and with lots of thought.\nI couldn’t have stopped what was happening- there was nothing to stop it right then. No aspirin could have gotten into my brain fast enough. If I already had an IV in place, if we knew at that moment there was no bleed, if we had TPA just laying around the house, maybe I could’ve gotten away with less deficit- but each of those ifs is more impossible than possible. So, what I feel like is a plant that gets sideswiped by a killing frost- a few leaves got crisped, but the plant is still healthy, and new leaves will grow.\nOnce a stroke starts, you can’t stop it, although prompt medical care can break up the clot (usually) or stop the bleed (sometimes). And then you deal with the damage done."}
{"_id": "fec1246f", "question": "Can stroke victims benefit from marijuana use?", "answers": "Stroke is a vascular problem. There is a decrease in the amount of oxygen going to the brain. This means neurons start to die, and brain function wipes out.\nCannabis (and in particular CBD) has been shown to be a neuroprotectant in mice, but its efficacy on humans has not been proven as of such yet. Anecdotally, and according to some NFL players, cannabis could indeed be neuroprotective. Cannabis may not only help protect surrounding nerves from the stroke/ischemic event, but may help repair them, too.\nWhy? Well, when a stroke occurs, “Glutamate” is released. Now, glutamate is a necessary chemical for sending signals to other cells, but is toxic when produced in excess. When a stroke occurs, the glutamate cannot be removed, destroying brain cells. CBD may help block this excess amount of glutamate from forming in the forst instance.\nThe problem with cannabis for stroke victims, however, is THC. THC may dull brain performance, so in this sense cannabis can be a bit of a “double-edged sword” for stroke victims."}
{"_id": "7171ff3e", "question": "Does a stroke cause permanent brain damage?", "answers": "I had a major stroke at age 52 which changed my life forever. My right side was paralyzed from head to foot, and I lost my speech. I had daily physical, occupational and speech therapy for a long time and off and on again for years after that first year and still to this date to keep me functioning. I still cannot walk well after 26 years because my ankle never recovered. My car still has to have a left-fooot accelerator so I can't rent a car which limits traveling. I won't go in to all the details.\nYes a stroke does cause permanent brain damage because the stroke continues for around 48 hours destroying more of your brain by either depriving it of oxygen or flooding it with blood.\nAnother result which I happened to suffer is RSD, Reflex Sympathetic Dystrophy. now known as Complex regional pain syndrome, CRPS. That is horrible. Intractable pain more severe than anything anyone can believe. It is the result of trauma, in this case brain trauma.\nThis may be more than you were looking for but if you were wondering if your brain gets all better by a certain time and things go back to normal, NO. Maybe you're wondering if someone you know will ever be the same. I have lots of residual issues which people can't see but I have to deal with. People having a major stroke like mine can kiss their paychecks good bye. You can no longer do the work you did before. And likely never will. But I'd say I'm doing pretty good for having half a brain!"}
{"_id": "a1a07b19", "question": "What is the best kind of food after a stroke?", "answers": "I don’t think the types of food make a real difference. There is no magical food.\nJust follow simple steps\nEat a wide variety of foods (mostly plant based) which contain all the nutrients and calories you need (number of calories is hard to estimate - check weight regularly to see if the average is growing or falling).\nAvoid foods which can increase your chances of another\nHigh fat foods for many people help cause strokes\nDiabetes can cause strokes - so if you have any problems it is probably a good idea to avoid sugar and too many refined carbohydrates (actually limiting the carb intake a little is often good - we tend to eat lots of carbs, just try not to replace them with things which are less healthy for you)\nIf your blood pressure is high, then lower your sodium intake\nAvoid transfats (probably fair advice for everyone)\nDrinking too much. A little can be ok, or depending on other health problems it can even be good. But a little so easily becomes a lot. Consumption of too much alcohol can cause a lot of problems associated with stroke.\nDon’t smoke\nexercise if you can (obviously that would depend on the severity).\nFollow doctors advice on medications and lifestyle.\nAll strokes are different anyway. A bleed will be different to a clot, etc."}
{"_id": "18a0920c", "question": "What were you doing just before you had a stroke?", "answers": "I was holidaying with my family in a caravan park in a coastal town. 3 young girls and my wife. I was 40 years old. As a prequel I had a dull headache for a few weeks. Nothing major but I don’t get headaches. Was at the docs for something else and mentioned it. He had a quick look and said it’s probably neck/muscle related and could go to a chiro/osteo which might help. And if it doesn’t, come back and he’ll run some tests. He then said “don’t worry, chance of manipulating your neck and a stroke is about 100 million to one!” So I did that but didn’t seem to make much difference. Then was straight on holidays so I thought if it persists I’ll see him when I get back.\nAfter dinner was finished on about the 6th day, my wife was putting the girls to bed and I was sitting in the camp chair with a glass of wine. I went to get up out of the chair to get a cigarette on the camp table and I started walking sideways. I checked myself and thought that was weird. I eventually got my smokes and made my way back to the chair and sat down. “Strange” I thought. But felt ok and resumed with a cigarette and the glass of wine. Note: it was only my 2nd glass so I knew I wasn’t drunk.\nI got up 15 minutes later and started cleaning up and everything was fine. About another 30 minutes later exactly the same thing happened. I got out of the chair and walked sideways. This time I concentrated on walking straight, but it just didn’t happen. Weird again I thought. Sat down and mildly concerned but not really that worried. My wife came out from the arduous task of putting 3 girls to bed ranging from about 4-10 and we had another wine.\nI then felt a bit weird. Sort of tired and not quite right. It was now about 9:30pm. I said I’m going to bed.\nI went to sleep pretty quick and over the next few hours woke up occasionally in a sort of stupor and tried to lift my head off the pillow but it wouldn’t move. It was like when you half wake up from a heavy sleep and you can’t lift your head so I thought it was dream state. Eventually I woke up and couldn’t lift my head and I thought “no, I’m really awake and I can’t lift my head” I tried a few times and then found I could sort of roll to one side. I really then concentrated and lifted myself up and crawled off the edge of the bed. I sort of sat down next to the bed and my wife woke up. She said are you ok, and I said I need a shower. I felt like my body was not right and was breathing heavier and just felt wrong. At this point I thought I may have been bitten by some bug and had been poisoned. She started getting concerned. About a minute later I said fairly calmly “I think you should call an ambulance”.\nWell panic broke out. She called an ambulance and i made my way outside with her assistance and sat on a chair. She was asking what was wrong. I said I’m not sure and was slurring my words and my whole right side was not working, including my mouth. We waited for about 15 minutes and the ambulance quietly made its way through the park and found us. The ambo talked to me and about a minute he said “I think you’re having a stroke”. It was surreal. My wife woke the girls up and neighbouring ‘campers’ came out and it was a bit of a scene. It was a bit sketchy but I was put in the ambulance and taken to the local country hospital.\nI spent about 4 hours in there with some scans and tests but they weren’t 100% sure what it was. They didn’t have an MRI machine and as I kept going in and out of ‘functions’ on my right side every 30 minutes one doctor thought it could be Bells Palsey. I could function almost normally and then a few minutes later my whole right side was paralysed and couldn’t talk properly. This happened at least 6 times at the hospital and on reflection happened at least that again from earlier in the evening.\nEventually they said I needed to be transferred to Melbourne and as I was stable went by ambulance. I stopped going in and out of paralysis by then and my right side was not as bad as the worst times but pretty much 80% gone. This is the first time I panicked. I though “what if this is it? Am I going to be like this forever”. It was very scarey. My only thoughts were for my wife and girls and they’d have to look after me forever. I was never afraid of dying and didn’t feel any real pain, just wrong.\nThe trip took 4 hours. As soon as I got to the specialist neuro hospital they did an MRI and found the spot where the clot had been. It was in my brain stem ( left pons). The clot had since cleared. The head of neuro came and saw me a few hours later and spoke to me. He said I had suffered multiple strokes every 30 minutes as the clot had moved slightly and let the blood flow. Then it lodged and blocked the flow. And so on. I’m not sure what happens but he said clots sometimes just eventually break up which mine did.\nTo cut the rest short I was probably lucky for the clot movements. It allowed some respite to get function going again for a while before the next stroke. I made a 90% recovery within 6–8 weeks. Slurred speech eventually came back and co-ordination which was all over the place also came back. I probably made ‘full’ recovery within 6 months, but it did change my tolerance to things and I came apathetic to many things.\nThey never found the cause (it wasn’t attributed to smoking). There was dozens of tests. My arteries and heart were fine and as the specialist said it’s fairly unusual in someone my age and most likely was an impact trauma (sport related or something) and a one off, but you never know.\nA year later I left my wife for reasons I can’t fully explain ( she is the most amazing person I’ve ever met and would make for another long story). I still regret it and will to the day I die, but we are still friends and have moved on with our lives and are relatively happy. Our girls are ok and are now beautiful young women.\nIt’s been 12 years and physically I’m fine. I still occasionally miss judge a step or something but you wouldn’t notice it. When I was in hospital I saw many older people who were pretty much vegetables. I was very, very lucky for the outcome.\nPostscript. When I went back to the doctor a few months after for ongoing medication etc, you should have seen the look on his face. He’s a good doctor and been our family doctor forever so I wasn’t going to look at any ‘avenues’. But I think he would have been quietly shitting himself."}
{"_id": "5756f083", "question": "I want to know everything about bikes. How do they work? What should be looked for before categorizing them into good and bad? What are cc, strokes, etc.?", "answers": "In this answer I will be trying to make you understand the terms which you are going to face often on the web pages of different motorcycles.\n4 Stroke Engine\nA 4 stroke engine is the one in which the piston completes four separate strokes while turning a crankshaft. A stroke refers to the full travel of the piston along the cylinder, in either direction.\n4 strokes can be categorized as following :\n(Please refer to this animation as I couldn't incorporate it in my answer\nFour-stroke engine\n)\nIntake: Open the intake valve(right one in the following diag.) so that air fuel mixture can come into the chamber.\n\nCompression: Compress the air fuel mixture.\n\nPower: While the mixture is fully compressed and piston is at its top most position, ignite the mixture using spark plug.Ignition leads to expansion of air-fuel mixture and thus forces the piston down to its bottom most position.\n\nExpansion: Exhaust valve (left one in above diag.) is opened and the piston forces the residual air-fuel mixture out of the chamber.\n\nThese days all bike engines are of 4 strokes so their is no need to get further into it. Let's start focusing on more important aspects.\n4 Valve and 2 Valve\nIn above diag. you can see there is one valve present for intake and one valve for exhaust of air fuel mixture hence the term 2 valve engine. In a 4 valve engine, there are 2 intake valves and 2 exhaust valves.\nJust as when you run at fast speeds you start taking breath from mouth as well, having 2 extra valves will help engine to get air-fuel mixture in sufficient amounts at higher rpms. Sports bike like R15 and CBR have 4 valve engine whereas 2 valve engines are more common in street bikes.\nSOHC and DOHC\nIn the engine diagram shown above, just above the rods attached to intake and exhaust valves, you can see two rotating pieces having a bulge outside. This mechanical piece is known as Cam and the bulge present at its surface helps to open and close the intake and exhaust valves just at right moments.\nBoth cams used to be attached to a single rotating shaft, known as Camshaft, as shown in the following diagram.\nFig. 1: The two bulgy pieces are Cams and the whole structure of cams and shaft/rod going through them is called Camshaft. Orange pieces are the rods connecting intake and exhaust valves.\n(Refer Camshaft\nfor complete animation)\nIn a 2 valve engine a single camshaft is enough to open and close intake and exhaust valves by placing the cams at appropriate angles. Things get complicated in a 4 valve engine. There are two options to circumvent this problem :\ni) Use two camshafts, each camshaft having 2 cams for 2 inatke valves and other camshaft having cams for 2 exhaust valves.\nii) Use single camshaft alongwith more complicated mechanism to operate all 4 valves.\nHence, the name dervied are :\nSOHC : Single Overhead Camshaft\nDOHC : Double Overhead Camshaft\n\nFig 2: 2 Valve SOHC Engine ( Image source Motorcycle Specifications\n)\n\nFig 3: 2 Valve DOHC Engine ( Image source Motorcycle Specifications\n)\nAs the camshafts are present just directly at the head of the engine, hence the name Overhead. Just to avoid any confusion, camshafts are present outside the engine but just above its head.\nDOHC layout has better valve opening and closing timings and more precise also but increases the weight and number of moving parts in engine. SOHC although will be lighter but we will have to use rocker arms to control the valves.\nCBR has 4 valve DOHC engine while R15 has 4 valve SOHC engine. 2 valve engine bikes have usual SOHC.\nSpark Plug\nPosition of spark plug plays key role in the efficient combustion of air-fuel mixture, as the ignition should spread evenly in the chamber. A 4 valve DOHC engine offers very favourable top central position for spark plug. In case of 4 valve SOHC engine, due to single camshaft present at top central position, spark plug is placed slightly away from this key position.\nFig 4: 4 Valve DOHC Engine with spark plug in the middle of 4 vlaves (Image source http://www.caranddriver.com\n)\nBajaj has been using DTSi technology which use two spark plugs instead of one for more efficient combustion although other key players are able to give equivalent benefits using only single spark plug.\nAir Cooled and Liquid Cooled\nAir cooled engines are cooled naturally by outside air. They generally have fins present to dissipate more heat.\nFig 5: Air cooled engine. (Image source http://zxj510228.en.ec21.com\n)\nLiquid cooled engine is surrounded by a continusouly flowing coolant which absorbs the heat and dissipate it at the radiator. Liquid cooling is used in the engines having high compression ratio, which can operate at high rpms as sports bike.\nFig 6: Liquid cooled engine (Image source http://www.iamabiker.com\n)\nR15 and CBR use liquid cooled engine as opposed to air cooled engine in FZS, Gixxer, etc.\nMax Power and Max Torque\nThese parameters are of great importance to look out for while comparing motorcycles but they are very hard to understand and quite confusing. I am incorporating few words from this article http://www.bikesindia.org/reviews/difference-between-motorcycle-power-torque-explained-which-is-better.html\n\nPower: The Power produced by any engine is the capacity of that engine to take the motorcycle to its maximum speed.\nTorque: The Torque generated by an engine is an entity which determines the pulling capacity of the bike.\nYou will have to dive deep into this topic on your own.\nDisplacement\nAs given on Wikipedia, engine displacement is the volume swept by the piston inside the cylinder of engine in a single movement from top dead centre (topmost position) to bottom dead centre (bottommost position), commonly specified in cubic centimeters(cc). Generally higher the displacement higher the torque and power you get. But there is no direct relationship between displacement and power. For example Honda CB Trigger with 150cc engine given max power of 14 bhp whereas Honda CBR 150R with 150cc engine gives max power of 18 bhp.\nSo instead of looking just at displacement, give more weightage to maximum torque and maximum power the engine can deliver.\nDisc Brake and Drum Brake\nIn a disc brake, the brake pads squeeze the disc attached instead of the wheel, and the force is transmitted hydraulically instead of through a cable. Friction between the pads and the disc slows the disc down.\nFig 7: Working of disc brake ( Image source http://auto.howstuffworks.com\n)\nIn drum brake set of shoes or pads press outward against a rotating cylinder-shaped part called brake drum.\nDisc brakes are superior to drum brakes in stopping vehicle, they dissipate heat better and also have less wear and tear. General trend is to have disc brakes in front, as momentum is transferred to the from while stopping, and drum brakes in rear due to cost constraints. High end bikes have disc brakes in both front and rear.\nFuel Injection and Carburetor\nConstant supply of air-fuel mixture in right proportions and in right amount to engine is of upmost importance and the amount should be adaptable according to the factors like the speed at which engine is running, load, etc. Before the advent of modern electronic sensors, this task was handled by a mechanical device called Carburetor.\nFig 8: Carburetor (Image source http://www.rc-trucks.org\n)\nNow days, carburetors are replaced with electronic Fuel Injection systems which gather engine operation information using various sensors and then decide the control over the air-fuel mixture.\nCarburetor are still popular in motorcycles and there is a heated debate between which one to use. Carburetors can be diagnosed by a mechanic in case you got unlucky in some remote area and their performance have been quite satisfactory until now. Fuel injection systems provide better fuel efficiency and power but to what extent is a topic of debate. Also if you got unlucky with fuel injection system in a remote area, then there is not much that you can do. There are lot of other factors which you can find on internet.\nTwinshock and Monoshock Rear Suspension\nFor rear suspension generally Twinshock absorbers are used but they add additional weight and get bendy and flexible in extreme riding conditions.\nFig 9: Simplified view of twinshock absorber ( Image source The Car Maintenance Bibles\n)\nThese problems can be overcomed by the use of Monoshock absorbers.\nFig 10: Monoshock absorber ( Image source BikeAdvice.in\n)\nMonoshock are more popular with high end sports bike and Twinshock with general street bikes.\nFull Fairing and Half Fairing\nA motorcycle fairing is a shell placed over the fame of some motorcycles with primary purpose to reduce air drag. Full fairings cover both upper and lower portions of motorcycles, as distinct from a half fairing, which only has an upper section, and leaves the lower half of the motorcycle exposed.\nFig 11: Full fairing, most portion of engine gets hidden behind the fairing. (Image source http://sv1000.lsn.net\n)\nFig 12: Semi faired version of Karizma. (Image source Top Speed In\n)\nKerb Weight\nKerb weight is the total weight of a vehicle with standard equipment, all necessary operating consumables such as motor oil, transmission oil, coolant, air conditioning refrigerant, and a full tank of fuel, while not loaded with either passengers or cargo. So lesser the kerb weight more performance engine can provide.\nWheelbase\nWheelbase is the distance between the centers of the front and rear wheels. Well the shorter it is the quicker a bike can turn and the longer it is the more stable it will be. That is why criusers like Bajaj Avenger have much greater wheelbase compared to other street and sports bikes.\nFig 13: (Image source http://www.carbibles.com\n)\nMore motorcycle geometry and handling factors can be read at Motorcycle Geometry 101\n.\nTubeless Tyres\nTubeless tyres do not require a separate inner tube and hence light weight and air leakage is slower in case of puncture. You can cover few more kilometers on motorcycle itself once tyre gets punctured.\n\nAt the end of my answer, I will say that although the features described above play key role, factors which cannot be described but rather can only be experienced are handling, comfort, easiness in shifting gears, engine vibrations, noise and many more.\nI will also not recommend you to maximize the features described above as that will lead you only to Sports Bikes. Instead, first the select category from which you want your bike to be and then you can sort according to the above parameters. Bikes are broadly categorized as :\nStreet\nCruiser\nSports\nHappy Hunting !!"}
{"_id": "46a645a1", "question": "Why is the risk of a stroke in young people on the rise?", "answers": "I assume you're talking about the recent report published in the Annals of Neurology.\nFirst, it's important to note that the increased risk over the last couple of decades looms large in terms of percentage but is quite small in terms of actual numbers: from 3.1 cases per 10,000 people to 4.7 cases per 10,000 people.\nSecond, the authors note that some of the increase isn't actually because more people are having strokes, but that we're getting better at detecting and diagnosing strokes.\nMost of the young people who had strokes, according to the study, had diabetes or high blood pressure. So the risk factors that lead to diabetes or high blood pressure are, unsurprisingly, also risk factors for stroke: obesity, poor diet, smoking, lack of exercise."}
{"_id": "37fe9319", "question": "After a stroke caused by a clot, how long does the blood clot remain in the brain?", "answers": "There is an adage that when something involves the brain, it's like real estate - it's all location, location and location. Even with the evolution of intracranial bleeds, location (what space they occur in) is important. The Question suggests it is about intracerebral bleeds (blood within the brain itself, instead of around it), so I will answer accordingly.\nAll clot within the brain eventually reabsorbs, if the patient lives long enough. There is much variability in how long this takes, but in general, the larger the clot, the longer it takes.\nA small \"bruise\" may disappear in a week or two on CT or MRI. A larger clot may take 3 - 6 weeks to clear. The really big ones may clear in terms of their density on CT, but will show permanent MRI changes and leave a cavity and distorted residual brain behind.\nPlease keep in mind that if you look hard enough (for example, using PET scanning, or post-mortem fine histology) you can find identifiable residua more often and for a longer time.\nAlso keep in mind that such structural evaluations have only a weak relation to how well the brain functions around the clot, and how quickly recovery of that function takes place.\nAnyone who has been in this business long enough will remember a patient with normal CT and MRI who nevertheless exhibits a deep and prolonged coma. On the other hand, we occasionally see surprisingly good function in patients with impressive clots in so-called \"non-silent\" parts of the brain.\nIt's amazing I think to see how the body has a sense of what tissue belongs where and in what quantities - even in the brain, which is more isolated from healing and immunological cells than other organs.\nHope this helps!"}
{"_id": "c69bc483", "question": "What is the basic difference betwen 6 stroke engine and 4 stroke engine?", "answers": "Six stroke engine have two additional strokes than four stroke engine. Those extra two strokes are again inlet and exhaust.\nThere is lot of heat energy stored in cylinder walls from previous Power stroke. This accumulated heat is used to expand either air or water(Which will convert into steam), Depending upon specs.\nWorking\nExhaust stroke completes, then air or water is injected into a cylinder. After that, enthalpy of air increases and it expands rapidly resulting one more power stroke. Air is released to atmosphere.\nSix stroke engines have higher efficiency and does not require sophisticated cooling system. However, it is difficult to gain smooth power from six stroke engine because, 1st power stroke is very powerful and 2nd power stroke does not contain more power as well as it takes twice the time to take 3rd power stroke from second as compared 1st and 2nd..\nIn short six stroke engines are not refined as four stroke engines. It will require lot of improvement to use commercially."}
{"_id": "259ab7c8", "question": "Transgender: Are there any dangers in allowing adults to change their legal genders at the stroke of a pen?", "answers": "In some countries (I can only speak for the US), you already can petition to have the government recognize you as having the gender of your choice.\nThe requirements to do so vary depending on where you are:\nIn places like California, your doctor has to fill out an affidavit stating that you have taken the \"clinically appropriate treatment\"[1] to change your gender.\nPlaces like DC are more flexible - they still require some professional's affidavit, but it only needs to state what your gender identity is[2], not what you've done about it.\nOther states (and countries) will have slightly different requirements.\n\nYour petition could be denied - though you can usually apply again.\nThere are, of course, conditions and restrictions to doing so - just like there are for changing your name. As Mykell Miller and Key Foster point out, the bureaucracy alone will probably deter most frivolous applications.\nThere may be additional restrictions and/or guidelines, depending on what other laws or institutions refer to a person's gender:\nMarriage - Jurisdictions that don't recognize same-sex marriage would presumably want to stop same-sex couples from \"simply\" changing their gender in order to be legally married. (Happily, this isn't a legal in the US anymore.)\nPrison - Some systems are not co-ed, so either prisoners would not be allowed to change genders while incarcerated or the system would have to handle the situation where they do.\nBusiness fraud - Any state would probably look down on someone applying for a change in gender designation simply for access to lower insurance rates[3], for example.\nThese are just off the top of my head; there are likely many others.\n\nSo, to answer the question exactly as explained in the question details:\nWould there be dangers in allowing people to change their legal gender designation without any restrictions or conditions? Definitely.\nHowever, this is not a plausible scenario by any stretch - because a person's legally designated gender has a variety of legal implications, there would have to be a formal process with conditions and restrictions around it.\nWould there be dangers in allowing people to request changes to their legally designated gender at will? Not really.\nThere would be many considerations (such as the above examples), but this is largely because there are many laws/institutions that were made under the assumption that everyone is Cisgender\nby birth.\nThere aren't \"dangers\" - in the sense that there aren't any harms that would necessarily follow from the basic idea of permitting people to change their legally designated gender.\n---\n[1] http://www.courts.ca.gov/1105.htm#genderonly\n\n[2] http://dctranscoalition.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/legal-guide-for-clients-dc.pdf\n\n[3] http://www.forbes.com/sites/moneywisewomen/2013/01/08/what-really-goes-into-determining-your-insurance-rates/"}
{"_id": "63639f87", "question": "Which type of engine is used in marine, two stroke or four stroke?", "answers": "What a coincidence..!!\nI just gave my IC end semester exams and here I am answering the Same question.\nSpecifically, in Marine engine, 2 STROKE ULTRA LONG STROKE ENGINE running on Heavy Diesel Oil are used. They are used to produce High Torque and longs stroke is used to provide enough time to burn that heavy residual diesel oil. Also, in Merchant vessels, speed is rarely a requirement..So the rpm is around 80–100. These engines are 3 storey's tall, with a bore diameter of upto 1 m.\nHigh Toque is required for propulsion. It also prevents losses which might occur in the propeller (cavitation, Eddy current losses.etc)\nAlthough, Medium speed 4 Stroke engines are couples to generators for production of electricity onboard ships.\nHope it helped!!!"}
{"_id": "531cf396", "question": "Do cows like being stroked?", "answers": "If they're tamed, sure. Cows are domestic, but most aren't truly tamed, two different things. You can raise a baby cow like a pet and it will be like a pet and enjoy being stroked and pampered, but most cattle free range on pasture and don't consider themselves pets, a human approaches they move away. When a farmer rounds up his cattle he's in essence hunting them, in the eyes of the cattle and the dogs he is using to do it. The whole activity relies on predator/prey instincts and behaviours from all parties. You can have one or two tame pet cows, but you could never have hundreds or thousands. Big herds of cattle by definition need to be largely independent and see themselves as free wild animals, even if they technically are not. A human then is just another predator."}
{"_id": "0ab3f1c3", "question": "What's the best way to get in shape by swimming? What’s the most time efficient method, and what are the best strokes? How many laps?", "answers": "I think swimming is awesome exercise. Swimming is also something that everyone thinks comes naturally but in reality 95% of everybody is extremely bad at it! Swimming got a reputation for being 'good' cardio because 95% of people just churn the water, waste energy and just exhaust themselves. It is possible to go get very good at swimming very quickly. In which case swimming becomes high quality, comfortable cardio where you elevate for heart rate for extended periods of time, you have low impact to your joints (and you don't feel like you are dying).\nIt is possible to get very good at swimming very quickly. The key is to follow the Total Immersion Swimming Program by Terry Laughlin. Let me repeat that because no one believes me. The key to getting good at swimming it to read (and watch the DVD) the book Total Immersion Swimming by Terry Laughlin.\nTerry is the de facto expert on teaching people how to swim PROPERLY in the shortest amount of time.\nI will not talk about the swimming drills that Terry recommends because they are in his book and you should read it. What I will mention is how swimming is a different kind of skill them most people think. In running, 90% of your energy is used to move you forward and 10% of your energy is loss to drag. In biking, 50% of your energy is used to move you forward and 50% is loss to drag. In swimming, 2% of your energy is used to move you forward and 98% is loss to drag! Olympic swimmers are 300% faster at swimming then the average person because they use 6% of their energy and ONLY waste 94% of their energy.\nWhat does this mean?? It means that to be a good swimmer you should be WHOLLY concentrating on reducing drag. That is the path to quick swimming. If you master the drills that Terry says you will quit drowning and will start being able to swim lap after lap after lap with constant heart rate.\nWhat is the single best indicator for a good swimmer:\nStroke count --how many strokes does it take to get across the pool? This number is an indicator of the quality of your form and your ability to reduce drag. A bad swimmer takes 22+ strokes to get across the pool. An average swimmer takes ~18 strokes to get across the pool. A good swimmer takes ~13 stokes to get across the pool. A Olympic swimmer takes 9 strokes to get a cross the pool! If you can use less strokes to get across the pool then you are using less energy per distance which means you are swimming more efficiently (i.e. less drag). Terry teaches you how to learn good form and reduce drag.\n\nHow I used Total Immersion Swimming.\nIn 2010 I did a Triathlon. Prior to this I had not swam for about 10 years. I practiced the drills in the book and on the DVD and I went from dying on 2 laps to over 40 laps with no problem. I also did all of this in 10 hours of TOTAL practice time. I then did a Sprint Triathlon with 1/2 mile open water ocean swim, 12.4 mi bike ride and 3.1 mi run. I placed in the top 50 percentile at the race. Not bad.\nHere is another good introduction and testimonial of the power of Total Immersion swimming by author Tim Ferris. Total Immersion: How I Learned to Swim Effortlessly in 10 Days and You Can Too\nFor schedule I would do three weights lifting sessions a week and do two swimming sessions a week. Although if you actually learn how to swim properly then the stress of swimming will actually be extremely mild on your body and you could either swim after your weightlifting sessions a form of recovery or you could swim six days a week in the morning because you enjoy it. It won't really matter. Just find out what you like."}
{"_id": "c65ec91d", "question": "Can a person be fully recovered after brain stroke?", "answers": "Yes, a person can be fully recovered after brain stroke but it will depend on condition to condition. If there is a very little portion of Brain is damaged due to stroke then the recovery is possible within few weeks but if it damaged a major portion of the brain then there are chances that full recovery may not possible.\nIf you want treatment for Brain Stroke then you can consult with Dr. Vikram Bohra who working as a Neurologist in Jaipur\n."}
{"_id": "d61fd9b9", "question": "Can young adults get stroke from stress and bad diets?", "answers": "Yes, now the age we could not comment on any thing, as I have. Seen the people, who got heartattack at very young age. It so very good for technology is growing in India day by day, but how the people are getting addicted on daily routine, it is not beneficial for every one for healthy life,. This is the reason, people are trying to get more luxurious life but at the same time situation getting worse and effecting to Thier health. I can tell you ample of example, which shows the bad effects- using mobile,. Seeting work for long hour, at desktop,. Fast food or junk food,. No exersize, running more havning bike and car as is mode of transport for daily work. I know the time, when my father, grandfather use to travel by bicycle for 10 km 20 km 50 km. This is not because of they were not having Money to buy, just because of good habit and maintaining there at very old age. I would like to as those type strength in today's generation. So that all can make their physic in well manner."}
{"_id": "3e2194d3", "question": "In a campaign ad, Joe Biden says “Trump stepped off the golf course and with the stroke of his pen, cut Social Security”. Is Biden’s claim true? Can US Presidents really cut Social Security with the stroke of their pen, as Biden said?", "answers": "I have researched Social Security for nearly a decade. There is no truth to any of Biden’s statements about Social Security. He should know his statements are inaccurate. (There are fact problems with Trump’s words too - but that is a different question.)\nSocial Security is a serious program, and deserves better from both sides.\nStatement by Vice President Joe Biden on President Trump’s Executive Orders to Sow More Chaos and…\n“Donald Trump said today that if he is re-elected, he will defund Social Security.”\n“Our seniors are under enough stress without Trump putting their hard-earned benefits in doubt.”\n“One order is Donald Trump’s first shot in a new, reckless war on Social Security. Trump announced a payroll tax plan with no protections or guarantees — like the ones the Obama-Biden administration enforced a decade ago — that the Social Security Trust Fund will be made whole.”\nAll False 100%\nTrump’s executive order has nearly no impact on Social Security because of the quirky way that Social Security collects revenue - see #1 if you want detail.\nTrump has said that he will pursue legal means to forgive the deferred taxes. This is only something that Congress can do, and in every case in the past the program has been re-imbursed for lost revenue - including the CARES ACT - see point #2 for detail\nTrump has said that he would like to repeal the payroll taxes, and replace them with money from the general fund. This is the opposite of a cut -see #3 if you want detail.\nThere are enough problems with Trump’s policies that there is no need to fear-monger the elderly purely for the benefit of votes.\n——-\n#1 : This is the SSA’s documentation on how Social Security collects revenue : Taxflow and adjustments\n. Trump’s order doesn’t last long enough to even delay revenue going to Social Security. When people talk about ‘a delay’ in revenue, it means that they do not know how the program works. hard truth.\n#2 : Here is the CARES Act text : https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/3548/text#id4e306ba7a4e7417ca51267b5ac407d8e\n#3 : Today we talk about benefit cuts when the trust fund is exhausted. This discussion goes away because Trump would make the program’s liabilities a liability of the government as a whole. That might sound good to you, but it opens the door to massive benefit cuts in the future because future voters may not like the idea that they have to pay for the gap between what we paid and the amounts that the people we elected promised. This is a dangerous policy - one that comes with either party."}
{"_id": "980ce4b3", "question": "Why are there hardly any sans-serif typefaces with a high contrast in stroke weight?", "answers": "This question addresses one of the fundamentals of type design, the function of the serif in the context of contrast.\nUnderstanding this issue is much easier when explaining it from the vantage point of calligraphy but for all of us non-calligraphers, here is an explanation that tackles it from a purely empirical perspective:\nLooking closely at the transition of thick to thin, tracing the stroke of the bowl in a glyph like the lower case d a characteristic dynamic in the development of thickness (or visual weight) can be observed. The difference in stroke weight and the transition between the thickest and the thinness moment is called the glyph’s contrast.\nTake for instance a typeface like Didot or Bodoni where the hairline curls around with unchanged thickness and then suddenly picks up weight.\nNow compare this unique transition of contrast to the gradual transition of weight in the b’s bowl of a typeface like Garamond or Bembo. Starting at the branching, the very first moment where the bowl branches from the stem, the thickness of the stroke increases throughout the arch of the bowl in a very typical manner.\nKeeping this observation in mind check out the lower case character i in each of the two typefaces. Without the serifs attached to that short little stem, the i might be part of just any old sans-serif typeface as there is no transition of visual weight. Without serifs the i would not have any contrast. The serifs take over this specific role. They represent for all the stems the transition of contrast that is taking place in the bowls. That way, with the help of the serifs, every stem in a typeface expresses the same thick-thin contrast as the bowls. This binds the glyphs of a typeface together. Thanks to the serifs they all follow the same set of design rules. This creates uniformity and makes sure all glyphs express their shared family traits.\nHigh contrast typefaces without serifs are simply breaking this rule. There is absolutely nothing wrong with breaking rules in design. But as always the expert can tell the difference between a designer who knows the rules and then breaks them and a designer who does so oblivious of the rules. This naiveté can be charming but hardly counts as good craftsmanship. The more the typographer understands type design the safer their choice of typeface becomes."}
{"_id": "da060fb1", "question": "Can you die in your sleep from a stroke?", "answers": "It's quite rare for a person to die due to stroke while sleeping.\nHowever it's possible.\nA strategic infarct in the brainstem due to occlusion of the basilar artery can knock out the respiratory and cardiac centers leading to death.\nMassive infarcts of the hemispheres could theoritically cause herniation and brainstem compression leading to death.\nTorrential intracerebral or subarachnoid haemorrage can also possibility lead to sudden death while asleep.\nHowever it's more common for a person to wake up from sleep with symptoms of stroke."}
{"_id": "9fd56ba0", "question": "Did you not recognize your symptoms of a heart attack or stroke?", "answers": "I blame TV for my ignorance of what a heart attack REALLY is. I had no clue what was happening or how lucky I was to be alive until days after.\nWe have all seen TV shows where the guy falls down and they get the defibrillator out and shock his heart to start again. This was a heart attack to me. And as I have recalled my experience to many others, they believed the same thing. That my friends is cardiac arrest and not a heart attack.\nFor those who may be ignorant on the subject as I was, your heart is a muscle and that muscle requires oxygen to survive. The oxygen is provided by blood that flows through the vessels along the heart muscle. When one of those vessels becomes restricted or blocked and the heart begins to starve for oxygen, you are having a heart attack.\nMy symptoms started Sunday night under stress. I had debilitating pain right between my shoulder blades. I went to work Monday for 2 hours before going home because of pain.\nMonday evening I went to a clinic because of this back pain. They checked my bp and sent me home with muscle relaxers.\nTuesday morning I woke up and the pain had moved from my back to my left arm. A horrible pain I will never forget. I went outside with my coffee, smoked 2 cigarettes, called in sick to work, took a Vicodin and a muscle relaxer and went back to sleep.\nTuesday afternoon I was curled in the fetal position crying from the pain. I had thrown up twice. Took more Vicodin along with some extra strength aspirin and more muscle relaxers.\nTuesday evening I couldn’t take the pain anymore. I called a friend to come take me to the hospital.\nThe admitting nurse took one look at me and knew. Crowded ER and I was taken immediately in and hooked up to an EKG and then told I was having a heart attack. Ten minutes later I was naked in the cath lab with a gown just thrown over me and I have no idea how many people swarming around me.\nTurns out, I had a 99% blockage of my Left Anterior Descending artery, a widow maker. There was permanent damage done to my heart. I was told a week later that a man a few years older than me came in 2 hours later for the exact same thing and didn’t make it.\nNo, I didn’t recognize my symptoms. Not because they weren’t there, but because of my ignorance."}
{"_id": "d24f283f", "question": "Is it true that President Trump had a small stroke this month?", "answers": "Writing this from UK\nI don’t know whether tRUMP did or did not have a “small” stroke - but such a stroke, if caught within a few hours - can be fixed quickly if it’s caused by a blood clot.\nI had a small stroke on a Saturday at 1pm.\nI was in the hospital within an hour, speedily transferred by ambulance to a stroke centre a few miles away and, after blood tests (in the first hospital) and a CT scan (at the second, where the blood-test results had already arrived), was diagnosed as having a small clot on the brain.\nSince it was a clot, not a bleed - and a small one - I was offered treatment with Alteplase, which washes away the clot (the pluses and minuses were fully explained to me).\nAll symptoms were gone by that evening (but I was still monitored at very regular intervals through the night) - confirmed by the consultant on the Sunday morning and re-confirmed by a physiotherapist that afternoon.\nI was discharged that evening, returning home by underground and taxi accompanied by my son.\nHappily (and quite contrary to how I’d imagine things would turn out when the stroke happened), I have had zero stroke-related problems since that time.\nOh, and since this was in the UK - which offers health care free-at-point of delivery - none of this (and none of the follow-up checkups and care) cost me a thing.\nHate to think what the bill would have been if I lived in the USA and didn’t have first-rate medical insurance.\nUpdate - May 2, 2020\nMy original answer referred to a stroke that happened in January 2018. Had another one in early January this year (2020), but considerably milder.\nNo need for Alteplase but what was thought to be a good idea - soon after I arrived in hospital - was to put a stent into my left carotid artery (up in the neck), which was somewhat clogged up. This took place under local anaethetic because I wasn’t “nil-by-mouth! - I had eaten fairly near the time when the procedure was to take place.\nWeird hearing it all going on and feeling the doctors inserting this thing into an artery in my groin and thrusting upwards towards my brain (well, a bit short of there but in that general direction).\nSadly, although the stent went in place okay and seemingly has been doing a good job since then, nobody noticed that a substantial blood clot has been created where the work that had taken place down where the cut was made to get the stent in.\nVery little blood was getting to my right leg or foot. When my left foot touched my right foot when I was in bed, it felt like it was resting on a piece of cold meat out of the fridge.\nUpshot of that was I went straight back to the hospital that night and it was decided to do a rather big cutting job to completely clean out the artery.\nThat seems to have been successful, too, but the scar is a bit of horror show.\nCost?\nWell, you know the answer to that - nothing."}
{"_id": "3f587961", "question": "How do you calculate BHP using MEP, stroke, and cylinder diameters in marine 2-stroke and 4-stroke engines in metric units?", "answers": "Well let me start,\nWork done = Pressure X change in displacement, so\nW.D = (BMEP) x(Swept volume)\nnow Power = Work done / unit time\nso P = (BMEP) x (swept volume) / (revs per which powerstroke occurs/current revs)\nlets say P = (BMEP x Vs) / (z / N)\nSo, BEMP you already know. Vs you can compute from stroke and bore, Z=2 for four stroke & 1 for two stroke, but N you will definitely need. More N more the BMEP, its in direct proportion and hence no way to eliminate that in any formula conversion you do."}
{"_id": "bd6f3554", "question": "A four-stroke cycle engine may or may not have a pressure boost (supercharger, turbocharger) in the intake system. Why must a two-stroke cycle engine always have an intake pressure boost?", "answers": "Two stroke small single cylinder engines don't have a supercharger but make use of the piston descending pressurising the crankcase to force the charge into the cylinder all others including diesels require a pressure to force air into the cylinder but why?\nA two stroke does not have an intake stroke with suction.\nWhen the piston ascends the crankcase depression draws in fresh air and fuel through a reed valve.\nWhen the piston descends it is on a power stroke unless the engine has not yet started in which case the cylinder may have left over combustion gasses or air/fuel.\nAt or before BDC the exhaust port opens and moments later the inlet port opens.\nThe piston coming down pressurises the crankcase until the inlet port opens and this blows exhaust out the exhaust port but also is directed up to the top of the bore by the piston shape which also directs exhaust out of the exhaust port.\nThe piston starts moving up the bore closes the inlet then the exhaust and compresses the charge.\nThe charge is ignited near TDC and so starts the process again.\nMulti cylinder or diesel two stroke.\nIf the multi cylinder petrol twostroke is treated as a number of single cylinder engines bolted together with separate crankcases the engine operates as above.\nMulti cyl two stroke with common crankcase.\nEach inlet port is connected to a common plenum pressurised to send air to any cylinder that has an open port.\nEach cylinder inlet will open in sequence.\nThe exhaust ports are normally connected to an extractor style exhaust to reduce back pressure.\nBest with port or direct injection.\nDiesels normaly have a valve for either inlet or exhaust or can have opposed pistons with one piston opening the inlet port and the other opening the exhaust.\nThis provides good scavanging with inlet as far away from the exhaust as possible.\nThey cannot have crankcase pressure porting because of the danger of oil fumes which they would run on.\nThey all have a supercharger to pressurise the inlet and some also have a turbocharger."}
{"_id": "8568511a", "question": "The moment you have a stroke, do you know what is happening to you?", "answers": "It was a Saturday afternoon I was in the garage, warming up to lift weights. After several minutes of jumping jacks, I felt tired, and wanted to sit down. As I was about to sit on the bench, my butt missed it, and I found myself on the floor, leaning against the bench. For some reason I felt extremely tired and unable to get up. I called my wife’s name, and thought I sounded different. She came out, and said she’s call our neighbor who was a cardiologist. Since I thought I was talking funny, and remembering an episode on House, M.D, about a patient with slurred speech, I asked her if my speech was slurred. She ignored me, and proceeded to call our neighbor friend cardiologist. He arrived, took my blood pressure which was 100 over 80 (pretty normal for me), and told my wife to take me to the Emergency Room of the hospital whose cardio dept he headed. My wife asked another of our neighbors to help drive me. I’m a pretty big guy, 5′10, and about 190 lbs. It took 3 of them to get me to our neighbor’s car.\nOn the drive to the hospital, I remember feeling really tired and sleepy. I wanted to sleep, but my wife kept me from falling asleep. When we arrived at the ER, I remember hearing someone say I was having a stroke. Nurses asked me questions, and I remember answering coherently (to my mind at least). After an MRI scan I was admitted to a room. The next day, I was moved via ambulance to another hospital which supposedly had a better neurological unit and better facilities.\nSo, yeah, I knew what was happening, but I didn’t know it was a stroke until hours later."}
{"_id": "63eeab3b", "question": "What can I do to restore brain function to pre-stroke condition?", "answers": "Even for the smallest strokes, the maximum that you can get is to restore partially the function that you lost. My father had an stroke when he was young, and he lost some movement of the right part of his body. Some years after, he was able to walk and perform all motor tasks with no problem, but he stills limp with his right leg a little bit, and sometimes he lost the grip with his right hand (it occurs rarely, but it does occur).\nThe reason for that is due to the plasticity ability of adults neurons. Adult brain does not have many room for plasticity, and therefore it is impossible to completely restore a lost condition."}
{"_id": "c6b01d9c", "question": "What is the difference between a 4 stroke and 2 stroke motor?", "answers": "A 4 stroke engine (most common) has an upstroke to expel the exhaust gas, a downstroke to suck in the gas-air mixture, an upstroke to compress the mixture, then, following the spark ignition, the power (down) stroke. A 2 stroke engine has the power stroke, at the end of which it draws in the gas/air mixure. After the up (compression) stroke, the spark plug fires and the power stroke begins again."}
{"_id": "eaf0d767", "question": "After a four stroke engine has completed one full operating cycle how many degrees has the crankshaft rotated?", "answers": "On a four stroke engine, you have four actions that take place which are the “strokes”.\nThe first one is when the engine breaths in it’s air/fuel mixture, otherwise known as the “Intake stroke”. It starts with the piston a the very top and pulls all the way to the bottom (180 degrees).\nNext the piston is pushed up to compress the air/fuel mixture, and as it said earlier this is called the “Compression stroke”. It started at the bottom and went all the way to the top so you get another 180 degrees (now we’re up to 360).\nNext is where the fun starts. Now that the air/fuel mixture has been compressed and is at the top, the spark plug (on a gas engine) lights it off and the explosion shoves the piston back down to the bottom again. This is called the “Power Stroke”. Now you have another 180 degrees (now were up to 540).\nThe final one is called the “Exhaust Stroke”. All of the burn air/fuel mixture does have to discharged, so the piston pushes back up from the bottom all the way to the top again, which would be your finial 180 degrees bringing us to a total of (drum roll please) 720 degrees.\nSo what did we learn today? The four strokes of a four stoke engine are 1) Intake 2) compression 3) Power and 4) Exhaust ."}
{"_id": "ec4ffc1f", "question": "Why is the 2-stroke engine more noisy than a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": "Air cooled 2 strokes have increased engine noise because of the thin cylinder walls.\nWater cooled and air cooled 2 strokes are also louder because of the exhaust design.\n2 stroke exhaust ports open near the end of combustion meaning some of the explosive energy is released into the exhaust increasing the amplitude of the pressure waves in the exhaust. The pressure wave in 2 stroke exhaust is used to help contain fresh air in the cylinder on the compression stroke through a tuned exhaust which reflects the pressure wave. Because of this tuned exhaust and firing on every revolution, 2 strokes have a pressure wave leave the exhaust twice for every rotation giving the high pitch sound. Now that high pitch sound combined with the high amplitude pressure waves combines with unrestricted exhausts to generate a high pitch high decibel level sound waves.\n4 strokes fire once every other revolution and commonly have a more restricted exhaust allowing the exhaust gases a more gradual path allowing the pressure wave to form a lower amplitude, lower frequency wave at a lower decibel level."}
{"_id": "a4400bb4", "question": "What are the telling symptoms of an oncoming stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8fa9b3f9", "question": "Why do you smell burnt toast before you have a stroke?", "answers": "The sudden presence of a smell associated with an event that is not in occurrence, is sometimes called a phantom smell, or phantosmia. Phantom smells may occur with any type of injury to the olfactory nerve or its brain origin, which could be due to trauma, stroke, seizures, tumors, or even migraines. To reiterate though, just because a person suddenly smells burnt toast doesn't mean they are having a stroke because there are several other conditions where phantosmia may occur (ie seizures, migraines, etc).\nWhat IS important is that if you think you or someone is having a stroke, you must immediately call 911 and make sure you are taken to a Stroke Center! Its also important that you know and recognize stroke warning signs and symptoms using the American Stroke Associations's Spot a Stroke FAST!\nFace drooping on one side or numbness\nArm weakness on one side or drifting down\nSpeech slurring or sounding strange\nTime to call 911 now!\nSo while smell can be affected in stroke, other diseases can also cause abnormal smells. Its good to consider stroke if you suddenly smell burnt toast while shopping at the Macy's perfume counter, but its far more beneficial to learn how to spot a stroke FAST!\nThe additional signs & symptoms of stroke (sans phantosmia) are conveniently listed on the screen-shot of the StrokeApp."}
